<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>rbucks.com - entrepreneurship</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rbucks.com/feeds/entrepreneurship.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rbucks.com/</id><updated>2025-04-27T20:57:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>My best advice for entrepreneurs</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2025/04/27/my-best-advice-for-entrepreneurs/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-04-27T20:57:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-27T20:57:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2025-04-27:/2025/04/27/my-best-advice-for-entrepreneurs/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on Shovels reaching $80K MRR and sharing my framework for evaluating business ideas - the most important factor in entrepreneurial success.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey, I've been writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been too long since I've posted here, but I've been writing on the Shovels blog, writing to my investors, and writing gobs and gobs of emails. I spend my evenings clearing my inbox or writing code. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight, however, is different. I feel like making my first rbucks post in a while. It's because I have something to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll throw this up on LinkedIn eventually, but my good news humblebrag here is that Shovels broke $80,000/mo in revenue last week. That's $80K MRR in startup-speak. That's shorthand for a million dollars per year in revenue! (I know, the real number is $83,333, but we'll round that down.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a big deal. It's the thing every startup dreams of when they first launch: let's make a million dollars. Let's clear that bar. At $80,000 per month you have a real business and you can support some real employees. There's NO DOUBT that the business has legs. The only question now is how far you can take it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took us 20 months to get here, and I have to admit that for the first time in my entrepreneurial career, I never doubted that this would happen. I knew Shovels felt different. I felt different. Together, we felt different. It was the right idea at the right time &lt;em&gt;for me&lt;/em&gt;. This trilogy is important. However, if I had to pick one from the three that matters most, it'd be the idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's what I want to share here: the importance of idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I interviewed to teach at DVC, I had to put a lesson plan together. I decided to do it on ideation. I still have my notes. I decided that tonight I need to turn this double-sided piece of paper into a blog post. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's an idea?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An idea is a thought or suggestion as to a suggested course of action or a concept / belief. That's what the dictionary says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurs call an idea &lt;strong&gt;a way to solve an unmet need.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unmet need! This concept is important. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's use an example: the light bulb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's a light bulb? Is it an idea? Or a solution? What's the purpose of a light bulb and whom does it benefit? A light bulb might solve several problems; which is the most important? Most of us have never thought of a light bulb like this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientist says, "My idea is to create light from electricity."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entrepreneur says, "My idea is to make people more productive indoors and at night."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A "business idea" takes an "idea" a few steps further. Let's explain this using our ideation selection framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How do you choose an idea?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should evaluate an idea by considering each of these attributes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Criteria&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Evaluation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Target market&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Size&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Existing solution&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Penetration&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unmet need&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Urgency&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Key benefits&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Strength&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Defensibility&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Technology&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each of the criteria, you want more of the evaluation. A good idea should be positive in every evaluation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An efficient way to evaluate is to turn the table above into a sentence. For our light bulb, it would go like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone dissatisfied with candles and kerosene lamps due to dimness, flicker, and inconvenience, I'm creating a light bulb that is bright, constant, portable, and electric, and is also difficult to manufacture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one-liner also makes a great pitch! When you have a strong idea, your pitch is also strong. They always go together. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shovels made it to $80K MRR because it was a good idea. That's the bulk of it. It helped that I was motivated, that I had the perfect co-founder, and I was able to get a great team together. Those aren't small things, but none of it would have been impactful if the idea was bad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while I celebrate this moment, and I've been glowing about it all week (enjoying it while it lasts), I'm simultaneously humbled by the simple fact that I'm at the mercy of the idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies work because ideas work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurs are merely vectors for good ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="shovels"></category><category term="business-strategy"></category><category term="advice"></category><category term="startups"></category></entry><entry><title>Thoughts on building a brand</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2024/12/25/thoughts-on-building-a-brand/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-12-25T09:06:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-25T09:06:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2024-12-25:/2024/12/25/thoughts-on-building-a-brand/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Marketing is increasingly central to who I am and what I do as an entrepreneur. This is not what I expected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started in entrepreneurship, I was the operations guy, not the CEO. I liked to think about how things worked. I dealt with the accountants, the lawyers, the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Marketing is increasingly central to who I am and what I do as an entrepreneur. This is not what I expected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started in entrepreneurship, I was the operations guy, not the CEO. I liked to think about how things worked. I dealt with the accountants, the lawyers, the recruiters. It was fun and I was good at it. When my first business failed, I remember meeting with a top-tier VC who funded us. He asked what I was going to do next. I said I didn't know. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Every company needs a Ryan Buckley," he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Thank you," I replied, unsure of exactly what he meant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conversation stuck with me ten years later. That was my personal brand back then: The guy who works behind the scenes and gets things done. A capable workhorse with some leadership potential. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My brand is different now: The CEO of Shovels who writes about entrepreneurship and building permit data. For my LinkedIn followers, I hope it's also about thoughtfulness and authenticity. For my new investors, I hope it's about determination and transparency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all the definitions of what a brand is, I like Seth Godin's concept of a &lt;em&gt;promise&lt;/em&gt;. A brand a promise. It's a set of expectations tightly bundled together into this thing that we call a brand. The rbucks.com blog brand is some authentic content (not AI), well-written (I try to minimize typos), about topics that I find interesting. The Shovels brand is high quality construction data accompanied with helpful customer service. The Saranap brand (my neighborhood) is walkable, family-friendly, charming area with lots of young kids. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A brand promises that these expectations are met. If the promise is broken by unmet expectations, the brand loses value. It gets tarnished. The best brands in the world have accumulated greater and greater expectations over the years, and the years themselves produce compounding value. This is how brands become incredibly valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One important note: a brand is not a logo. A logo is not a brand. A logo can represent a brand, and a beautiful logo can enhance a brand on the margins, but the logo itself doesn't make the brand. Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;!({static}/images/American_Express_logo_2018.svg_-1024x1022.png)

!({static}/images/Gap_logo.svg_-1024x1024.png)

!({static}/images/Bass_logo.svg_-849x1024.png)
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Express: Just a light blue square with the name of the company&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gap: Just a dark blue square with the name of the company&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bass: Just a red triangle above the name of the company&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the fonts are distinctive, but that's the effect of decades (or in the Bass case, nearly 250 years) of presence in society. A logo can be very, very simple, and the brand can still represent a wide variety of complex associations and expectations. Brand development takes hard work, years of consistency, and a dedicated staff to ensure that expectations are always met. Logo development just takes a consultant. I care about brands far, far more than I care about logos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My final point ties brand to culture. It's hard to imagine a great brand without a great culture, because you need that culture for the brand to consistently meet expectations. Years of achieving excellence cannot be driven by an outside consultant, a beautiful logo, or the perfect website with optimized copy. It's culture. Culture makes the brand work and that's why it's so important. Culture makes the product great, the support friendly, the documentation current. It's all of the things that allow a company to fulfill and even exceed the promise that the brand represents. I truly believe this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've had to think a lot recently about the Shovels brand. What does it mean to our audience? Is it meeting and exceeding expectations? Are the logo and website good brand ambassadors? It's been brought up to me more than once that we should consider a rebrand, make the Shovels guy and logo a bit more polished and serious. We should hire consultants to "rebrand" us. On the one hand, I can see that: make the logo more serious, get more serious customers! But on the other hand, it didn't sit right with me. Logos don't make companies. Logos don't make brands. Logos don't delight customers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I squashed it. We need design help, but we don't need a rebrand. And to the extent we need to rethink our positioning, that's work we have to do in-house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not a great slide designer, so I hired someone who can make great slides. They're not trying rebrand us. They're taking our content, our logo, and working with our brand to make a sales deck that looks nice. I'll translate the design over to the website and make it look nicer. These are useful exercises that are &lt;em&gt;part&lt;/em&gt; of building our brand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll always keep rethinking what we do and how we describe it. But WE need to be the ones doing it because that's how WE entrench the culture that makes our brand work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe there's such thing as a "good enough" logo. The three logos above fit that mold. They're not beautiful. They're just logos, and they're good enough. What makes the three &lt;em&gt;brands&lt;/em&gt; stand the test of time is everything else. That's what I'm focused on.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="branding"></category><category term="marketing"></category><category term="business-strategy"></category><category term="reflection"></category></entry><entry><title>Personal, Perceptible, Practical</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2020/03/28/personal-perceptible-practical/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-03-28T06:52:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-28T06:52:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2020-03-28:/2020/03/28/personal-perceptible-practical/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some time ago I learned about Susan Solomon, the atmospheric chemist who discovered that chlorofluorocarbons (a.k.a. CFCs) caused the huge hole in the ozone layer. Remember all that noise about this from the 90s? It went away because of Dr. Solomon. She received her PhD from UC Berkeley …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some time ago I learned about Susan Solomon, the atmospheric chemist who discovered that chlorofluorocarbons (a.k.a. CFCs) caused the huge hole in the ozone layer. Remember all that noise about this from the 90s? It went away because of Dr. Solomon. She received her PhD from UC Berkeley and she is currently still teaching and still doing atmospheric research at MIT. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been thinking about something she said about the tactics she used to get the world to care and do something about the problem. I was struck that she thought as much about the "marketing" of the ozone layer problem as the science behind it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!(https://www.pbs.org/wnet/peril-and-promise/files/2019/04/3_SusanSolomonV2-768x432.png)
&lt;em&gt;Susan Solomon at MIT. Credit: (https://www.pbs.org/wnet/peril-and-promise/2019/04/how-the-ozone-hole-can-help-us-communicate-climate-change/)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solomon said that effective environmental problem solving requires that the solution be &lt;strong&gt;personal&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;perceptible&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;practical&lt;/strong&gt;. I'd argue that this framework works for any problem, public or private, economic or environmental. It's relevant even when rallying the globe around fending off a global pandemic, too. I keep coming back to this when I read about the response to coronavirus, so let's apply Dr. Solomon's framework to our current global crisis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make people relate. Help individuals understand how the problem relates to them personally. Not the world, or the rainforests, or the spotted owls. Biologically, we are wired to care about #1 (ourselves) and although we can all point to examples of selfless behavior, on average, we're selfish. Rather than fight that tendency, make it work for the cause. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The harrowing stories of frontline health workers ring louder than the pleas of politicians. Doctors and nurses have an effective way of making things personal. Shelter in place to protect your family, your community, your own health. It also helps that nurses consistently rank among the (https://news.gallup.com/poll/180260/americans-rate-nurses-highest-honesty-ethical-standards.aspx). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perceptible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help people understand the units of measurement. In the case of coronavirus, it's the number of tests, cases, and deaths. Charts fly around Twitter comparing rates of infection by country, often on logarithmic scales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early challenge with coronavirus is that people who don't study math or economics don't have an appreciation for exponential growth. We all probably think we know what it means, but early dismissal of the risks show that most of us don't appreciate its gravity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason coronavirus spread so quickly is the same reason why you can't fold a paper in half more than eight times. It doesn't matter if you're folding a playing card or a football field. The reason is the thickness of the folds increases exponentially. After that eighth fold, no matter how thin it is to begin with (I mean, you need to be able to feel it), the material you'd need to fold is simply too thick. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply this principal to the spread of a virus, the number of initial vectors is like the thickness of the flat piece of paper. The more vectors, the thicker your piece of paper, so as you fold it and the vectors go out and infect, your thickness grows faster. The analogy of a really thin piece of paper is having just a few vectors, maybe just one, in a rural area, so he can't infect very many people very quickly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're starting with smaller numbers, so you might get more folds in. But exponential growth eventually looks the same, no matter how small the base. This is the perceptibility challenge we faced with coronavirus. Fortunately, it has helped that testing kit production is ramped up and we can see the exponential activity clearer now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circling back to the environmental application, when scientists were able to measure the rate of growth of the ozone hole and capture icebergs collapsing into the Arctic Ocean, people started to care. When the ban on CFCs went into effect and measurements showed the hole closing up, it reinforced the global community's behavior. Now it's no longer a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the feedback cycles on the coronavirus are even shorter than they are with the ozone hole. Effects of social distancing and lockdowns will be measured within two weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, this is the most important of the three. I believe the business adage that you can't fix what you can't measure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practical&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make the solution easy to understand. People don't want to think too hard. And if you're asking for a lot, then problem should be very personal and very perceptible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, this is where we really succumb to the human condition. Unlike many environmentalists I know, I don't think it's practical for everyone to give up meat and dairy products. Being 100% off fossil fuels is also not practical. But switching out the chemical in an aerosol can or using a product with a different applicator, as the ask was during the ozone crisis, is definitely practical. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the asks are huge. One billion people are restricted from congregating. Schools are closed. Small businesses are shut down. Public transportation ridership dropped by 90% in the Bay Area as employees were forced to work from home. The scale of this impact is mind-numbing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do believe this is the right solution, though, and my neighbors agree. These measures are practical in that they're easy to comprehend and it's easy to understand how they will help. With daily reports coming out about the spread of the virus, we're able to follow along as community by community we "flatten the curve" on the epidemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to sum it up, for me to get behind an action, I have to relate to it, be able to track progress, and have a well-defined way to contribute. When I first heard of this framework I thought it was a brilliant tool for activists to use. I never imagined that I'd experience a global pandemic, and it's interesting to see how this framework applies in this most extreme of circumstances too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="business-strategy"></category><category term="advice"></category></entry><entry><title>Being the other co-founder</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2019/03/22/being-the-other-co-founder/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T21:01:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T21:01:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2019-03-22:/2019/03/22/being-the-other-co-founder/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reflecting back on Scripted, I think it stopped feeling like my own company pretty early on. I had the luster of a co-founder title but I really was an employee like everyone else. There were some extra freedoms, perhaps, but not real freedom. Not like I have it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reflecting back on Scripted, I think it stopped feeling like my own company pretty early on. I had the luster of a co-founder title but I really was an employee like everyone else. There were some extra freedoms, perhaps, but not real freedom. Not like I have it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of it was not being CEO until the end. Being the second, internal, “other” founder of a company has its drawbacks. I didn’t have direct contact with the board. In the early days of Scripted, outside of board meetings, all contact went through my co-founder, who was CEO. This meant my co-founder knew everything and I only knew what he told me. Being a co-founder is not the same as being the CEO. Not even close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm coming up on two full years since my Scripted days came to a close. Since then I've run my own ship, sold that ship, and become a hired CEO. I haven't had a co-founder since Scripted and that distance and my most recent CEO experience has brought with it some new insights about those old days at Scripted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/munger.jpg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The co-founder or CEO / non-CEO-but-still-important pairing has many obvious examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steve Jobs and Steve Wozniak- Warren Buffet and Charlie Munger- Mark Zuckerberg and Sheryl Sandberg- Bill Hewlett and David Packard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's just some big names in tech and finance. There's a reason we like to have Presidents and Vice Presidents, Governors and Lieutenant Governors. Most leaders need a competent partner to achieve their greatest potential. Even the most competent CEO can't do it all. He or she needs a confidant, a second opinion, a voice to call out when they make a mistake. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's that last piece about trusting the second partner's opinion and hearing their voice that is most critical. The CEO can always overrule. That's the CEO's job. But if they don't listen, don't want to hear it, and consistently see things differently, then the partnership breaks down. It's inevitable, and history is littered with examples of partnership breakups too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Et tu, Brute?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I look back and reflect on the glory and the garbage, I think about what I could have done better as the other co-founder, when I wasn't CEO, and also what I could have done better once the mantle was passed to me. Did I speak up enough? Too much? Did I advocate for my CEO, try to make him better and successful? When it was my turn, did I listen and really absorb the opinions around me? Or did I listen too much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure the answer is: &lt;em&gt;all of the above&lt;/em&gt;. Had I played my cards perfectly, Scripted would have had a better outcome. But one thing I've learned from reading Warren Buffet's shareholder letters is when you have a business with even mediocre leadership but in a great, growing market, you can get away with making mistakes. You can make more than a few. At Scripted we made some mistakes, and unfortunately we were not forgiven. It was and still is a very tough market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I feel for the co-founder COO's of the world. It's a tough, nearly impossible position to be in. Charlie Munger, Sheryl Sandberg, my hat is off to you. You haven't made it look easy, but you've definitely made it look possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="scripted"></category><category term="leadership"></category><category term="startups"></category><category term="reflection"></category></entry><entry><title>If I could redo all of my content marketing</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2019/02/17/if-i-could-redo-all-of-my-content-marketing/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-17T21:56:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-17T21:56:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2019-02-17:/2019/02/17/if-i-could-redo-all-of-my-content-marketing/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If I could redo all of my content marketing, from every company I've ever worked on, I would keep this single, simple mantra in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content you publish should feel like you're giving a gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I certainly don't feel that about everything I've published. Perhaps the closest I've gotten …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If I could redo all of my content marketing, from every company I've ever worked on, I would keep this single, simple mantra in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content you publish should feel like you're giving a gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I certainly don't feel that about everything I've published. Perhaps the closest I've gotten to that is the (https://rbucks.com/the-parallel-entrepreneur/). I spent a lot of time on it and put a lot of planning into it. Outlines, research, conversations with people. That's probably what it takes to feel like I'm really &lt;em&gt;giving&lt;/em&gt; something valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is certainly aspirational. I don't expect to achieve this bar every time I click publish but I should be aware of when I don't reach that threshold. It's a good marker to go after. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get closer to it more often, I'll try to follow this process for future blog posts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write an outline first- Write in multiple sittings- Do a final reading before publishing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I did this with every blog post, not only would I publish better content, I think over time it would make me a better writer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post, perhaps ironically, did not have an outline but did get written over multiple sittings and did get a read-through. The first draft was kind of an outline, though. I can give myself credit for that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="marketing"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="business-strategy"></category><category term="content"></category><category term="advice"></category></entry><entry><title>I'm not fundable</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2019/02/01/im-not-fundable/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-01T14:42:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-01T14:42:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2019-02-01:/2019/02/01/im-not-fundable/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Someone raised a good question when I presented to a group of new companies at 500 Startups recently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Are you worried that no one will invest in you now?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My kneejerk, snarky answer would have been something along the lines of, “Nope! And guess what? I don’t care.” But …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Someone raised a good question when I presented to a group of new companies at 500 Startups recently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Are you worried that no one will invest in you now?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My kneejerk, snarky answer would have been something along the lines of, “Nope! And guess what? I don’t care.” But that’s not what I said. I’ll paraphrase my reply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're right, I probably am damaged goods now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say that not only because my investors lost their money on my last venture, but because I’ve been pretty forward about my feelings about venture capital in general, that it’s often not aligned with the interests of founders. My VCs didn't want my last venture to be a small success. It needed to be a huge exit or it needed to die. And so it died. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, you guys don’t need a multi-hundred million dollar exit to make your personal income statement pop. If you’ve raised a few million dollars then even a $10M exit will get you a house or at least a down payment on one, even after all the investors get paid (and they will get paid before you do.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A million bucks in your bank account is a life-changing event for you but your VC investors would call it a failure. They would compel you not to sell. That dichotomy is a real problem unless you also would shrug off anything less than a monster exit. So before you take VC money, be honest with yourself about how you define success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way for me to redeem myself is to build another great company. If I can’t raise money for it then I’ll have to do it without funding. I’m already doing that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, given where my mind is at today, I think if my bootstrapped business needed to become a big company, I’d sell it before I fundraised for it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember this: if you can fundraise, you can sell. If you can sell for a multiple of what you took fundraised (or ideally you just bootstrap), then you can change your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But don’t take my word for it. Here’s a quote from John Mackey, the now-even-more-rich co-founder of Whole Foods (in case you missed it, he sold to Amazon for $13.7 billion), in his (http://one.npr.org/?sharedMediaId=527979061:528000104).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…We turned to venture capitalists, who I have learned are like hitchhikers with credit cards. They get in your car, and as long as you take them where they want to go, they will help pay for the gas. But if you get lost or wander off the road you promised you were going down, they will hijack the car, throw you out and bring in a new driver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advice: be selfish. Take whatever exit that will change your life. And as for the VCs, let them eat cake.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="fundraising"></category><category term="bootstrapping"></category><category term="startups"></category><category term="reflection"></category></entry><entry><title>Why SaaS is a solo founder’s dream come true</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2017/11/23/why-saas-is-a-solo-founders-dream/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-11-23T19:51:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-11-23T19:51:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2017-11-23:/2017/11/23/why-saas-is-a-solo-founders-dream/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The dream is 100 customers paying you $100 per month. That’s the software-as-a-service (SaaS) solopreneur’s mecca.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hundred customers paying $100 per month adds up to $120,000 per year of revenue. Since we’re building software, you’ll have about 85% gross margins, so your gross profit …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The dream is 100 customers paying you $100 per month. That’s the software-as-a-service (SaaS) solopreneur’s mecca.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hundred customers paying $100 per month adds up to $120,000 per year of revenue. Since we’re building software, you’ll have about 85% gross margins, so your gross profit is at least $100,000. Your operating expenses are business-related assets and advertising activities, some of which will neatly cross over into your personal life (tax write-off for your home office, for example). Let’s say those expenses cost another $30,000 per year, so your “in-the-bank” net profit is $70,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it. That’s the big picture. That’s what you’re shooting for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a business that makes enough income for you to pay rent, even if you live in San Francisco or New York. If your home base is anywhere else, then you’re living like self-made royalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may still need your spouse or partner’s income to save for a house and take nice vacations, but what you’ve done with your $120K business is bought yourself time and flexibility. You might even keep your day job. Or you’ll start building a second $120K business because your first one pretty much runs itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s what it means to be a (https://medium.com/@rbucks/parallel-entrepreneurship-defined-34b2a1cca624). You don’t wait until your plate is empty in before you start another business. You just spin another one up and see if it grows as nicely as your first one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s “and” — not “or” — when you’re clearing $10K month with a SaaS business that runs itself. You can pretty much do anything you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few points about how to make this work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell to businesses&lt;/strong&gt;: Businesses don’t mind spending $100 per month. For most of them you’ll fly right under the radar during those inevitable months when they barely log into your product. Businesses these days are conditioned to accept monthly software fees. Take advantage of it!- 
&lt;strong&gt;Pick a problem that’s never really solved&lt;/strong&gt;: The beautiful thing about sales leads is you never stop needing them. That’s why (https://www.toofr.com) is a great little business. When it works (it finds good emails and generates good leads) it makes the users (sales reps and recruiters) want more. So the monthly nature of the billing actually makes sense!- 
&lt;strong&gt;Automate as much as humanly possible&lt;/strong&gt;: If you’re going to actually enjoy running a small business yourself or keep your team lean enough so you’re able to keep a ratio of $100K in profit per employee, then you need to automate. A lot. Often that means signing up for other people’s software products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will take some time to get there on a bootstrapped shoestring budget, but you’ll get those 100 customers eventually. Just stick to the gameplan and stay tuned into your market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="saas"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="bootstrapping"></category><category term="business-strategy"></category><category term="finance"></category></entry><entry><title>Hiring feels a lot different when it's your own money</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2017/11/01/hiring-feels-a-lot-different-when-its-your-own-money/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-11-01T13:08:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-11-01T13:08:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2017-11-01:/2017/11/01/hiring-feels-a-lot-different-when-its-your-own-money/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently posted a (https://www.toofr.com/jobs) to help me with a bunch of tactical stuff for Toofr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need help writing, SEO position tracking, supporting customers, and generally moving the ball downfield on all of my websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I posted on Craigslist, HireClub, and Remoteok.io. Over the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently posted a (https://www.toofr.com/jobs) to help me with a bunch of tactical stuff for Toofr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need help writing, SEO position tracking, supporting customers, and generally moving the ball downfield on all of my websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I posted on Craigslist, HireClub, and Remoteok.io. Over the last few days I received about 50 emails and set up calls with a dozen of them. I’ve asked two of those people I called to do a SEO assignment for me as a final step. I’m currently waiting to hear back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been a nerve-wracking experience. Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel really sensitive about compensation. The rest of the process was, for the most part, by the hiring playbook we developed at Scripted. We simply offered market rates, maybe a bit lower, and that was that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I feel differently now, of course, is obvious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Scripted, and this would be true for any venture-backed startup, you’re not really spending your own money. If you make a mistake, it hurts, but it doesn’t impact your own paycheck. You shrug it off and try again, careful not to waste any additional time and money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Toofr, it’s not that simple. The money I’m paying to this marketer is coming directly out of my paycheck. It’s basically like I’m opening up my own wallet and paying them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve hired contractors before but that was before Toofr became my main source of income. When it really was just a side project I felt more generous. I cared less and, frankly, I didn’t have a choice. I needed the help because I was at Scripted all day and if Toofr broke I needed someone else to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do everything but it’s probably not the &lt;em&gt;best &lt;/em&gt;thing for me to do. I need to specialize if Toofr’s going to graduate into the $30K MRR club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re bootstrapped the stakes are higher. Hiring the wrong person is not something you can just shrug off if you don’t get right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time it’s much more personal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="hiring"></category><category term="bootstrapping"></category><category term="toofr"></category><category term="business-strategy"></category></entry><entry><title>The definition of parallel entrepreneurship</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2017/10/27/parallel-entrepreneurship-defined/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-27T20:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-27T20:20:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2017-10-27:/2017/10/27/parallel-entrepreneurship-defined/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/a2d87-16ltjqklmrny90acqqj8vvg.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You don’t quit your day job and then build a startup. You build a startup and then quit your day job.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no reason anymore to go full-time into any one thing. If you have the itch to try your …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/a2d87-16ltjqklmrny90acqqj8vvg.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You don’t quit your day job and then build a startup. You build a startup and then quit your day job.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no reason anymore to go full-time into any one thing. If you have the itch to try your hand at starting a business, then you should do it while your employer limits your risk with a regular paycheck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing a lot of people seem to forget is that you can start and run and grow a real business that makes a meaningful amount of money just during nights and weekends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does mean some amount of sacrifice. You won’t be able to do this and keep up with the latest Warriors trades and Game of Thrones episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these are much better sacrifices to make than losing a paycheck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here’s why it’s important. It’s getting harder and harder to raise equity financing. The bar is so high by the time you actually check all the investors’ boxes you wouldn’t actually need their money anymore. When you’re a new entrepreneur the finance guys need to de-risk as much as possible and they do that by asking you to be flawless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, it’s getting harder and harder to earn revenue. Customers are getting harder to grab because starting internet businesses is getting easier. Simply put, there’s more competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently launched my sixth website app in the last 12 months. Of those six, only two are making money. My main source of income now, (https://www.toofr.com), was a side business I started nearly four years ago. Now I live off of it and with every new venture I start, I’m even more grateful to have even one business that works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took that long — four years of nights and weekends—to get this business to a state where I can live comfortably off of it. It seems these days it might take four years of full-time effort to yield the same result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having multiple income streams is the ultimate insurance. It’s the same idea that financial fund managers use. Better to diversify your investments. Don’t be all in on tech stocks or bonds or index funds. You should mix high risk and low risk investments whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors don’t move their money serially. They don’t go 100% into stocks, then 100% into bonds, and then move everything into some other instrument?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No way! They hold a mixture of all them simultaneously. In parallel. Spread across multiple markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should do the same with your career. You don’t need to rely on a spouse or partner to have the stable or high risk job. You can have them both, yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So go and be a parallel entrepreneur. Build a startup while keeping your day job.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="parallel-entrepreneurship"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="business-strategy"></category><category term="career"></category><category term="advice"></category></entry><entry><title>Parallel entrepreneur profile: John Zimmer, Lyft</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2017/08/14/parallel-entrepreneur-john-zimmer-lyft/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-14T11:06:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-08-14T11:06:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2017-08-14:/2017/08/14/parallel-entrepreneur-john-zimmer-lyft/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;John Zimmer studied hospitality management at Cornell. He graduated in 2006 and joined Lehman Brothers, a prestigious investment bank, in order to get a better finance background but found himself bored within the first year of a two-year analyst program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Logan Green, a friend of a friend, posted on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;John Zimmer studied hospitality management at Cornell. He graduated in 2006 and joined Lehman Brothers, a prestigious investment bank, in order to get a better finance background but found himself bored within the first year of a two-year analyst program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Logan Green, a friend of a friend, posted on Facebook that he was building a carpooling website, John got interested. A course he took in college emphasized that overconsumption of resources will ultimately threaten human survival. The lessons stuck with him but he wasn’t inspired yet to work on a solution. The carpooling service idea struck a chord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, Logan was in Santa Barbara and John was working in New York City. The two connected online and met for the first time in person when Logan traveled to New York a few weeks later. They hit it off and decided to collaborate on Logan’s idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John stayed at Lehman Brothers for another year while Logan built the website and John hammered away on marketing campaigns and partnerships at college campuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He kept his day job while working on a side project that had no overlap or potential conflicts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2008, when Zimride, the carpooling site, was running and making money, he quit Lehman Brothers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friends and family thought he was crazy. “Why would you quit on a sure thing like Lehman?” they’d ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lehman Brothers went bankrupt three months later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Zimmer is now co-founder and major shareholder of a business with 1,500 employees that is worth north of $5 billion.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="john-zimmer"></category><category term="lyft"></category><category term="profiles"></category><category term="parallel-entrepreneurship"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category></entry><entry><title>Why company values are important</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2015/07/08/why-company-values-are-important/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-08T21:43:00-07:00</published><updated>2015-07-08T21:43:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2015-07-08:/2015/07/08/why-company-values-are-important/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At Scripted's last company-wide retreat in Santa Cruz, we finally presented something that’s been years in the making: Scripted’s company values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many companies, we have unspoken values. We like to hire scrappy people who enjoy working hard. They’re usually humble and don’t expect special treatment …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At Scripted's last company-wide retreat in Santa Cruz, we finally presented something that’s been years in the making: Scripted’s company values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many companies, we have unspoken values. We like to hire scrappy people who enjoy working hard. They’re usually humble and don’t expect special treatment. You feel this humility when you walk into our office, and see it in the way we interact with each other. I’ve always been very proud of this. We have our own way of doing things, and most of the time there is consensus on the path forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as we’ve grown, that consensus has been harder to find. We’ll have differing views on prospective job candidates, new and existing office perks, and our product roadmap. When we talked through these problems, we’d sometimes find ourselves talking in circles. We needed a rubric by which to evaluate our most difficult questions and answers. That rubric has become our seven company values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are our company values, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scrappiness- Passion- Intrinsic Motivation- Selflessness- Friendliness- Openness- Simplicity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Values create a common language that motivates and bonds us. Values shape and define our company culture, which means that they also impact our growth and productivity. These values that we’ve created and documented dictate how we run our company, and how we work with both clients and employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some ways that your own company values can be used in everyday workplace scenarios:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Hiring&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many employers believe in the old saying that you should trade 90 percent of employee talent for 10 percent of character. In other words, character and willingness to fit in with a corporate culture are even more valuable to a company than talent and experience. By using your company values as a guide, you can identify whether a prospective employee has the traits to fit in with the rest of your team. If passion and selflessness are part of your values, make sure that these characteristics are part of your hiring criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Making Tough Decisions and Solving Problems&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Company values can help you make important decisions. When solving problems, values can remind you of your priorities and help you get back to basics when things get complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Spending&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re wondering how values can play a part in your company spending practices, consider the core meaning of a value like “scrappiness.” Scrappiness means that you’re willing to work in a low-frills environment that prizes concentration and focus over unnecessary distractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launching New Products&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passion plays a huge part in launching new products or services. If you foster a company culture of passion and enthusiasm, it will be evident to your audience, and there’s nothing more infectious than enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Marketing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Values can play a huge part in your marketing campaigns. Consider this: If your company has a reputation for openness and honesty, then you’ve already gone a long way in establishing client trust. It starts with company culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Values are the glue that keeps us working together in the same direction, using a common language and motivating factors which we call our Scripted company values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's our official Slideshare: (http://www.slideshare.net/Emaccoll/scripteds-company-values-presentation)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="scripted"></category><category term="leadership"></category><category term="business-strategy"></category><category term="company-culture"></category></entry></feed>