<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>rbucks.com - food-cooking</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rbucks.com/feeds/food-cooking.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rbucks.com/</id><updated>2017-01-02T12:18:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Buckley’s grilled cowboy rib eye steaks</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2017/01/02/buckleys-grilled-cowboy-rib-eyes/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-02T12:18:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-01-02T12:18:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2017-01-02:/2017/01/02/buckleys-grilled-cowboy-rib-eyes/</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;!({static}/images/a728c-1hiag9lulzmwfvtxuz7qwqg.jpeg?w=400)- !({static}/images/f2f1c-1y4vw-w8d5an3wcvcfzoplg.jpeg?w=399)- !({static}/images/a6fef-16alve8xi7ilntwepjysmtq.jpeg?w=400)- !({static}/images/b1020-1lgbesqsx5vu6icdd8uo4dg.jpeg?w=400)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the recipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get some big ass cowboy rib eye steaks. Bone-in because you’re not a wimp and you’re willing to pay $17 …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;!({static}/images/a728c-1hiag9lulzmwfvtxuz7qwqg.jpeg?w=400)- !({static}/images/f2f1c-1y4vw-w8d5an3wcvcfzoplg.jpeg?w=399)- !({static}/images/a6fef-16alve8xi7ilntwepjysmtq.jpeg?w=400)- !({static}/images/b1020-1lgbesqsx5vu6icdd8uo4dg.jpeg?w=400)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the recipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get some big ass cowboy rib eye steaks. Bone-in because you’re not a wimp and you’re willing to pay $17 per pound for some carbon. Seriously, shell out. These two bad boys costed $64 at Whole Foods. Hurt so good!- Sprinkle LIBERALLY with salt. Yes, like Bernie Sanders liberally.- Use a rub if you have one. I got a thoughtful present of various Williams Sonoma rubs and appreciate the simplicity of it. It’s a higher level of abstraction than looking up a recipe, discovering I’m missing the damn nutmeg, and wondering if that’s why the taste is off. It’s not wimpy to use a rub.- Let them sit at room temperature for 30–60 minutes before grilling. I’m not sure why, but every damn grilling blog on the planet says you should, so I will too. And I did it and although I’m not sure what effect it had, my steaks turned out GREAT.- Because they’re so thick, you have to do the “reverse sear.” That just elitist grilling speak for “save the direct flame for the end.” Your steak might look weird for the first 30 mins, but it’s ok. They’ll be fine.- So, warm the grill to about 350 degrees. Keep the temp between 325 and 350 the entire time. Since I have three burners, I put the outer two burners on low and kept the middle burner off. Works a treat.- Both of these steaks are 2.5–3in thick, and I set a timer for 17 minutes per side. I only flipped once.- For the sear, I turned up the flame on one side of the grill and put both steaks over it for 2 mins. Then flipped and set the 2 min timer again.- By the way, for all of these cooking times, you’re cooking with the lid closed. You know that, ya?- Also, if you have kids like me or are highly distracted for other reasons, the timer is a good idea. You don’t want to overcook your $64 steaks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I’ll tell you what. This was the best steak I’ve ever made. It was kind of by accident too. I have Instacart to thank. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to grill a good rib eye on my last weekend of paternity leave / winter break / 2016. Having two kids now and all, going grocery shopping is a bridge too far, so we were delighted when Instacart showed up in Walnut Creek. I put 2 pieces down in my order and was more than shocked when I saw the $64 tag on the meat wrapper. Wow. I never would have done it if I’d done the shopping in person. But I’m so glad my Instacart person knew me so well. This person isn’t afraid to throw down for the best steak on earth, he or she must have thought. Let’s go big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, mystery shopper!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="food-cooking"></category><category term="food"></category><category term="cooking"></category><category term="recipes"></category><category term="grilling"></category><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Pinecrest buttermilk waffles</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2016/09/18/pinecrest-buttermilk-waffles/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-18T07:52:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-18T07:52:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2016-09-18:/2016/09/18/pinecrest-buttermilk-waffles/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Here’s my family’s secret recipe for buttermilk waffles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear internet, here is a treat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, a long, long, time ago, a relative of mine brought a waffle iron up to (https://rbucks.com/2019/03/03/my-happy-place/) of the lake in Pinecrest, California. Not knowing …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Here’s my family’s secret recipe for buttermilk waffles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear internet, here is a treat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, a long, long, time ago, a relative of mine brought a waffle iron up to (https://rbucks.com/2019/03/03/my-happy-place/) of the lake in Pinecrest, California. Not knowing what else to make with it, another relative of mine (my grandmother, I’m told), modified a buttermilk waffle recipe and posted it on the inside of a cabinet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year for 34 years I’ve enjoyed these waffles. It’s the hallmark of my summer. I write now, dear internet, to share this goodness with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/d3f90-17j231ywynawp08s-iwo4uq.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there it has stayed since long before I was born. You can see the weathering on the scotch tape from decades of summers and winters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ingredients are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 7/8 cups of flour
2 cups buttermilk
2 teaspoons sugar
1/2 teaspoon salt
1 teaspoon baking soda
1 1/2 teaspoons baking powder
4 tablespoons melted butter
2 eggs beaten&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I once tried to find the recipe online. It’s similar to a Betty Crocker recipe, but like I said, it got modified over the years. Perhaps for the higher elevation, perhaps for the crazy old waffle iron. I don’t know. But you’ll find that these waffles are perfect. Here’s the optimized instructions for how to make them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put all of the dry ingredients into an ancient flour sifter. (You might check in the back of one of your cabinets, behind the navy beans and Quaker Oats). Sift into a large bowl until you have a nice fine powder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/5c09f-1uijd2bcmab-zktpqa1-aba.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the buttermilk next. You can get some at the general store on the other side of the lake. Fold it in, don’t beat it. Beating your batter will make your waffles chewy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/e02ab-1e_jxwwznao1r97pkkdnnpq.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the melted butter. Bacon grease works well too, especially if you have some already cooking behind you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/826ad-1ck4vdwpihy_tr8twxec2zw.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whisk your eggs into a froth. Hand egg beaters are an excellent choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/19a85-1urvsik6qza4tpbx-mzrt6g.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fold in the eggs. Again, don’t over-mix or beat the batter. It’ll take several folds, but your batter is ready as soon as the golden egg froth disappears. Do this part slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set the stage. Melted butter is great for waffle iron preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/38a05-1mbcwzsgfqg_2u5rucsejyq.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your waffle batter should fall easily off of a spoon and form patty-like shapes on the waffle iron.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/3621b-1xq8cvb6r7k8jahfqhee6na.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoy, of course! You’ll get a feel for when the waffle is at a golden crisp. It just takes practice. Always eat with real butter and maple syrup. Never the fake stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/152e1-11-lqmplqcawncxcdsjqo3g.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And share with people you love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/3b13b-124nz1gie9v63bv1yby8ujw.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="food-cooking"></category><category term="food"></category><category term="cooking"></category><category term="recipes"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="personal"></category></entry></feed>