<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>rbucks.com - health-fitness</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rbucks.com/feeds/health-fitness.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rbucks.com/</id><updated>2023-04-08T20:59:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>An exploration of deep exhaustion</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2023/04/08/an-exploration-of-deep-exhaustion/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-08T20:59:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-08T20:59:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2023-04-08:/2023/04/08/an-exploration-of-deep-exhaustion/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This month I plan to push my endurance to the outer limits. I rode my bicycle 142 miles in just under 12 hours a week ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week from now, I will do it again, but with twice the vertical climb. It will be my second year in a row …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This month I plan to push my endurance to the outer limits. I rode my bicycle 142 miles in just under 12 hours a week ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week from now, I will do it again, but with twice the vertical climb. It will be my second year in a row doing the (https://www.belgianwaffleride.bike/pages/california), a day-long ride on road, gravel, and sandy dirt trails in the hills above San Marcos, California. It's a silly 135 miles and 11,000 feet of climb. That's the equivalent of riding around the base of Mt. Diablo twice and hitting the summit three times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who does a ride like that? Me, apparently. It's becoming clearer to me why I like doing it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term "deep exhaustion" comes to mind when I think about why I do this. I googled it. Deep exhaustion has mostly negative connotations, like when you hit a wall of fatigue and can't break through it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not the deep exhaustion I'm referring to. This type of exhaustion sits in your bones but drives you forward. You somersault through the fatigue and come around to the other side of it. You find energy in the heavy cloak. Somehow, incomprehensibly, the deep exhaustion actually feels good. It's comforting because it's supposed to be there, and the thrill lies in seeing how long and how far you can carry it with you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the start of my 142-mile loop, it took about 40 miles and a bit over two hours for me to ride from my house in Lafayette to the estuary on the eastern side of the Dumbarton Bridge. That's when I got my first taste of tiredness. I stopped there and stretched. I filled my water bottles at a little trailhead visitor center structure. I took this picture there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/IMG_4207-1024x768.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was still feeling good. I stretched my legs, felt a twinge of cramp coming on but shook it off. I hopped back on and kept going. At 50 miles, I took a picture at the peak of the bridge span. I took my last picture as I entered Martinez from the north ninety miles later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;!({static}/images/IMG_4208-1024x768.jpeg)

!({static}/images/IMG_4216-1024x768.jpeg)
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I planned to circle the bay and cross five of the seven bridges (I couldn't fit San Mateo in and the Bay Bridge has no bike lane on the western span.) From the Dumbarton Bridge, I headed north up the western shore, through San Mateo, Redwood City, Belmont, and into SFO. The stretch along the airport is a drain. It's long and windy. Eventually, I crossed the freeway and hit another windy stretch opposite Candlestick Point, near the Cow Palace. This is the threshold between South San Francisco and SF proper. The Bayview / Hunter's Point district is not my favorite part of the city. I push up and then down the hills and onto the Chase Center and Oracle Park. I followed the Embarcadero around to the Golden Gate Bridge. This is about 85 miles from home. I cross into Sausalito, and a quick twenty miles later, I'm on the Richmond Bridge span. This is my third bridge with a wide, protected bicycle lane. I got a little lost (Garmin fail) between the Richmond Bridge and the Carquinez Bridge (the fourth), but I finally found it about 125 miles into the ride. Fifteen miles later, I hit the fifth bridge. Mission accomplished! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep exhaustion hit me right around mile 60. I carried it for another 80 miles. I'm proud that I lasted that long. It took work and preparation to do this. I trained by exercising regularly. I run, I swim, and I bike. I generally do one of them every other day. So my base fitness was good going into this monster ride. I stopped, stretched, and ate every 20 miles. I mentally rode in 5-mile increments, each one a step closer to my next break. At the sixty-mile mark, I was somewhere in Belmont and stopped at a Roam burger restaurant. I ate like a champion. Feeling better but still quite tired, I kept going. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty miles later, I was on the Embarcadero, tourists everywhere. I pulled to the side and forced a few handfuls of trail mix down my throat. I was tired, but I wasn't any more tired than I was at mile 60. That awareness gave me strength. I crossed the century mark in Larkspur. Again I wasn't any more tired than before, and I was excited to head back to the east bay. More energy. At mile 120, I was just north of Rodeo. I stopped on a bikeway right along the bayfront. I could feel my energy waning with the afternoon. I was about ten hours into the ride at this point, and I was concerned I wouldn't make it home before dark. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mile 140 was a short stop in Benicia. I fed myself, but I wasn't feeling great. The deep exhaustion was starting to wear me out. I crossed the Martinez Bridge and was already in the evening shadows. The sun was still up, but the hills to the west hid it. The temperature never broke 60F the whole ride, but I felt cold for the first time here. I rode a quiet street through a refinery to get to the main road connecting Martinez and Concord. I was uncomfortable, jittery, and hungry, but I couldn't eat any more of the food in my little backpack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I peddled forward, finally reaching the commercial stretch of Pleasant Hill. I saw a McDonald's and decided to stop. I ordered my food and sat haggardly, my helmet and gloves still on. I filled a cup with Dr. Pepper and ate my Big Mac. The evening turned to dusk, and I wasn't going to leave that McDonald's on my bike. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the last seven miles home in an Uber. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I survived. No close calls, no near collisions. I didn't let foolish pride get in my way of a safe ride home. At that point, I was in no condition to ride in the dark. I was able to push my limits without breaking them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that's what deep exhaustion is to me. It's the point where I push my endurance outward. I'm not a weightlifter, but I understand that muscle gets built on slow, consistent reps with heavier and heavier weights. Perhaps endurance works the same way. You grind your way to the outer limits, and you carry its heavy load in order to extend your stamina runway. Parts of the process are painful, but for the most part, it's fine. It's just a steady exertion for a long period of time. At some point, you can't go any further, but until then, you're just tired. Being tired, in the right context, can feel really good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm looking forward to the Belgian Waffle Ride next weekend. I know it will be hard. I know I'll bump up against the limits of my exhaustion. I'll do a better job with nutrition and fluids. I'll stop at every checkpoint, relax my body, eat, drink, and stretch. I'll take as much time as I need and try to enjoy the process for what it is: an exploration of deep exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And boy oh boy, I'll look forward to eating dinner afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="health-fitness"></category><category term="cycling"></category><category term="endurance-sports"></category><category term="fitness"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Why I run</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2022/01/02/why-i-run/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-01-02T20:47:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-02T20:47:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2022-01-02:/2022/01/02/why-i-run/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I run because I need to. When I don't run, I don't feel great. I need the exercise, I need the exhaustion, but most importantly, I need the time alone. I've found that I don't love running with other people. I'll do it because it makes me better at running …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I run because I need to. When I don't run, I don't feel great. I need the exercise, I need the exhaustion, but most importantly, I need the time alone. I've found that I don't love running with other people. I'll do it because it makes me better at running and introduces me to new routes and possibilities, but I'm happiest when I run alone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/870B29A7-D99C-4A64-8C34-38A441F4CDCA_1_105_c-683x1024.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run because it feels good. I'm pushing 40 now and my achilles and ankles take a few minutes to warm up. I feel them when I take those first few steps down my driveway. I know that the little aches and pains will go away within 10 minutes. I'll be just over a mile away from my house by then, and happy to have at least another hour ahead of me. A good run for me takes about an hour and a half. That's when the little bits of pain start to return, but in different places. I'll feel it first at the bottom of my feet. My heel will get a dull ache, and then that bony ball below my toes will join the chorus. This is when I know I've reached the outer limits of my running fitness. It usually comes after about two hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/56EB400D-BC3B-4BC6-B7E2-A76C403A5692_1_105_c.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run because it's fun to explore. I enjoy not knowing exactly where I'm going. When I discover a new route, I set out in a general direction uphill, figuring that two sides of a ridge must connect to a trail or road somewhere. I'll consult my Strava app's heat maps to make sure I have some hope of finding a loop, but once I'm out there I mostly rely on instinct. I did this a month ago, trying to turn the eight miles back from a park where my family took holiday pictures into a twelve-mile mostly trail run. I set on Bollinger Canyon Road, noting that after a few miles it appeared to dead-end into a trailhead. However, a neighbor told me there's a bunch of No Trespassing signs and some folks who aren't used to having visitors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deciding to trust Google and Strava more than my neighbor, I turned up that road and sweated my way to the end of it. I ran past dirt driveways and gurgling streams, through oak forests and grassy fields. Finally the road ended at a gate and a couple of dirt driveways. I met two guys there who looked at me inquisitively. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You &lt;em&gt;ran&lt;/em&gt; all the way up this road?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Yessir. I'm looking for a trail."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Well, there ain't no trail past here."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't believe him but I didn't push it. I ran back down the road, knowing that just on the other side of the ridge to the north I would find the network of trails on my map. When those guys were out of sight, I headed up a dirt driveway and followed it as far up the hill as I could before it turned into a much more private road close to someone's house. Seeing no semblance of a hiking trail anywhere, I turned around once more and headed back to the main road. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a quarter of a mile down, I decided to try again. This time it was a fire road that went straight up a steep grassy hillside in exactly the direction I needed to head. I set out, hopped a railing and climbed up to another cattle gate. Beyond it was the ridge, and on the ridge, I saw another trail heading toward the neighborhood of my daughter's elementary school. I figured I would be able to get back on a road over there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the ridge I looked to the north and west. It's another world. A small ranch and pond, another ridge with a few houses overlooking the valley. Clusters of oak trees and waves of green, flowing grass. I smiled on the inside. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why I run. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;!({static}/images/D16AE852-F852-4803-BD78-DFF40CE0E4B5_1_105_c.jpeg)

!({static}/images/5C4931D5-AE57-4F3A-8C49-65DB35DD247B_1_105_c.jpeg)

!({static}/images/286B2AC8-90D7-49A1-823A-388E017C09DA_1_105_c.jpeg)

!({static}/images/IMG_2851-1024x768.jpeg)

!({static}/images/B7D5C0F0-99C1-445F-8316-0482979CC99C_1_102_o-473x1024.jpeg)

!({static}/images/F5BA0430-8947-4792-851D-891F98D8ACD0_1_105_c.jpeg)

!({static}/images/77F1F466-83AD-4333-A63F-0BEC8B1DC1F7_1_105_c.jpeg)

!({static}/images/IMG_2853-1024x768.jpeg)
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><category term="health-fitness"></category><category term="running"></category><category term="fitness"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="exercise"></category></entry><entry><title>And now, a bit of certainty</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2019/04/27/and-now-a-bit-of-certainty/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-27T21:33:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-27T21:33:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2019-04-27:/2019/04/27/and-now-a-bit-of-certainty/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you're new to my cancer saga, here are parts (https://rbucks.com/2017/06/24/my-thyroid-got-cancer/) and (https://rbucks.com/2018/02/22/my-thyroid-got-cancer-one-year-later/). Part three is coming along in a couple of sittings like (https://rbucks.com/2019/02/13/the-thing-that-wont-go-away/) (https://rbucks.com/2019/03/22/here-i-go-again …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you're new to my cancer saga, here are parts (https://rbucks.com/2017/06/24/my-thyroid-got-cancer/) and (https://rbucks.com/2018/02/22/my-thyroid-got-cancer-one-year-later/). Part three is coming along in a couple of sittings like (https://rbucks.com/2019/02/13/the-thing-that-wont-go-away/) (https://rbucks.com/2019/03/22/here-i-go-again/). It's the part where after I get diagnosed with papillary thyroid cancer, get it removed, and carry on with a bit of cloud hanging over my head, the cloud comes into focus. Now I know what's next. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you hadn't heard, cancer sucks. If it doesn't kill your body, it tries to kill your spirit, your innocence, your optimism that you can fight and handle anything if you just eat healthy, work out, and be nice to people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, cancer doesn't give a fucking shit about any of it. I could be a paleo-keto-vegan monk teaching orphans how to meditate. I'd still have this fucking cancer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last two years, my biggest concern about my experience with cancer was not my missing thyroid or the pills I have to take, it was the uncertainty that it might still be there, lurking in the shadows of my neck. My blood tests didn't &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; pass muster. My ultrasounds and MRIs were not &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; pristine. Something was afoot, and the evidence kept pointing back to this one rogue lymph node. An asymmetric blob that my docs at Kaiser found and my docs at John Muir Medical Center finally biopsied. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's where I left off last time. The follow-up involved an MRI to thoroughly case my neck, explicitly looking for more funny business. Neck MRI scans, because this area of the body is so complex, take a while. The technician told me that these are the longest scans they do. For forty-five minutes I'm squished in a tube, unable to move my upper body, with earplugs in my ears to muddle out the crazy thumping and bumping sounds that the MRI machine makes. It's the worst. I'm grateful for the technology. I'm glad that I have insurance and can afford the copay. But boy do I wish I didn't have to get MRIs of my neck. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been coupling these cancer hospital appointments with swim workouts. The motion of my body and the sound of the water feels cleansing, like a baptism. Hospitals, for all of their sterility, feel dirty to me. It's like I need to wash the hospital air right off of me. Hospitals are for sick people. I'm not sick. At least I don't feel like it, don't think it, don't act like it. And technically I'm not sick, even though at this very moment I have papillary thyroid cancer in a lymph node near my clavicle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've made the mistake of reading through the (https://www.reddit.com/r/cancer/). It is not a place for the faint of heart. These are real tragedies. My saga is a fairy tale compared to many people writing on that forum. I can't complain, but I do because it's only natural to gripe when something's not fair, even when other innocent people have it worse. Far worse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was on Reddit that I learned a new word, "scanxiety." It's the fear of finding out your test results, the moment when your doctor's number shows up on your phone and you realize that in mere seconds you will find out if the news you've been waiting for is good or bad. Did the numbers go up or down? Is it better or worse? Am I going to live a long life or die next month? After every scan there's more scanxiety waiting for you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was how I felt after the MRI. After the biopsy I was fully prepared for the bad news. It was pretty obvious that Dr. B thought they'd find cancer. What she didn't know is if, given that biopsy, there would be evidence of other cancers in my neck. It's not unusual in papillary thyroid cancer for it to spread in the local lymph nodes. However, for this particular cancer, even with the spread it is technically a Stage 1 cancer. Meaning, even without this positive biopsy, I'd be a Stage 1 papillary thyroid cancer patient. Having the one positive lymph node doesn't change the stage. To be Stage 2 they'd have to find it beyond the lymph nodes in my neck. It was possible the MRI could show this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yes indeed, I had scanxiety when the report came back, first via email, and then via a phone call from Dr. B's office. I remember I got the email when I was putting my younger daughter to bed. When she's drifting off, I rub her back with one hand and play chess or crossword puzzles on my phone with my other. The email alert popped up and I saw it was a test result from John Muir Hospital. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly I have two hands on the phone. My breathing is a bit shorter. My lips tense and contract. I try to calm myself as I open the message, click on the link, and log in. I wait for the screen to load, click on the test, and read the results. I scan for the punchline and find it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more bad news. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! Finally, some certainty. My bad news stops with one lymph node, and that can be dealt with using a little bit of radioactive iodine. In my position this is as good as it gets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now I'm waiting for my insurance and the pharmacy to do their dance and tell me how much more savings I have to put into my treatment. For the first time in my life, I will probably hit my out-of-pocket maximum. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm grateful for insurance, and also that I can afford it, but man oh man. If cancer wasn't scary enough, the cancer treatment bills make it even scarier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life goes on though. You make money, you spend it. We'll see what happens next.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="health-fitness"></category><category term="cancer"></category><category term="thyroid-cancer"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category></entry><entry><title>I don't use shampoo</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2019/03/03/i-dont-use-shampoo/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-03T22:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-03-03T22:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2019-03-03:/2019/03/03/i-dont-use-shampoo/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, I stopped putting weird liquid soap in my hair every time I showered. The decision point happened amidst a profound and literal "shower thought." I picked up a bottle of shampoo, looked at it, and thought, “Why am I doing this, again?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I stopped doing …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, I stopped putting weird liquid soap in my hair every time I showered. The decision point happened amidst a profound and literal "shower thought." I picked up a bottle of shampoo, looked at it, and thought, “Why am I doing this, again?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I stopped doing it. That was a long time ago and I've never looked back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I do shower regularly. If I didn’t, I’d start to stink pretty fast. I like a good shower and I always use bar soap. I don’t put that habit in the same category as shampooing every day, which I deem entirely unnecessary. I also do occasionally shampoo my hair with actual shampoo, bar soap, or body wash if it's handy and I think my hair needs it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But honestly, what makes everyone think hair should be washed with soap every day? And when that shampoo dries out your scalp and hair, what do we do? We put this weird lubricant "conditioner" in it. We're replacing the natural oil we washed out of our hair with fake manufactured stuff. The instructions tell us to swap our natural hair oils for fake hair oils every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? Well, that answer is obvious. These shampoo companies need to grow! They use every social selling trick in the book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Urgency&lt;/strong&gt;: Do this every day, even twice a day, for best results. - &lt;strong&gt;Social proof&lt;/strong&gt;: Everyone else is doing it. Don't be the weirdo who doesn't shampoo (me!)- &lt;strong&gt;Escalation of commitment&lt;/strong&gt;: Start with our shampoo, graduate to our conditioner. Start with once a day, expand to twice per day. - &lt;strong&gt;Benefits&lt;/strong&gt;: Fuller, silkier, shinier hair. (Same as it would be if you just thoroughly rinsed with water.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've decided to do some research and look into what exactly &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; shampoo. And while I'm at it, what the heck is soap?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is soap?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remembered learning about phospholipids in high school chemistry. It stuck with me because it was a real-world application of science. These molecules are polar: one end  is hyprophilic (attracted to water molecules) and the other is hydrophobic (not so much). This is important because the polar ends of the soap molecule allow it to dissolve water into oils, breaking them up the globs of oil and "cleaning" them out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've ever made brownies (I'm quite a pro) you may remember some recipes that call for a fraction of a cup of both water and oil. You mix them into a bowl (often with an egg) and you can immediately see that the oil and water don't mix. They just gel around each other. This happens because oil is nonpolar while water has a charge on both ends (remember how H20 is positive on one side and negative on the other -- it's ionic!) So since water has nothing to grab a hold of, it doesn't mix into the oil. Soap fixes this by being neutral on one end and polar on the other, acting as a bridge between the oil and the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's how soap cleans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is shampoo?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shampoo is essentially a soap with some other stuff mixed in, including water. I read that shampoo is actually 60-70% water and the soap component comes in a few different varieties, but the most common form are "sodium laurel ether sulphates." This term describes the chemical structure but the important thing for us to know is they are biodegradable and create a foaming effect when mixing into your hair. Other chemicals are added to thicken the shampoo and prevent bacteria growth (yummy!) and make it all smell like a summer rose garden. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What are the downsides of shampooing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main one is indeed the gripe that I described earlier. Shampoo strips hair of its sebum, which is a natural, slightly yellow oily substance that glands in our skin secrete to keep our skin and hair moisturized. In the context of your head, sebum protects your hair shaft from getting brittle, dry, and breaking off. When shampoo strips that sebum away, hair can get in bad shape. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why the shampoo industry invented conditioners, which replaces the natural sebum that shampoo removed with fake, manufactured sebum, that you get to buy at Walgreens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the chemical industry-inspired cycle we're supposed to follow goes something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dirt and sweat get in our hair through the process of being alive.- Rather than washing it out with water or a bit of soap, we're supposed to lather our whole head, twice even, and stripe our hair of dirt, sweat, and everything good that our body produces to keep our hair healthy.- Replace the good natural hair oils (sebum) with inferior chemical ones.- Repeat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, for one, am not buying it, and neither should you. However, I understand it can be a bit jarring to make the change. Instead, I encourage you to try it out. Skip shampooing for a day, then two. Wash thoroughly with water instead. It may take a few days, but eventually, you won't notice a difference. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll save money and let your body do what it's supposed to do: keep you healthy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="health-fitness"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="lifestyle"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="self-improvement"></category></entry><entry><title>My thyroid got cancer: one year later</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2018/02/22/my-thyroid-got-cancer-one-year-later/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-22T22:45:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-22T22:45:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2018-02-22:/2018/02/22/my-thyroid-got-cancer-one-year-later/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a follow-up to my first article, (https://rbucks.com/2017/06/24/my-thyroid-got-cancer/).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultrasounds are soothing. The whir of the machine, the doctor’s thoughtful grunts as she probes my neck, the crackle of the paper on the examination table. It is very familiar to me now …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a follow-up to my first article, (https://rbucks.com/2017/06/24/my-thyroid-got-cancer/).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultrasounds are soothing. The whir of the machine, the doctor’s thoughtful grunts as she probes my neck, the crackle of the paper on the examination table. It is very familiar to me now. I relax into it and close my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think about my kids. I see my older daughter sitting on the couch, her attention wafting between the television and me. She smiles and rolls onto her stomach. Her younger sister is there too, waddling around the living room, looking for attention. There’s sunshine coming through our large windows. It’s warm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the scene in my mind every time I lie down on that examination table. It starts with the doctor squirting gel onto the ultrasound probe. It ends when she lifts the probe off my neck. The tension in the room lifts and I look at her face for signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t get any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently my endocrinologist was looking for a rogue lymph node that caused concern during my last ultrasound a month ago. She wanted to find it, pull out some tissue, and order a biopsy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked briefly and I laid down on the examination table. The paper crackled beneath me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Okay, let’s see where this thing is,” she said slowly and squirted that gel onto the ultrasound probe. I closed my eyes and saw my daughters again. The sun was still shining. I watched them play the game of chase they invented, running back and forth between the kitchen table and the mini lounge chairs they have near the couch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was sitting in my own lounge chair, wafting back and forth between my daughters and the ultrasound probe. I could tell something was up last time. The technician kept returning to one part of my neck. It lasted longer than usual. The next day I got the email I expected: they found an abnormal lymph node and I’d probably need to get a biopsy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the ultrasound is also taking a while. My daughters looked at me, bored, asking what we were going to play next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know,” I tell them, starting to feel nervous and agitated. “I thought you were going to keep playing chase?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultrasound probe lifts and I’m brought back to the examination room. I shift my weight and the paper crackles beneath me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think I got anything,” explained my doctor. “There’s so much tissue in the neck and these lymph nodes are really small. Every time I thought I saw it it disappeared again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She punched some notes into the computer. “Let’s order you an MRI just to be safe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She explained that the MRI results would help her definitively identify any rogue lymph nodes and also help a neck surgeon find and remove any other cancers. I picked an appointment a few days later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An MRI is not relaxing. I closed my eyes as I was conveyed into the GE-branded plastic cave in a fancy trailer outside of my local Kaiser hospital. I wasn’t comfortable. My hair was caught behind my head, causing a slight pull that was just painful enough to prevent me from tuning it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came the knocks, the chest-pounding thuds that reminded me of those times I’d find myself near the subwoofer at a nightclub. My clothes shook. I opened my eyes and looked through the Hannibal Lecter-like mask constraining my head. There was nothing to see so I closed my eyes again, forcing myself to think about something, anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pictured my girls but they looked scared, worried for me, confused about where I was and why I was so tense. I didn’t want to explain so instead I thought about work. I picked a programming problem and analyzed it. I had the full day ahead of me so I thought about what else I wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much longer? More knocking, screeching, buzzing. Finally, the tech tells me through the speaker that he’s going to pull me out and inject me with a solution to provide contrast to the “pictures” he was taking of my neck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great, more needles. I try to stay upbeat as he tries a couple of times to find my vein. I roll back into the cave and the symphony of jackhammers, machine guns, and subwoofing bass strikes up again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I’m free. I thank the kind bearded man at the MRI controls and appreciate the endless sky above me. They asked me on the screening form if I was claustrophobic. I said no but now I’m not so sure. I really didn’t like being in that tiny plastic hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I waited for the results. I didn’t have to wait long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love my neighborhood for many reasons, but the biggest one is my neighbors. On my street there is a first grade teacher, a web designer, an executive director of an education non-profit, and a radiologist. A radiologist at Kaiser. The same Kaiser where I had my MRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So of course in the days leading up to my ultrasound and MRI I gave him the play-by-play as our kids scooted around the cul de sac. He knows cancer better than anyone I know. He sees it every day, in every part of the body, and when I was first diagnosed he too told me that thyroid cancer is the best of them. He told me he would be working the morning of my MRI. When I left the trailer I texted him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/9c923-1eqwcpmepbrtrzwhmzpt8ya.png)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That afternoon his two boys were out playing so I went out with my two girls, beer in hand. I could tell when he walked down the driveway that he didn’t want to tell me his read on my MRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yea,” he began. “The node your endocrinologist couldn’t find? It’s there and I found a couple other irregular ones too.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t say anything yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“She’ll probably want to get them checked out. Sorry man.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked him a couple questions and then let my disappointment set in. I’d been optimistic, hopeful that whatever the original ultrasound found was simply due to one of the many winter bugs my daughter brought home from preschool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my inevitable googling of lymph node maladies I read that they swell and change shape when there’s an infection nearby. It was perfectly reasonable that an enlarged lymph node would be caused by a throat infection rather than cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My neighbor didn’t use the c-word but that uncertainty was the hardest part. My MRI was on the Friday of President’s Day weekend. I probably wouldn’t hear my endocrinologists’ read on it until Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That meant a whole weekend wafting in cancer limbo. I was able to tune it out, though, and decided to focus on things that I can control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can control how I feel. I can choose not to be nervous, anxious, and desperate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can control what I do. I can eat well, exercise, and do things that make me happy and remove other anxieties from my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t control cancers without medical help but I can at least manage what I feel and do. I reminded myself of this throughout that weekend and into the following week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I heard from endocrinologist and it was mostly good news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was delayed in getting back to me because she wanted a few more opinions on my chart. There was consensus that the irregularities in these lymph nodes in my neck were more likely caused by normal infections rather than cancers. She would bring my case to her monthly board review to get more feedback but that’s where it stands now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relief. For now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been intimately familiar with cancer for over a year already. It’s hard to put myself in the place I was before. Post-cancer I’m more grateful, more conscious, more vulnerable, more motivated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d never been “sick.” I don’t take aspirin or Tylenol or Advil when I get headaches. Before this cancer stuff I saw a doctor every two years. At the most. Now it’s every three months. Now I have to take two pills every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t like it but I’m getting used to it. I’m getting used to the latent uncertainty too, the anxiety that never goes away. That’s maybe the one thing that all cancer patients share. Some cases are worse than others. Most cases are worse than mine. But we all know that cancer can strike any time. It can come back, it can get worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That fact is you’re never really cancer-free. Sadly, no one is. You can spend your time worrying about that, a problem you can’t fix, or focus on what you can control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Control what you feel. Control what you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That gives me power and that makes me happy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="health-fitness"></category><category term="cancer"></category><category term="thyroid-cancer"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category></entry><entry><title>Learning to hike</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2017/11/24/when-i-finally-learned-to-hike/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-11-24T20:42:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-11-24T20:42:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2017-11-24:/2017/11/24/when-i-finally-learned-to-hike/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/2b401-1ukfvhllbfjaefeqtqiufbq.jpeg)
&lt;em&gt;One of the many hiking trails&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/4b59c-18ezr2ezsrhpgqzbzii_0pw.jpeg)
&lt;em&gt;Fall in Briones Regional Park, about 20 miles east of San Francisco.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up going on hikes but it wasn’t until this year, at age 35, that I learned how to hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/2b401-1ukfvhllbfjaefeqtqiufbq.jpeg)
&lt;em&gt;One of the many hiking trails&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/4b59c-18ezr2ezsrhpgqzbzii_0pw.jpeg)
&lt;em&gt;Fall in Briones Regional Park, about 20 miles east of San Francisco.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up going on hikes but it wasn’t until this year, at age 35, that I learned how to hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a confession to make. My relatives may be shocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last 35 years I didn’t really enjoy hiking. It’s just something I did because I was raised going to a lakeside cabin every summer. I loved Pinecrest Lake— I still do — but I looked forward to the cooking, the swimming, the reading on the hammock. Hiking for me was a sideshow, not the main attraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d hike for the sole purpose of reaching a destination like Cleo’s Bath, or Herring Creek, or around Pinecrest Lake to pick up some (https://medium.com/@rbucks/pinecrest-buttermilk-waffles-76709adc7c09) on the shore opposite my family’s cabin in the Sierras. I’d muster the energy and enthusiasm and head out and let my mind wander to pass the time faster between the start and the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Aunt Harriet and Uncle Dan take a completely different approach. They drive all around Pinecrest to various trailheads and do day hikes. The hikes are the activity. It’s not about which lake they went to or what peak they summited. The whole point was to hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always admired this about them but I didn’t understand it. How could you just… hike? I should know this. I should be one of them. My family has this unique mountain legacy but I didn’t become a hiker until this year and I wasn’t converted at Pinecrest Lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all happened in Briones Regional Park with my second daughter in tow behind me. It only took me 35 years to learn how to hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/30b87-1eceqk8b_yj3-oshgzps3pg.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/5d035-1van61vku2xbysfmywgiiuw.jpeg)
&lt;em&gt;One of about 100 hikes in the past two years. This one was on Norah’s first birthday.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve now probably gone on 100 hikes all around the east bay. Short hikes, long hikes, some with my older daughter, some with my younger daughter, and always with (https://medium.com/@rbucks/the-ascent-of-blue-1da38dbe855b).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in those 100 hikes a change happened. A point on the map was no longer the destination. The hike itself became the point, and I learned how to really truly enjoy it. I’d pay attention to the creeks to my left and the crests to my right. I’d notice how the shrubbery changes when water is nearby and how grassy meadows smell differently than oak forests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also learned the logic behind trails. A straight long climb probably follows a waterway. Those are my favorite trails. Those climbs eventually leave the creek and start to zigzag up a hillside and then there’s usually a trail along the ridge and another one back down the other side. Eventually a trail will traverse back to reconnect the two. Those are favorite kind of loops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now can tell how long a hike will take and I can keep a good sense of where the trailhead is relative to my position on the trail. I’ve never been lost (and fortunately Google has a lot of these trails mapped with accurate GPS placement) but with a baby on board it’s of course important to know how long it will take to get back to the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m accustomed now to hiking with a 30 pound baby on my back, jabbering and sleeping and tugging at the back of my hat. I also now know that there is such thing as being in good hiking shape. The first time I did some of these climbs I was completely winded and had to stop a few times on the way up. Now I do it in one go and reach the top sweating but not out of breath. Hiking is not the same thing as walking and it is a really good workout. It took me about 25 hikes to figure that out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiking no longer feels like work. I look forward to it every time. These days, with (https://medium.com/@rbucks/how-i-made-a-5-000-return-on-a-fancy-2-day-vacation-21b9100d3fb5) and without a nanny on Wednesdays and Fridays, I take Norah hiking while most dads are at work. Two hours on the trail in the morning goes by fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I want to find a new trail or do an old loop? How far out do I want to drive this time? How long ago did it rain? Does it look like the trail follows a creek?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the the questions that hikers ask. I’m glad to be among them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="health-fitness"></category><category term="hiking"></category><category term="fitness"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="lifestyle"></category></entry></feed>