<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>rbucks.com - personal</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rbucks.com/feeds/personal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rbucks.com/</id><updated>2025-02-17T21:07:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Short post of appreciation</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2025/02/17/short-post-of-appreciation/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-02-17T21:07:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-02-17T21:07:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2025-02-17:/2025/02/17/short-post-of-appreciation/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'd like to think that I take nothing for granted, that I'm always present and appreciative and live life to the fullest. None of this is true, of course. I get caught up in what I'm doing or the exact opposite, caught up on my screens, oblivious to what I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'd like to think that I take nothing for granted, that I'm always present and appreciative and live life to the fullest. None of this is true, of course. I get caught up in what I'm doing or the exact opposite, caught up on my screens, oblivious to what I or anyone around me is doing. Either way, I get sucked into the vortex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I can say with certainty is I have held myself to one standard: when my kid asks for my attention, I give it to them, and when they ask me to do something with them -- &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; with them -- I do it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is a holiday, President's Day, so my kids were not in school, but my wife and I worked. After dinner I did what I usually do while my kids are noodling around the house: I worked. I think I was editing a Snowflake query when I heard those magical words, "Dad, will you play chess with me?" &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did the right thing. I closed my MacBook and walked to the kitchen table where I keep a chessboard for this exact reason. While I played chess with my 8-year-old, my 10-year-old was practicing "Let It Be" on the piano. She was playing on the Yamaha Clavinova that I bought to replace the Baldwin piano that I inherited from my grandpa. Chess and piano. These are not the pieces of the puzzle that my wife brought to the picture. These are both mine, two hobbies that my kids adopted and seem to really enjoy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the rest of their lives, they'll know how to play chess. They'll appreciate the game. And at least one of my kids will know how to find middle C and play an A minor chord on piano. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did that, and it took work. It took leading by example and showing interest when they showed interest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm thinking about this tonight because yesterday my wife learned that her good friend was going through something awful. Her husband is on life support, perhaps from a heart attack, but we don't know. He's been in a coma for a week. They have two kids and a third child is due in five months. He may not make it. It's a tragedy on every dimension. I can't think of anything positive about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't help but think, "What if it was me?" What would I regret? What would my kids remember? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us hope to die surrounded by family. I still read the obituaries and most of the time that's what they say. There must be a reason for it. Family is in our DNA, ever present in our thoughts, a safe place in our souls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our friend's husband might die surrounded by family. He may not know it. He also might break the coma and live another healthy fifty years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time will tell, but in the meantime, I take this moment to appreciate what I've done well and what I'll still improve. Take it day by day, try to be present, and appreciate everything I love.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="appreciation"></category><category term="gratitude"></category><category term="lifestyle"></category></entry><entry><title>What I want in 2024</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2024/01/01/what-i-want-in-2024/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-01T18:02:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-01-01T18:02:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2024-01-01:/2024/01/01/what-i-want-in-2024/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If I do this right, the way I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to do it and believe that I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do it, this will be a big year for me. Maybe the biggest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I shared a couple of blog posts ago, (https://rbucks.com/2023/08/25/happy-41st-birthday-to-me/). Age is only a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If I do this right, the way I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to do it and believe that I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do it, this will be a big year for me. Maybe the biggest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I shared a couple of blog posts ago, (https://rbucks.com/2023/08/25/happy-41st-birthday-to-me/). Age is only a number, but it has become a symbol on a map. It's the sign post on the road, a ticking clock. Turning 41 in 2023 meant a lot to me. It meant roots, friendships, patterns, and routines. It meant kids that are getting older and more independent. It meant a marriage that lasted many times longer than the one between my mom and dad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted financial stability when my kids were young and we had a (https://rbucks.com/2016/03/22/an-ode-to-the-suburbs/) and then (https://rbucks.com/2021/11/14/how-we-did-our-home-addition-and-remodel/). Now it's different. I feel like I can dream big again. This past year set the stage. This next year is when I go for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Shovels to find product-market fit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this is going to be the year of (https://rbucks.com/2022/11/22/business-evaluation-shovels/). I've already gone all-in on this idea. I've raised $1.3M to date, and likely will raise another $200K more before hitting the upper limit on how much dilution we can take in this round. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the fundraising is important because we need it, the goal is to build a big business. Big to me, right now, is $10M ARR (annual recurring revenue). That's the target, and I'm willing to fight tooth and nail to get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The path that we'll take is selling to the enterprise. We have to sell bigger deals to bigger companies. The ability for me to hire a sales team depends on it. We'll still take the smaller customers -- I want to support climate tech startups -- but we can't spend time handholding them through the process. The product itself will need to do 99% of it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have 10 small customers. Our MRR (monthly recurring revenue) is already higher than my last two bootstrapped companies. This business is inherently different. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big deals are in my pipeline, and I'm attracting an elite team to help me find more. It's all very clear to me. It just makes sense. It's like I can see the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think about Shovels, I feel a combination of pride, excitement, and anticipation. It's a potent mixture. I think the last time I had it was in college. Everything worked out as planned (I went to grad school at Harvard) and I have many reasons to believe that my dreams for Shovels will come true too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll know if it's working by the start of summer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Teaching to be rewarding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I'm not doing business, I'm teaching it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This spring I'll teach a couple of supervision and management courses that I've never taught before. I'm looking forward to it. I did most of my course preparation last week in Hawaii. Poolside, palm trees swaying in the breeze, the Pacific Ocean in the distance. Kids playing in the pool. It could be worse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to introduce cases into my teaching. Every week, we'll discuss a case and I'll let the students work on their responses in class. The supervision and management cases are interesting. We'll discuss Uber and Netflix, how cultures form, and how important leadership is throughout the lifecycle of a business. As Shovels grows up, examples like these will take on new meaning. It's the perfect time for me to study management, supervision, and leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm living these lessons as I teach them, and for me this has become something of a superpower. I really enjoy interacting with students in class. I like extemporaneous speech. I look forward to grading. Perhaps someday it will get tiring. Maybe I'll find that I can no longer be an entrepreneur while I teach entrepreneurship. I'm not so sure, though. For now, I'm finding that doing and teaching at the same time has a positive amplifying effect on both. If that ever changes, I'll deal with it then. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Friendships to matter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks before I turned 40, I took a group of guys up to (https://rbucks.com/2019/03/03/my-happy-place/). We hiked, we swam, we grilled, and we played Cards Against Humanity. It was awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember vividly one moment at the end of the weekend. Only two guys remained, and since I was their ride home, they helped me put the cabin back together. We were sweeping the front deck when my career came up, and I lamented that I wasn't sure exactly what I was going to do next. I had some ideas but I was uncertain which one to pick. I told them I really wanted to be a climate tech CEO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"That makes all the sense in the world," one of my friends said. The other agreed emphatically. On the drive home, I decided my building permit idea was the best one and hired a couple of programmers on Upwork to start scraping permits in Contra Costa County the following day. This was the start of the chain reaction that would become Shovels. It happened because of my friends. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm making more friends as a result of the work I'm doing on Shovels and at DVC. I'm also hearing from more old friends than any time in recent memory. I find it very rewarding, and it tells me that I'm doing something right. My network grows when I'm most productive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fitness to keep improving&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm in the best shape of my life. It's true. I credit a combination of my daily core routine, training for some (https://rbucks.com/2023/04/08/an-exploration-of-deep-exhaustion/), and doing a triathlon which really was about forcing myself to swim laps. Now a typical workout week for me looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 mornings of 10 minute core. Mondays I do a 5 minute straight arm blank. Tuesday through Friday I do 4 minutes on my elbows. The rest of the workout is various crunches, stretches, squats, and 40 pushups. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of 5.5 mile runs. Plus one 10+ mile run or a 35 mile bike ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 mile swim at a pace of about 2 mins per 100 yards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Peloton workout. My favorite is a 20 minute ride followed by a 20 minute full body strength&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The morning core routine, which I've now been doing for more years than I can track, is table stakes. It's always there, so I don't think about it. This means I work out twice on most days. It feels normal. In fact, on days when I don't work out at all, I get restless. That's when I head out to the backyard cottage where we have our Peloton stuff and knock one out. I have to exercise every day or I don't feel right. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, I remember thinking one sweaty exercise a week was all I needed. Maybe that was true at the time. A few years ago, I got into a rhythm of exercising every third day. One day on, two days off. It felt like work, but I stuck to it. I've been narrowing that gap in off days ever since, and it's now to the point where even on vacation I have to get my workouts in. The only days I didn't exercise in Hawaii were the days spent packing and flying. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm proud of (https://www.strava.com/athletes/6960326). I want to keep it going. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;To take chess more seriously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chess is a different kind of release. It's what I do to ramp into work mode. It's also what I do to reward myself for getting work done. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I happen to be on a really good clip right now. My chess is strong, but I've been playing long enough to know that it's cyclical. This could last another two weeks or maybe another two months. Then I'll hit a losing streak and drop about 200 points. Right now, though, I see the board and accurately anticipate my opponents' moves. I know this because they slow down in response. It's thrilling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I play 5-0 and 3-0 games. That means five minutes, no increment, or three minutes, no increment. These are fast games. I like using the clock as a weapon. No incremental time after each move (alternatively, you can get 2 or 3 seconds back after each move).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A different personality comes out when I play chess. I talk shit (chat it, actually). I'm hyper-competitive. I allow myself to dislike my opponent. I'm mean!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had to critique my entrepreneurship, it's that I tend to be too nice. It's great for building a network, but it's probably bad for sales and negotiation. I want to pull parts of my chess personality into my entrepreneur personality. That's one goal for this year, especially as each new Shovels enterprise deal becomes a negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's five good goals for me to keep in mind going into this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm ready 😁&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category><category term="shovels"></category><category term="teaching"></category><category term="fitness"></category><category term="reflection"></category></entry><entry><title>Above-average mediocrity</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2021/10/10/above-average-mediocrity/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-10T20:17:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-10T20:17:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2021-10-10:/2021/10/10/above-average-mediocrity/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;*I started writing this a while ago and am publishing it now even though I don't feel this anymore. Nonetheless, I edited and finished it because I think the vibe is interesting and might be helpful to another fellow "bottom of the top 1%"-er. *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So here we go.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;*I started writing this a while ago and am publishing it now even though I don't feel this anymore. Nonetheless, I edited and finished it because I think the vibe is interesting and might be helpful to another fellow "bottom of the top 1%"-er. *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So here we go.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to chip off a piece of the feeling I described in my previous posts, (https://rbucks.com/2021/03/24/its-been-a-long-long-time/) and (https://rbucks.com/2021/07/19/my-unannounced-and-inconsequential-break-from-social-media/), and dissect it a bit more, just for fun. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Delusions of grandeur&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I had big plans, big ambitions. "Three million by 30," is what I used to tell myself in my mid-to-late 20s when my (https://rbucks.com/2019/02/01/the-bitter-taste-of-failure/) was starting up in San Francisco. I figured three million dollars at six percent interest (conservative investments) would yield $180,000 per year. I could retire with that annuity if I wanted to (but of course I wouldn't). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believed I was destined for greatness, that all I had to do was put one foot in front of the other and I'd walk my way, chest puffed and bent arms swinging, to the top of the heap. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recalled a mentor at UC Berkeley meeting my girlfriend at the time at a fancy banquet. When I introduced him to her he smiled and pointed at me. "He's going to be rich," he said to her. I never forgot that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was leading some environmental programs at UC Berkeley I remember one of the campus facilities leaders introduced me to her peers as the future governor of California. I don't remember what I was there to talk about, but I remember she said that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school, I sat in the right rear seat of a car while my friend's mom drove. My friend sat in front of me, on the passenger side. Out of the blue, his mom turned around at a red light and told me she'll vote for me when I run for governor. Another friend, someone I volunteered with at a community organization in high school, also reminds people we meet that I'll be governor someday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governor. Someday. Sigh. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The older I get, the harder it is to live up to these lofty expectations. It's as if my first two decades were a dream where everyone I knew seemed to anticipate my gilded future. Now I'm awake, two decades later, and those things I was told were supposed to happen haven't happened. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've worked hard. I've put one foot in front of the other. But the fortune and fame have not materialized. I'm not at the top of the heap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I find myself at the bottom of the top 1-ish percent, a no man's land of far more than most but far, far, far away from the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;meta charset="utf-8"&gt;Pride and punishment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I shouldn't care. Sometimes I really truly honestly don't, and those days are wonderful. Sometimes that feeling of freedom from expectation and comparison lasts for a week. In that time I'm at peace. I don't want, I don't need. I'm content with my work, my assets, and my friends and family. My lot is just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I get a LinkedIn or Twitter alert. A guy I know from graduate school is listing his company on the NASDAQ. A friend from college has a top position in the Biden administration. Another one sold his company for $30 million, has $500 million in cryptocurrency tokens, or a hundred thousand Twitter followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think about the companies I've started and sold for barely a fraction of those amounts. I look at my bank account, Twitter likes, blog visits, and crypto portfolio. I ask myself what I've been doing, why I missed those opportunities, started the wrong companies, bought the wrong stocks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it comes on a phone call. Just a regular check in with an old friend. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Oh, you're still doing that?" &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You're going to sell for what?" &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You can't join the syndicate? It's just $30,000."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And suddenly I'm inadequate. It corkscrews my intestines. It impacts my mood. I get off the call and just think. I cross my arms across my chest and stare at the wall, lost in thought, feeling bad about myself for feeling bad about myself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell myself to let the feelings cycle through. I chew them up, like I'm digesting them, and explore the colors and textures, shapes and smells. I've mulled over these so much in the last few months, and I'm finally, finally able to get them out. A long-awaited defecation of self-destructive emotional waste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a proud person. I want for myself what many people along the way have also wanted for me: above average success. I went to Berkeley, Harvard, and MIT. I started companies, sold them, got married, started a family, bought a house. I'm a good leader and a great husband and father. I know these things and I'm proud of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also recognize that it's the same forces that got me this far that keep me from settling down. I haven't lost the lust to have a "great" career. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what's a "great" career and how is it measured? I'm still figuring that out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Personal greatness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The opinions that matter most to me are my wife's and kids'. It's been that way since I became a husband and a dad and I know that I'm doing A+ work there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't compare myself to other dads. How can I? I don't know what happens when their front doors close. I don't know if they fight or yell or ignore their kids all evening while staring at the TV or their phones. But I really truly doubt it. Either way, it has no bearing on me (but I'm glad, for my neighborhood's sake, that my fellow fathers all seem to be very good at this parenting thing.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I have no father FOMO. When I see a happy family walking through my neighborhood with beautiful, happy children, it warms my insides. I want to meet them, let some of their good vibes rub off on me, and make a new friend. I want them to come over for dinner, to invite the dad to a creek campfire, to celebrate each other's good fortune to be raising a family right here, right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's no jealousy at all, so I have what I might call a "dad swagger." I'm confident, happy, and friendly with every dad I meet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Professional greatness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not the same for me professionally. I compare myself to everyone and feign a smile through the bitter taste of jealousy when someone has achieved something that I want. This is the punishment for my pride, the thing I'm improving upon but still dealing with. It's the shit I need to extricate after chewing on it for years but really being aware of it for the last few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't cap off my corporate career until I've maxed out my earning potential. I have another company or two left to build, run, and sell. I think about it &lt;em&gt;all &lt;/em&gt;the time. I mean &lt;em&gt;all &lt;/em&gt;the time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, it's good. I'm ambitious. But on the other, it impacts my appreciation of right now. My professional aspirations are future-facing. My personal ones are right now. I'm happy with right now, but I lust for the future. It beckons me, like a siren song, to be smarter, get luckier, try harder, work longer, and get the big break I've been craving since we first started Scripted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I'll regret not giving myself the opportunity to be a founder or super early employee of a unicorn (that's a company with a $1 billion valuation, for you non-tech people). Odds are not in my favor that it happens, and I'm okay with that, but I need to try. This is my next Harvard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I'm preparing. (https://rbucks.com/2021/01/08/welcome-letter-to-my-search-marketing-class/) is one way of prepping myself. Taking classes on Solidity and anything else I find interesting is another. I also find that exercise does wonders for my energy and creativity, so I'm working out a lot and treating my body well. This process is taking time, but I'm enjoying it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the next big break opportunity comes, I'll jump on it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Political opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someday I will retire as a politician and get back into teaching and writing. I know this for sure. What happens between now and then is still up in the air. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm 39 now, going on 40. That's still pretty young but also pretty damn old. I once believed I needed to be running for something or already in office by my 40th birthday. I've given myself another decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met a MIT Media Lab guy who ran for congress in Southern California. He's very impressive and working on fundraising software and blockchain technology now. He told me that his 30s were about "me" and his 40s will be about "we." He's going to do one company only and focus on his family for the next decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like my 30s were "we" (especially since my first kid was born when I was 32) and my 40s will be a little bit more "me" but still mostly "we" and my 50s will be downright selfish as I'll definitely be in politics by then, fully immersed in the whole scene. All of it. The dinners, the ceremonies, the late-night dinners and networking. I'll be all over it once my kids have moved out of the house when I'm in my early 50s.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be a good politician. I might even be a great one. Time will tell. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Until then&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day at a time. That's it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="ambition"></category><category term="career"></category><category term="life-lessons"></category></entry><entry><title>In memory of Irving Katuna</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2021/05/08/in-memory-of-irving-katuna/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-05-08T12:17:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-05-08T12:17:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2021-05-08:/2021/05/08/in-memory-of-irving-katuna/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit: I've turned this blog post into a eulogy that I'll give at Rossmoor for my grandpa's funeral. He passed away early in the morning on Tuesday, April 27, 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My grandpa, Irving Katuna, was born on January 12, 1929 in Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania. It was a Saturday, and it was …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit: I've turned this blog post into a eulogy that I'll give at Rossmoor for my grandpa's funeral. He passed away early in the morning on Tuesday, April 27, 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My grandpa, Irving Katuna, was born on January 12, 1929 in Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania. It was a Saturday, and it was cold. A light dusting of snow passed through Pennsylvania the previous night and the temperature stayed just above freezing the day he was born. I'm not sure how many of his dozen older siblings were still living in the house then, but I picture my infant grandfather passed around to plenty of happy hands when he arrived home from the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilkes-Barre is a coal mining town about 120 miles west of New York City. Its population swelled to a peak of 80,000 around 1930 and declined through the depression and the aftermath of World War II. My grandpa was 11 when the draft was instituted in 1940 and was still too young to serve when the draft ended in 1946. Only about 30,000 people live in Wilkes-Barre today. Industry left, and so did my grandpa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He matriculated to UCLA but graduated from UC Berkeley and settled in San Francisco. He was the first of his siblings to go to college, a unique opportunity that did not go unnoticed by his older brothers. But in addition to being the youngest, he also was born with a stunted right arm, a midwife's mishap made during delivery at the hospital that cold Saturday in Wilkes-Barre, which prevented him from helping at the feed store his family owned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He met my grandma, Berna Mendell, at a dance at the Hillel in San Francisco while he was studying history at Cal. They quickly married and had four children: Linda (my mom), Judy, Bruce, and Brad. Along the way, he earned a Master's degree from San Francisco State and attempted a Ph.D. but did not submit a thesis. He began his career as a teacher and became a vice principal at Benjamin Franklin Junior High School in the Fillmore District before returning once again to the classroom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My grandpa's Jewish faith, along with his many years teaching Black students, brought him to Selma, Alabama in 1964. He accompanied five rabbis to support the Montgomery bus boycott and show solidarity of the Jewish community with a popular Christian pastor named Martin Luther King, Jr. My grandpa and these rabbis marched and were imprisoned with Dr. King. He spent less than a week in Selma but it would leave an impression on him and his family for the rest of his life. We celebrated his trip to Selma for his 80th birthday, and at 92 he had just completed writing a book about it with support from my mom and cousin Lisa.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My grandpa was opinionated and curious. He was a docent at the San Francisco Academy of Sciences and loved to buy books at thrift shops, a few of which he actually read. He liked pastries for breakfast and would go out of his way to pick up a scone or a bear claw from his favorite bakery. Breakfast at home usually involved cereal, which he kept in neat airtight plastic bins, and he preferred to eat it with fruit salad on top. On special occasions, like when his grandson stayed over, he made french toast in the morning. He enjoyed jogging and playing tennis, and when age forced him to hang up his running shoes, he returned to his lifelong love of swimming. He was a natural leader, someone who tended to reside over the organizations he volunteered for. He loved to join elder hostels, especially in Ashland, Oregon, where he attended the Shakespeare Festival with his wife Thelma for many years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My grandpa eventually left San Francisco and settled here in Rossmoor where he and Thelma became members of local Democratic and Jewish organizations and discovered the best local Chinese restaurants. Lucid and curious until the end, Irving loved to read and talk to his family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My house is only a couple of miles away from his apartment here and over the last few years we settled into a routine of bringing Chinese food over and eating dinner together: sweet and sour fish filets for Thelma, tomato beef chow mein for Irv, and vegetable chow mein for me and my girls. When COVID hit, I'd drop the food off and leave, aware that I wouldn't know which of these dinners would be our last. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grandpa Irv was immensely proud of all of us. And we were proud of him too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farewell, Grandpa Irv. We will miss you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/FE03D723-42E1-4AD3-8436-EC06E470E13E-1024x768.jpg)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="memory"></category><category term="life-lessons"></category></entry><entry><title>It's been a long, long time</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2021/03/24/its-been-a-long-long-time/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-03-24T20:53:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-03-24T20:53:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2021-03-24:/2021/03/24/its-been-a-long-long-time/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A year or so before the pandemic, which would be about two years before today, I took singing lessons in the "piano room" at our house. We called it the piano room because it's where we put my grandmother's piano. This was a behemoth of a piano -- a beautiful black …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A year or so before the pandemic, which would be about two years before today, I took singing lessons in the "piano room" at our house. We called it the piano room because it's where we put my grandmother's piano. This was a behemoth of a piano -- a beautiful black seven-foot long Baldwin parlor grand -- and it weighed a metric ton. It hardly fit, so a few years later, we swapped it for a Yamaha Clavinova. Now my piano has a volume control and stands against the wall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/A20C1926-F200-425C-8159-BF7FD7634AA9-1024x768.jpg)
&lt;strong&gt;Too much piano for a small house&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the songs I decided to learn to sing is this one, "It's Been A Long, Long Time," by Bing Crosby and Les Paul. I first heard it on Spotify, and it touched me. The guitar is beautiful, the lyrics are haunting, and the purity of just Bing's voice and Les's guitar is magical. I've been on a WW1 and WW2 movie-watching kick for a while and I figured that this song was about the war. A quick google search confirmed my hunch. (Another one that would be obvious, if you listened closely, is "I'll Be Home For Christmas.") &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I learned the chords and the lovely guitar solo and took it to my piano and vocal teacher and asked her to work with me on it. We spent a few weeks improving my tone and breathing through the high notes and then moved on to other songs, but this one still has a special place in my heart. And that sentiment has only deepened over the last two momentous years.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I write this, my dog is five and a half years old. He's middle-aged, just like me, and he's sore after our long jogs. My oldest daughter is six, and she's lanky and has a big gap-toothed smile. I still remember her smiling to herself, asleep in a crib in San Francisco, her arm stretched out in that baby sleeping pose. I knew then that she'd be a happy kid, and she is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/2CC8C2A1-BBAF-4B5A-A3B8-36A04E98D132-1024x768.jpg)
&lt;strong&gt;A smiling baby Lily&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My youngest is now four years old. She's sassy, strong, and increasingly independent. Before the pandemic, we followed her around everywhere, protecting her fall. She was barely three years old then. Within weeks of the lockdowns we let her out of sight, playing with our neighbors at the end of our cul-de-sac. Now she's even more mobile, on a bike, a scooter, a skateboard, or rollerblades. I couldn't keep up if I tried, so I don't. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, it's been a long, long time since I've changed a diaper. I'm grateful for that, and also sad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sold our BOB jogging stroller last weekend. I can't count how many miles I pushed that thing. It would be in the hundreds. We went all over the northern flats and hills of San Francisco, along Crissy Field and up into the Presidio. My runs got longer when we (https://rbucks.com/2016/03/22/an-ode-to-the-suburbs/). I jogged that stroller to preschool, daycare, and elementary school. Countless trips to Noah's Bagels with plain reduced fat smears stuffed into the pockets on our way home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm now a dad without a stroller. It took six years, but it happened fast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;figure&gt;!({static}/images/819EAEDF-D0B4-40BA-B246-50B1D73F78C5-768x1024.jpg)- !({static}/images/44A5C7D3-C65D-4023-B16F-947D48464691-1024x768.jpg)- !({static}/images/93C3A95A-8FFF-4CC8-86EE-4BB6F044FE93-768x1024.jpg)- !({static}/images/0D5D2ABA-CA6A-449B-8DA1-8586726EDDAD-1024x768.jpg)
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my neighborhood dad friends get together and drink beers by a fire in one of our backyards, I'm reminded that I'm the old guy now. Most of my neighbors are still having kids, planning on having more. They're in their early to mid-30s. I'm at the end of that decade. I moved into this neighborhood before them. Now I'm the one who knows the history, who lived in what house and has since moved away. That's crazy to me. When I first moved here there were other guys who knew the lore. Now I'm one of them. The old guard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been running MightySignal longer than I was at the Harvard Kennedy School. I've been living in Saranap longer than I was at UC Berkeley. All of these experiences are stacking on top of each other like loaded bricks and sometimes they weigh down on me. What does it all mean? What's it supposed to mean? Does it mean anything? I don't know. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I've been going through a transition. I have too much on the line right now to say exactly what it's about, but it has involved months of debate with myself and friends who will listen. There's a longer post to be written about this, and I will get to it (I look forward to multiple sittings on this one), but it all boils down to this same refrain: "It's Been A Long, Long Time." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been alive for a long, long time. I've been an adult for a long, long time. I've been out of grad school for a long, long time. My kids are older, I'm older, and in many ways, I'm able to do whatever I want. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now what?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="creativity"></category></entry><entry><title>Three early observations about writing a novel</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2020/08/23/three-early-observations-about-writing-a-novel/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-23T20:38:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-23T20:38:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2020-08-23:/2020/08/23/three-early-observations-about-writing-a-novel/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'll state the obvious first: it actually is as hard as you think. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I (https://rbucks.com/2019/09/19/a-few-days-of-radioactive-seclusion/) around around this time last year, I told myself not to overthink it. I was going to write a novel, simple as that. I wasn't going to agonize …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'll state the obvious first: it actually is as hard as you think. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I (https://rbucks.com/2019/09/19/a-few-days-of-radioactive-seclusion/) around around this time last year, I told myself not to overthink it. I was going to write a novel, simple as that. I wasn't going to agonize over plot lines and details. I wasn't going to do any reader panels. I wasn't writing for fame, after all, but rather to try something new. Prior to diving into this project I hadn't done &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; creative writing. None. In a long time, at least a decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the spark of an idea. I'd been thinking about it a lot. I knew the premise: *Man gets sick and is certain to die. Man hears about a faraway adventure hospice and decides to go, leaving his family behind. Man regrets. Man dies. *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about the characters, the setting, and how agonizing this decision would be for everyone involved. It felt like there was a lot of meat on this bone and when I shared that much of the story with family and friends, their eyebrows raised. They were immediately intrigued and it spurred all kinds of questions, and even some disgust. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I can't believe anyone would do that! Would &lt;em&gt;you &lt;/em&gt;do that to your wife and family?" Probably not, actually, but I loved that my plot elicited that type of reaction. It meant readership and book groups once it was published. And it meant it would be fun, even easy, to write. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was right and wrong. It has been fun. It has not been easy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Observation #1: It's the main character, stupid&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Story Genius by Lisa Cron&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was about 40,000 words into it, I read (https://www.amazon.com/Story-Genius-Science-Outlining-Riveting/dp/1607748894) by Lisa Cron and loved it. Around the time I started the novel I also read (https://www.amazon.com/Save-Last-Book-Screenwriting-Youll/dp/1932907009/) on the recommendation of a neighbor. Both touch on the same theme: &lt;em&gt;character, character, character&lt;/em&gt;. Plots are just things that happen. Characters are what we remember. Characters are what we care about. Characters are what actually drives the story and makes the plot &lt;em&gt;matter&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we read a great novel, we emote as the main character struggles with a misguided belief that drives him against the roiling ocean that is the plot. We feel him as he makes decisions and rejoice as he evolves, becoming a new person at the end. This is the formula that the most commercially successful novels and screenplays use to sell copies and &lt;em&gt;move&lt;/em&gt; people. You want your reader immersed in your story, rooting for or enamored with your character. You want them invested through to the last page, and you want your story to be a real gift to them. For those five or six hours the reader spent with you, they got a real glimpse into another world, a new universe, a sidecar's view into something extraordinary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans seem to be uniquely able to get wrapped up fiction. The story is a device unlike any other. It takes us away from one reality and places us into another one. It's science fiction, but it's just words on paper. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Observation #2: Writing fiction is dreaming while awake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting "in the zone" on a piece of fiction is much different than feeling the same effect while writing non-fiction, as I typically do on this blog. When I get in the mood to write, as I did tonight, I can flow for a good 45 minutes, finishing a post in one sitting. During that time I'm focused. I feel good. Basically, I just feel like writing, and the ideas come and I jot them down and the sentences just write themselves with very little editing. But I'm very much awake. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flow of creative writing is much different. At peak flow, I'm barely there. I'm fully engaged with the story. For those moments, the characters are real and I'm in it, watching them talk and make decisions, trying to take notes as fast and as best I can. I've cried while writing, which is actually an incredible experience. Two people who read early drafts of this novel told me they cried too. I wonder if we cried at the same part. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best analogy I can offer is it's like a dream, except you're awake. You're aware that you're awake, because you're working hard, furiously trying to record it in writing, which is maybe the thing that makes it most distinct from a real dream. But during those moments you're a voyeur, a spy, a fly on the wall and your mind is working in two dimensions at once but it's just buzzing on a creative writing high. That feeling is addictive. I wish I could say that it happens every time I sit down and write. It does not, but now that I know it's there, I keep holding out for it to show up again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This insight is one reason that I keep chipping away at this novel. It also helps me to justify my writing retreats. I know that getting there requires open mental space, the long runway of an open afternoon where my only obligation is to use that time to write. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Observation #3: Decision fatigue is real&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other big difference about non-fiction and fiction writing is the exponentially greater number of decisions that must be made in a fiction story. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the topic is of my non-fiction piece (business, usually), I have a framework to follow. There's a set of facts and my decision-making is simply around how I describe my observations, what references to make, and how deep I want to go. (By the way, for some of the best non-fiction writing I've found, check out (https://alexdanco.com/).)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great non-fiction writing is academic but accessible. It might also weave a storyline through it, using some of the character techniques described in Observation #1. For the epitome of that technique, look no further than Alexander Hamilton's biography or the musical inspired by it. Laden with facts, it had to decide what to keep and what to ignore, what to expand upon and what to merely mention in passing. These are big decisions, no doubt, but not as many as would have been made if Alexander Hamilton were a purely fiction character. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dealing with decision fatigue is actually what originally led me to the second observation. In the flow state, decisions feel like they're being made for me. Even though I'm writing a fiction, in the "dream" I have as I write, the story just happens and I simply record it, like a biographer reviewing source material for his subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can manufacture it in some ways by basing a character on someone I know, much the way an artist uses a living model for a painting or sculpture. I can make fewer decisions this way, letting my memory of that person take the reins. It helps me save energy for the scenes when I don't have an experience to run them against. These take real work, a bit of googling, and progress the slowest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm 72,000 words into what should be an 80,000-word novel. The last 10 percent has been the hardest. I'm stuck on the ending. I thought I had it, but now I'm not so sure, and I'm aware that if I deviate too far, I'll either end up having to rewrite a good portion before this ending or extend the novel out another 20-30,000 words. Neither outcome is appealing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is what I think about when I go to bed, when I swim laps, and when I'm mindlessly throwing the ball from my (https://rbucks.com/2017/06/19/the-ascent-of-blue/). Because ultimately that's what writing a novel is. It's getting absorbed in it, thinking about it, and knocking out some of the thousand hours it takes to write a book that will get consumed 200x faster. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's the glory in writing a novel. "It's the journey, not the destination" has never felt more true.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="writing"></category><category term="creativity"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Read Write Play: Q3 2019</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2019/11/18/read-write-play-q3-2019/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-18T22:11:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-11-18T22:11:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2019-11-18:/2019/11/18/read-write-play-q3-2019/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In just a couple of months I will have been tracking my RWP for two years. Not bad for a silly little trope that nobody (except me) cares about. I try to be consistent in what I do, though, and being conscious of the RWP is just as important to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In just a couple of months I will have been tracking my RWP for two years. Not bad for a silly little trope that nobody (except me) cares about. I try to be consistent in what I do, though, and being conscious of the RWP is just as important to me as the RWP itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it another way, when there's so much noise, so much to care about and be stressed out about and want to care about, it's nice to be able to shove it all aside because I've already distilled it all down to three things that actually matter. Indeed, these three things that are always going to be alone-time well-spent: Reading, writing, and playing (music). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Read&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I basically failed my design curriculum. I really meant to get into it, but I got distracted. I'm not sure if or when I'll pick it back up. I want to learn to draw better, but that kind of itch is getting scratched by my piano playing, which I'll describe below. I feel like that's my physical art, and when my kids are drawing, I can be in the same room with them playing piano. It's what I want to do and it makes me happy, so I'm not going to fight it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I started reading (https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10464006-save-the-cat), a book about screenwriting that could be applied to any kind of writing. It was recommended to me by a neighbor and I thought it prudent since I am working on my first novel and am about halfway through writing it. Save The Cat has good ideas about character and story development. I think about it as I edit my half-written novel. I'm also about halfway through Save The Cat. Someday I will finish it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One night I didn't feel like working or watching television or playing chess. I pulled up the Kindle Store and quickly settled in on (https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40180098-the-overstory) by Richard Powers. It's a long book. It took me about three weeks of reading at night to get through it, and I thought the ending dragged on a ways, but I thoroughly enjoyed it. It's a book about people and the environment. More specifically, it's about different peoples' interactions with trees. Many parts of the book are moving and beautiful. The writing reminds me of Paulo Coelho or Gabriel García Márquez. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as I finished &lt;em&gt;The Overstory&lt;/em&gt;, I started reading a book, (https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29507568-the-hidden-life-of-trees) by Peter Wohlleben, that Richard Powers referenced. I'll write more about this book next time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, true to form, I read one long book in Q3. The march continues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Write&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm happy to report that there was a lot of writing happening in Q3 2019! I started a novel and gave a 5,000 word speech at Diablo Valley College. If I include the smattering of blog posts I bet I wrote more than 40,000 words last quarter. That's a hefty amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned my novel in this blog post about the (https://rbucks.com/2019/09/19/a-few-days-of-radioactive-seclusion/) I had to endure in August 2019. This wasn't a physical hardship. There was some mental stress, I suppose, but fortunately everything worked out fine, and I got to take advantage of a "doctor's orders" excuse to be secluded with my dad at my family's cabin (https://rbucks.com/2019/03/03/my-happy-place/). I had four nights and five days up there, able to set my own schedule, unbound by the family routine back home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used this reprieve to start a novel that had been banging around in my head for months. I wrote a short outline and gave myself at least five hours each day to sit and write. In all I cranked out over 25,000 words and I managed to write another 7,000 after I got home. Progress has slowed down significantly since then, but I'm not too worried about it. I'll pick it back up at a writing retreat or something similar this winter. I really want to get the first draft done. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason it stalled is I had another writing project, a big speech at Diablo Valley College. I (https://rbucks.com/2019/09/11/four-simple-truths-about-entrepreneurship/). I had over an hour to stand in front of a bunch of people and talk. I did the math and figured if I had no slides, I would need a speech of about 5,000 words to fill that time. So, I wrote it. I felt pretty good about how it all went. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That speech and my follow-up post about (https://rbucks.com/2019/09/18/dealing-with-public-speaking-panic-attacks/) performed relatively well on my blog. My personal favorite, though, is the post I wrote (https://rbucks.com/2019/10/17/becoming-a-better-public-singer/) with my neighbors on one sunny day at the end of summer. I really enjoyed it. The blog post has some videos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Play&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September I bid farewell to the Baldwin 7 foot parlor grand piano that I inherited from my grandparents. It just wasn't practical to have a piano this size in our small home. And although we kept it for nearly four years, it was time to let it go and let the room where we kept it turn into something else. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still needed a piano, of course, and looked all around for good uprights. I played some at the Music Exchange in Walnut Creek but since the grand was all I knew, these pianos just didn't sound right. They were tinny and shrill compared to the broad, warm tones of my Baldwin. It was really disappointing to make the step down. Then, one day at Music Exchange, I sat down at one of the Yamaha Clavinova digital pianos in the showroom. I loved it. I loved everything about it. The weighted keys, the tone, the look, the sound. Best of all, they were priced the same as a used upright piano. I had to convince my wife that this wasn't some dinky synthesizer, that it was basically the same thing as an upright piano, except a lot better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She agreed to trust me and I was able to find a family in Alamo who had the space and the desire for our piano. I sold it and with money to spare I bought the Clavinova. I'd like to say I miss my grandparents' piano, but I don't. I love the Clav, and since I can adjust the volume and play piano in the same room where my girls are drawing, I play a lot more. Like, a LOT more. This is all that would have mattered to my grandparents. They just want to know that music is being played. I know it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;figure&gt;!({static}/images/75e3344b-d2e8-4b2a-8273-e971326eb94a.jpg?w=1024)- !({static}/images/a20c1926-f200-425c-8159-bf7fd7634aa9.jpg?w=1024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After and before.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I paused my piano lessons while this transition took place. When I contacted my piano teacher again, I was happy to introduce her to two new pupils: my wife and my oldest daughter. All of my piano practicing has finally paid off: two more people are learning to play. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I'm going over the same songs I've been playing since the first RWP, but doing a lot better. I've been wanting to play Bennie and The Jets for years. Just this past month I settled in and focused on it, and I had it down within a week. I'm now able to play multiple inversions of common chords by sight. Crazy chords like F#m7 will trip me up, but I'm seeing now how relative minors factor in. That F#m7 chord has the same notes as an A chord. So I play an A, which I already know, and put an F# octave on the base. Boom: F#m7. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also continue to sing along with the Elton John tunes, even though they're out of my range. I keep hoping one day I'll wake up and be able to sing a high G as well as Billy Joel, but that day hasn't come yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still playing guitar too, mostly because my oldest daughter has become &lt;em&gt;obsessed&lt;/em&gt; with The Beatles. It's the cutest thing, and a proud dad moment for me. I bought a book of Beatles songs on a whim at a music shop near my house that was closing. I figured it'd be nice to have on hand. What I couldn't have known then, and what I still can't believe, is that my daughter would use this book to teach herself to read by listening to Beatles songs and following the lyrics. Often, instead of asking Alexa, I'll play along on guitar and sing with her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight, when I put her to bed, we sang "You Like Me Too Much" and "Here Comes The Sun." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The girl loves George Harrison.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="reading"></category><category term="writing"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="self-improvement"></category><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>On nine whole years of marriage</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2019/06/12/on-nine-whole-years-of-marriage/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-12T22:16:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-12T22:16:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2019-06-12:/2019/06/12/on-nine-whole-years-of-marriage/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;*Note: my wife did not know I was going to write and publish this. *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a lucky man. I think most people in my neighborhood would recognize this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife is friendly, attractive, likes to cook and do laundry, is a wonderful mom to my daughters... and works! She …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;*Note: my wife did not know I was going to write and publish this. *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a lucky man. I think most people in my neighborhood would recognize this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife is friendly, attractive, likes to cook and do laundry, is a wonderful mom to my daughters... and works! She makes a lot of money. If we were really keeping score (and we're not), I'd have her beat by a little bit, but we're basically even contributors to the family budget's bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, she loves me. I've never doubted it, never felt otherwise, never needed to question, and I realize that I probably take this entirely for granted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I am a lucky man. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I forgive myself for that oversight, as most men tend to do, because I think I'm a pretty good husband. If I may say so myself. I cook, I clean, I wash dishes and put them away, I do laundry (when she lets me) and I take the kids to school 99.9% of the time (she picks them up). Until just recently I was home every day because I worked from home (I'll describe my first temporary office in Walnut Creek for summer interns in (https://rbucks.com/2019/08/07/back-to-the-office-and-back-again/)). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I can tell, the things most married couples argue over relate to conflicts between work and family time. I'm no saint, but I think I do a pretty good job of managing that balance. Even with my new office situation, I'm home by 5:30pm and I still take the kids to school. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the improvement side, I work (or at least am on my computer) more than half the evenings in a given week, including weekends. Despite (https://rbucks.com/2017/04/28/three-life-hacks-i-wish-i-did-more-often/) it, I'm definitely on my phone too much. I could be more proactive about planning meals, family activities, and time alone with just my wife. I'm aware, and writing this down helps me remind myself that it's important to translate awareness into action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, okay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nine years is a long time. A damn long time. If I think about how much happened between when I was born and my ninth birthday, I think wow, that's a lot. Infant to fourth grade. Twice my older daughter's age. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a long time, and yet it has flown by. How can it be? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer, I believe, is the same one that I described in my wedding toast nine years ago tonight. In it, I described how I was nervous about getting married. There's a lot of divorce in my family, including my own parents. When I was dating my wife-to-be, I wasn't sure what to make of that. I definitely didn't want to get divorced, but it seemed the odds were against me. I decided to get married anyway because it felt so &lt;em&gt;easy.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, everything about our relationship was easy. We just got along. We didn't argue, we didn't suppress feelings. When we had feelings, we shared them. I remember a few times when I felt that she was upset but not telling me, and called her out on it. She relented and we worked through the issues without either of us getting too upset. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've cried, she's cried, we've cried together at one time or another in these nine years. Looking back on those times now, I don't have bad feelings. Those were part of our evolution as a couple. Those were real moments when we both learned what the other needed to feel happy, safe, protected, and loved. Those were critical moments that actually strengthened our relationship, like building a muscle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So since she and I have been on a exercise kick the last few months, that's the thought that I will end with. Nine years of marriage is certainly a workout, but the result is strength. Every passing year I feel a tighter, stronger bond with the woman I have married. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a lucky man. And she is lucky too :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/zjcu2huzrvghlrvtxmmdqq.jpg)
&lt;em&gt;My wife and I on our driveway. Photo taken by our neighbor. Out of scene: lots of kids on bikes and scooters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="marriage"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="relationships"></category></entry><entry><title>Read Write Play: Q1 2019</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2019/04/28/read-write-play-q1-2019/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-28T14:14:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-28T14:14:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2019-04-28:/2019/04/28/read-write-play-q1-2019/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another quarter, another RWP. I'm glad to report that I've been doing a LOT of reading, writing, and playing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Read: 3 books on Finance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quarter I managed to read three books as part of my self-improvement curriculum. In (https://rbucks.com/2019/02/06/my-personal-2018-recap/), I mentioned how I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another quarter, another RWP. I'm glad to report that I've been doing a LOT of reading, writing, and playing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Read: 3 books on Finance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quarter I managed to read three books as part of my self-improvement curriculum. In (https://rbucks.com/2019/02/06/my-personal-2018-recap/), I mentioned how I wanted to focus my media consumption on specific topics. Rather than trying to read and keep up on everything, I'd put blinders up and focus on one (fairly broad) topic. I decided to make finance and accounting the inaugural subject matter, and I initially set out to read two books. However long it took to read two books on finance would be the length of my "class." I ended up reading three. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;(https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0018QQQKS) by Nial Ferguson&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An awesome overview of the financial history of the world. I listened to the audiobook many years ago and told myself then that this book deserved a second pass. It's so dense, so fascinating, so comprehensive that it warrants real study. I tried to read this book slowly and let it sink in, but giving it the treatment it deserved probably would have meant taking months to read it rather than weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made 16 Kindle highlight notes in this book, which is a lot for me. Ferguson goes deep into economic theory, noting the structures that make economies actually work. Here are some examples I highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Poor countries are poor, in other words, because they lack secure property rights, the ‘hidden architecture’ of a successful economy." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Nial Ferguson
&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He writes a lot about the role that government plays in laying the groundwork for successful economies. It makes a lot of sense. Government policies can also ruin an economy, as in the example of hyperinflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Inflation is a monetary phenomenon, as Milton Friedman said. But hyperinflation is always and everywhere a political phenomenon, in the sense that it cannot occur without a fundamental malfunction of a country’s political economy."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Nial Ferguson&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also explains how government policies in the future can improve the gap between rich and poor. I've often wondered why poverty has existed throughout history. I've not heard of a society in all of modern humanity, going back to the advent of cities, where there wasn't an upper class and a lower class. Prior to the birth of cities, I think there was a forced egalitarianism. I think (and I admit to needing to study this) that Native American societies didn't have the concept of rich and poor. One's hierarchical ascent in their society came only with age. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Only when borrowers have access to efficient credit networks can they escape from the clutches of loan sharks, and only when savers can deposit their money in reliable banks can it be channelled from the idle rich to the industrious poor."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Nial Ferguson&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course this purely free market solution could certainly be argued against. Ferguson addresses externalities throughout the book but clearly has a firm belief that when an economic structure exists with clear rules that allows the free economic transfer of goods and services, people will prosper. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is a great read for anyone studying economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;(https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18966580-financial-intelligence-revised-edition) by Karen Berman and Joe Knight&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the perfect book for what I was looking for: a simple review of financial statements and the common ratios to analyze them. It is well-written, informative, and just the right length. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, unlike The Ascent of Money, I didn't make a single highlight. It's not a reflection on the quality of the book at all. It's just not the kind of read that makes you want to highlight. It is, however, exactly as advertised. I do have a better understanding of the art behind finance. I'm more financially intelligent. I know now where the subjectivity lies in the income statement, around how revenue and depreciation can be impacted simply by what rule the controller chooses to recognize them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also now have greater appreciation for Warren Buffet's view on financial statements. He puts the greatest weight on the Statement of Cash Flows, because for the most part, this statement can't be influenced by the whims of the people running the books. There are ratios, which I recall from my MBA classes but didn't really click until I read about them in this context, that compare numbers from Statement of Cash Flows with the Income Statement or Balance Sheet. Those seem like the best way to evaluate a business. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm very glad I read this one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;(https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/70420.The_Undercover_Economist) by Tim Harford&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Undercover Economist came up in some podcasts and Google searches. I liked Freakonomics and decided that this would be a good book to read to start my finance "course." It turned out to be my least favorite of the three books I read, but it's not necessarily because it's a bad book. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harford writes about how both positive and negative externalities can be unexpected and some surprising factors that influence pricing. He also makes a case for expanded health care, something similar to "Medicare for all," saying this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The best  system would be one that compels patients to pay for many of the costs, thus providing an incentive to inform themselves and to make choices that are both in their interests and reasonably cost-effective, but which leaves the most severe costs to the government or insurance."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Tim Harford&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also thought his arguments in favor of free trade were compelling. He explains why presidents are in favor of free trade (it's good for the nation as a whole, even if some specific communities are impacted negatively), and explains why global free trade ought to save the environment and decrease poverty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as is the case with Financial Intelligence, financial statements and global markets don't work perfectly because whims and emotions get in the way. As Hartford writes, "In the end, economics is about people." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would add, "and people aren't perfect."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus my financial class is complete. I subscribed to the Wall Street Journal and started reading it every day, watched some financial documentaries, read some other articles on finance, and finished these books. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quarter I am going to read 3 books about design and do something I've been wanting to do for decades. I've started to learn how to draw. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Write: Cancer stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a book in mind that I intend to write, but I haven't started writing it yet. There's an outline but that's it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, my writing in Q1 was dominated mostly by some good and bad news I got regarding my papillary thyroid cancer. I think it's summarized pretty well in my most (https://rbucks.com/2019/04/27/and-now-a-bit-of-certainty/). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The news is mostly good, and I am mostly fine. Writing about it is therapeutic and sharing it kind of sets it off to sea. I share because if I write and don't share then I feel like it's still stuck with me. By publishing it, I can push it into the world and out of my head, away from my psyche. So that's why I write and publish these stories. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Play: The Rolling Sloans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been playing a lot of guitar and piano and I've started taking singing lessons too. I found a (http://erinsvoiceandpiano.com) who I pay a little bit extra for the convenience of her coming to my house for our lessons. She coaches me through beginner to intermediate-ish pieces by Mozart, Beethoven, and Bach. She gives me scale exercises and guidance on how to make sure my fingering is correct when the sheet music isn't explicit. I've become a much better piano player since the lessons began and it's become more and more fun to play piano. It really started to click for me in the last few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, I've been preparing for the 10 year reunion of my grad school band, The Rolling Sloans. We're playing in Boston on Saturday night, June 8, and I've been preparing for this for months. I have a Spotify playlist of our set, printouts of the music, and have been playing along with the songs as frequently as I can. When my girls are playing in the court with my neighbors, I fire up Spotify, grab my acoustic guitar, and jam along with the tracks. It's the best way I can think of to practice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;!({static}/images/screen-shot-2019-04-28-at-2.45.31-pm.png)
&lt;em&gt;First half&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;!({static}/images/screen-shot-2019-04-28-at-2.45.12-pm.png)
&lt;em&gt;Second half&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to sing a few, just like I did for our 3-hour set five years ago. This time we'll have between 1.5-2 hours to play and we're going to jam in as much music as possible. The songs I'm leading for are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alone - Heart- My Hero - Foo Fighters- Mayonaise - Smashing Pumpkins- Love Yourself - Justin Bieber- Shine - Collective Soul&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been working on these with my teacher, who in the course of the last few months has increased my upper range by a minor third (three half-steps). More importantly, I'm more confident, more comfortable, and more excited to sing in front of my classmates than ever. I was nervous five years ago, and spent most of my prep time working on guitar solos. I didn't practice singing. When I was an MBA student, I definitely didn't practice singing. There was no time. I played lead guitar and let our rhythm guitar player and singer do all the vocals. We had a blast playing more shows than I can count. We were in demand because we were really good. Like &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten years later I want to present myself a bit more polished and matured as a musician. I will have more fun on stage if I'm confident, and I will be more confident if I'm comfortable with how I'm playing and sounding. So I've basically been playing my solo songs non-stop, in front of family and neighbors and of course my piano and voice teacher. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next RWP will feature highlights from the show! Can't wait.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="reading"></category><category term="writing"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="self-improvement"></category><category term="finance"></category></entry><entry><title>The game I'm playing</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2019/04/26/the-game-im-playing/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-26T21:11:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-26T21:11:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2019-04-26:/2019/04/26/the-game-im-playing/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's more mid-30s introspection about life and goals. These are things I've been thinking about as the people around me and I get older. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What game am I playing? How do I know if I'm winning or at least doing above average?  And why, for goodness sake, does this even …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's more mid-30s introspection about life and goals. These are things I've been thinking about as the people around me and I get older. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What game am I playing? How do I know if I'm winning or at least doing above average?  And why, for goodness sake, does this even matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most people with a pulse, I have pride and ego. It would be really nice if I honestly truly didn't care about how successful my friends, neighbors, and schoolmates are, that I don't notice when someone I know buys a Porsche or a Tesla or is an early employee (or founder) of a publicly traded company. I do notice, I do think about it, I do introspect for a moment, sometimes longer, and ask myself if I'm still doing it right. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer, I've decided, depends on what game I'm playing. Is it the make as much money as possible game? Have the biggest house and fanciest car game? Is it the have the most social impact game? Travel to the most places game? Have the most fun game? All of these are interesting, valid ways to live a life. But am I playing them? Am I even on the field? If not, what am I doing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing this post to help myself figure out this fairly existential problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Game #1: Make the most money. (Answer: No.)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd love to have $20M in my bank account. I would not love what it (most likely) takes to get that $20M. Here are a few scenarios. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Be a founder of a public company.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too much work. I looked into this, tried it on for size, worked really hard for about five years, and came up short. Sadly, the window I had to start a company that might go public (https://rbucks.com/2019/02/01/im-not-fundable/) on my poor little fingers. We raised $16M and did all the things that venture-backed companies in early stages do to try to make it, (https://rbucks.com/2017/07/12/scripted-dont-quit/).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've seen other friends have much more success, and while I tip my hat to each and every one of them, I also recognize the sacrifices they made to get there. It's a lot of work, stress, and time. This is a lifestyle I don't want right now. It's not my game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Be a partner or senior executive at a large company.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't need to start a company to get rich, of course. Managing directors and C-level executives at top consulting and other private sector firms can make north of $1M per year in salary and bonuses. In fact, this is how a majority of millionaires make their millions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also a lifestyle where you go to the office every day, work late, wake up early, and probably travel an awful lot. I caught a glimpse of this during my two years of management consulting after college. I decided this was not for me. So I went to grad school and did my startups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've concluded that I'm not great at making gobs of money. I'm good at making enough money to be comfortable in the Bay Area, which is a feat itself, but beyond a certain point, I get complacent. The itch to earn more fades away pretty fast. Like I said, not my game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Game #2: Have the most expensive things. (Answer: No.)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't need to make tons of money to have a lot of nice things. If you maximize for consumption, then you need merely to minimize your other expenses. For example, if I really wanted to have a bunch of nice things, like fancy cars, income properties, and jewelry, I would not have had kids. Having kids is the worst way to go about having expensive things, and yet I had two of them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, this is not my game either, and if you know me then this should come as no surprise. I like comforts. I like nice cigars, scotches, and hotels, but I'd rather ride my bike or jog than drive my Camry or my Hyundai. I have a Rolex but it was a gift from my parents. Our house is expensive but it's below average for the Bay Area. The expensive things I own are not out of some flamboyant need for show or due to personal preference. They're expensive because they have to be expensive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I didn't have to spend $24,000 on a car for my family, but I did the research and bought a nice, safe, &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt; car.  Same with the patio we put on the side of the house and the deck we added soon after we purchased. Those are necessities, and since we plan to live here forever, it felt like good investments to choose the nicer options of those projects. I want to be able to make decisions like that. Get the more expensive, higher quality housing materials. Do some upgrades! We can afford it because we've opted out of the most expensive options elsewhere in our spending. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So no, I don't want to have the most expensive things. I don't want the biggest house or the best car. In fact, I never did. I just want to be comfortable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Game #3: Have the most impact. (Answer: Maybe.)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point in my life, this was definitely a goal. I really wanted to dedicate myself to environmental sustainability. I was going to be an activist, a networker, mover-and-shaker, someone who could influence policy at the highest levels. This was the person I was in high school and college. It's the person who spoke at his college graduation, got some University-wide and national awards, and ultimately got accepted to the (https://rbucks.com/2019/06/06/what-my-grad-school-experience-meant-to-me/). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That guy is still here, but he's... chillin'. He got older, fell in love, started a family, and fell into the world of technology and startups and the fascinating leadership, management, and other intellectual challenges surrounding them. This is where I'm at now. I'm immersed in the challenge of building and running startups. It checks all of my boxes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interesting work - Interesting people- Good salary with great upside- Autonomy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to build things. I like to run them too. It's a lot easier to build and run a technology company than an environmental non-profit. I like to have customers. The flow of money is a simple way to measure the value of what I'm building. Even when I know it's not necessarily making the world better, I know that I'm at least making &lt;em&gt;someone's&lt;/em&gt; life better. They wouldn't be paying for my product otherwise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That simple little thing, knowing that I built or am running something valuable enough to make hundreds of thousands or millions of dollars (haven't reached that "tens of millions" stage yet) , is enough to get me by. I'm content, but I do wish that I could add this bullet to the list I wrote above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Makes a meaningful positive impact on the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scripted had elements of this. We helped people with writing talents make ends meet. Moms bought groceries with the money we helped them earn. Dads bought Christmas presents they would not have otherwise afforded. These are real stories we heard and that felt legitimately good. Nothing I've built since has had impact anywhere close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yes, this is a game I want to play. I'm not playing it now, but it's a field I want to be on. Someday I will make it happen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Game #4: Travel, be independent, have fun. (Answer: No.)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The single bachelors I know are not the most happy people I know. They struggle like everyone else to figure out the game that they're playing too. Even though these are the guys that have the freedom, financially and otherwise, to travel anywhere, attend any event, and date anyone. I have seen that this is not the key to happiness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness takes time to enroot. During that time, I believe, you have to be relatively still. You can't keep moving all the time, forming new relationships with people and places. You need to settle down long enough for the happiness to grow, and the longer you stay still, the deeper those roots grow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm three years into my (https://rbucks.com/2016/03/22/an-ode-to-the-suburbs/) and still can't believe my luck. We have incredible neighbors. A wonderful community of like-minded people who are friendly and interesting and easy to talk to. I've happened upon a group of dads in my neighborhood whom I'll host (https://rbucks.com/2017/08/27/the-view-from-35/) and see much more frequently out on the street. This is a neighborhood where people run into each other in front of their houses &lt;em&gt;all the time&lt;/em&gt;. It's amazing. And these relationships take time to develop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've found that it takes several random meetings like this to make a new friend. The first time I see a new face in the neighborhood, I'm pretty quick to say hi. We exchange the normal pleasantries and pretty quickly move along. I'm usually walking or jogging my kids when this happens. The next time, the conversation lasts longer. If they have a kid, then our kids will play. I learn more about them, more connections are made. The third time I see them, we're basically friends. There's familiarity and a genuine interest in catching up on the last conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, this sequence of three meetings takes time. In most cases, it takes several months. If this is a dad who happens to, like me, be out in the hood chasing a kid nearly every day, then it can happen faster. Most of the time it's slow. And this is what I mean about happiness taking time to enroot. Happiness is really about community. The people with a strong community are the happiest. That community can be family, church, neighbors, coworkers, but it's a community. You can't build a community when you're moving all the time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So although I do sometimes wish I could be 23 backpacking through Europe again, I recognize that that was then and this is now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty happy then. I'm even happier now. I choose these roots over that freedom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Game #5: Comfort and flexibility. (Answer: Yes.)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rigged it. Is this a game? I don't know. I guess so. I've certainly optimized for it, so it must be something, but I picked this game because I'm doing very well at it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm comfortable. I have a mortgage and two kids in pre-school in the California Bay Area and I can shop at Whole Foods, eat out at restaurants, and still save for the future. This is a huge accomplishment by any measure. Add on top of that the fact that I can work from home whenever I want, have a job that I actually enjoy, and get to choose when I work and who I work with, and yes, I'm crushing the game. I'm like 12 under par at the Master's. I'm the Tiger Woods of finding comfort and flexibility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also appreciate that I worked hard to get this. This lifestyle wasn't handed to me, and it was never a given that I'd get it. I set myself up for this, took some risks, and I'm enjoying the rewards. I should allow myself to be proud of the fact that the game I ended  up playing is the one I'm most equipped to win. Maybe I've already won it. It's been over two years since I've had to be in an office every day. I don't think I'm ever going back. If I have an office again it'll be the office I use when I'm in the office, not the office I'm expected in every day. That's just not how I roll. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;So now what?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've just determined that I'm winning at something. I have a game, comfort and flexibility, and I'm on top of it. So now what? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the answer is pretty clear. I want to keep the baseline the same and add two more elements, in this order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a larger social impact- Earn more money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two could go hand-in-hand. I've often thought that I would be a very good millionnaire. When I think about having tons of disposable income, I don't think about private jets and oil paintings. I think about writing a huge check to UC Berkeley. I think about hearing about or witnessing a tragedy in my community and having the means to address it. I would love nothing more than to find out a community organization that does important work is shy $25,000 of their financing goal and tap the director on the shoulder and tell them I have it covered. That's what I would do if I had the money. I'd totally be that guy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that windfall would come only because I set myself up for luck and I got lucky. I'm not going to earn that kind of money by force of sheer will. It's not my game. So if I don't make millions on a windfall, I'll have to make an impact in other ways. Maybe I'll come up with an amazing idea for a product that people or businesses will pay for that actually makes the world a better place. Maybe I'll invent a better compost bin, a new way to (https://rbucks.com/2019/05/24/what-im-most-afraid-of/), a website that somehow reduces global warming. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had that idea, I'd be building it right now. Alas, I don't. So I will keep playing the game I'm playing until the game I want to play comes into view: Comfort, flexibility, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; impact. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, that's the game I want to play. It's just a matter of time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="ambition"></category></entry><entry><title>One-hundred-and-two</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2018/12/31/one-hundred-and-two/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-31T21:25:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-31T21:25:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2018-12-31:/2018/12/31/one-hundred-and-two/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s a very short story I wrote earlier this year that encapsulates a lot of what 2018 was for me. Some introspection, some awareness of aging, and growth all around me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How old are you?” she asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“36,” I replied. I know where she’s going with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s a very short story I wrote earlier this year that encapsulates a lot of what 2018 was for me. Some introspection, some awareness of aging, and growth all around me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How old are you?” she asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“36,” I replied. I know where she’s going with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How long until you’ll be 100?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A long time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How old will you be after 100?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“101.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And after that?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“102.” I start to imagine myself here at our old family cabin on Pinecrest Lake when I’m 102. She would be just turning 70. A hazy sadness wafts over me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And after that then you’ll die?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes, probably.” She’s not even four yet. Why is she thinking about this right now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She rolls over toward me in the tiny wooden bunk where I slept when I was her age and grips my hand. Her fingers are smooth and tiny, soft and warm to the touch. I trace them gently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I love you,” she whispers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Lily, I love you so much,” I whisper back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes she’s asleep.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="goals"></category><category term="fitness"></category><category term="achievement"></category></entry><entry><title>Read Write Play: Q3 2018</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2018/09/29/read-write-play-q3-2018/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-29T23:09:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T23:09:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2018-09-29:/2018/09/29/read-write-play-q3-2018/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This quarter I had a nice warm summer enjoying my entrepreneurship, my working from home, and my family. It was the first time in a long time that my wife and I got to spend a lot of time at home alone together. Both of my daughters are now at …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This quarter I had a nice warm summer enjoying my entrepreneurship, my working from home, and my family. It was the first time in a long time that my wife and I got to spend a lot of time at home alone together. Both of my daughters are now at pre-school and oooh boy, what a treat that is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent some time reading, writing, and playing during these respites from parenting. I wish I did more of it, but I had to do a fair bit of work too. Businesses don't grow themselves, and one of the things I did was change the billing system on my cash cow. We'll see how it goes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My reading and playing were mostly fun. The writing was work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Read: The Great Alone&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife found (https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34912895-the-great-alone) and I have to say, the author Kristin Hannah is an artist. Her storytelling and character development is among the best I've ever read. I loved every page. I also read (https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22663563-the-nightingale) by Kristin Hannah and it is equally off-the-charts wonderful. It's a delicious, page-turning adventure that makes me feel good for reading it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will definitely read more of her stuff. She deserves all the fandom and accolades. This is an author who absolutely should be atop the charts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Write: On metered billing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took my company, (https://www.findemails.com), and dramatically (https://rbucks.com/2018/06/12/moving-from-saas-to-metered-billing/) it is billed. Rather than charging a higher flat fee regardless of usage, I dropped everyone down to the same $9/mo plan and billed for usage. I knew this would drop my monthly recurring revenue (MRR) but I thought it would improve my other metrics. I might get more customers, fewer cancellations, and therefore earn back the lost MRR and then some over time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initial responses were promising. I'll have to write something again about it next month to see what really happens! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Play: Some Mozart&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my (https://rbucks.com/2016/09/24/remembering-meredith/) I had a chance to rummage through the extensive collection of piano music he and my grandma accumulated over the 50 years they lived in their house. They had boxes and boxes of it and I only had a few minutes to look through them before I had to leave. We were picking up the piano that my dad inherited and bringing it the house we had recently purchased in Walnut Creek. The piano movers were almost ready to leave. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked up some old jazz standards that my grandma used to play and some very well-worn classical music, written up with decades-old notes from years of piano lessons and hours of practicing. This collection sits atop the piano today and one of my favorite picks from the pile is this collection of easy to play Mozart pieces. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm mostly pecking at them now but I will choose one to master. Probably next quarter.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="reading"></category><category term="writing"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="self-improvement"></category><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Lifestyle over money</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2018/09/20/lifestyle-over-money/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-20T13:02:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-20T13:02:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2018-09-20:/2018/09/20/lifestyle-over-money/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I reconnected with a few college friends recently who I rarely see. They were overachievers — 3.95 GPAs at UC Berkeley (which is quite literally insane, especially in the poli sci and math departments they graduated from) — and went on to get great jobs and MBAs from Stanford and Harvard …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I reconnected with a few college friends recently who I rarely see. They were overachievers — 3.95 GPAs at UC Berkeley (which is quite literally insane, especially in the poli sci and math departments they graduated from) — and went on to get great jobs and MBAs from Stanford and Harvard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They both have plenty of money, lots of friends, and well-established careers. It’s fun to reconnect and compare notes, tracking back to the dreams and ambitions we had and shared during our last years at Cal. Nearly 15 years on, we’re pretty much in the thick of real life. We’re starting families, buying homes, and making foundational decisions that are hard if not impossible to reverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the scary thing about being 36. We can see the cement of adulthood hardening all around us and we just have to hope that when it dries we’re happy with where we’re at because there’s really no going back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been out of the professional job market for about two years. That’s a long time in your mid-30s and I am well aware of the fact that every day I’m &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; holding an office job is another shovel deeper into this hole. Pretty soon I’m going to be unemployable, perhaps with a stigma around my time working from home. Or maybe I’ll come out of it “acquihired” into a larger company, fulfilling my stated mission to eventually sell these little businesses I’ve started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure, but one thing I am sure about is I’m not alone in feeling this way. These two illustrious friends of mine also struggle against the walls setting in all around them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over lunch at Wingtip, a swanky cigar and whiskey lounge in San Francisco, one friend told me she needs to have her “pivotal” position by 40 or 45 at the latest. If you haven’t had your career-changing role, the one they’d write your business school case study about by age 45, you’re not going to get one. Time’s up. People in their 50s don’t get these moonshots, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s her struggle. She recently quit her job at a startup in order to focus on starting a family. Well aware what this might do to her career, she’s anxious but still determined to focus on raising her first kid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My other friend started a hedge fund after business school and recently shut it down to work in the family office of one of his hedge fund’s LPs. It’s a great gig and he could potentially walk away with millions of dollars in a few short years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked him if he was happy. He shrugged and then cringed and said no, not really. I asked him what would make him happy. Hiking all day, he said. He just wants to go on hikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He left to go back to work and my other friend and I talked a while. She’s intentionally unemployed and scheming to get back into the game. I’m semi-retired. I’m not rich but I have a rich lifestyle. I’m not actually retired but I can act like it. It’s the ultimate freedom that I described at length in (https://www.amazon.com/Parallel-Entrepreneur-start-businesses-keeping-ebook/dp/B07CG8SV5V/).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t tell my friend this but about those hikes? Yea, I do that. I also work until midnight sometimes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the freedom that’s important. Freedom makes you happy, not the amount of money in the bank. I’m sure my balance sheet pales in comparison to these friends of mine, but am I equally happy, if not more? I think so.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="lifestyle"></category><category term="career"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category></entry><entry><title>Read Write Play: Q2 2018</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2018/06/28/read-write-play-q2-2018/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-28T23:04:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-28T23:04:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2018-06-28:/2018/06/28/read-write-play-q2-2018/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Coming off an intense Q1, I reflected on knocking out my big accomplishment: writing a damn book and self-publishing it on Amazon. The book launched in the #1 spot in New Releases in small business on the Amazon spots where it stayed for a week! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that was on my …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Coming off an intense Q1, I reflected on knocking out my big accomplishment: writing a damn book and self-publishing it on Amazon. The book launched in the #1 spot in New Releases in small business on the Amazon spots where it stayed for a week! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that was on my mind for my reading and writing this quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Read: The Originals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read this book soon after (https://rbucks.com/the-parallel-entrepreneur/). I chose it because it seemed like the more professional, mainstream, "official" version of my own book. I'd never read Adam Grant before but this title was getting a lot of airtime on podcasts and on Twitter. I bought it and dove in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, this was the perfect book selection. Several of the themes in &lt;em&gt;The Parallel Entrepreneur&lt;/em&gt; were confirmed by Grant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take this one, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurs who kept their day jobs had 33 percent lower odds of failure than those who quit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Adam Grant, &lt;em&gt;Originals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This point is reinforced throughout &lt;em&gt;The Parallel Entrepreneur&lt;/em&gt;. Side projects are real assets, not distractions. And looking the other direction, your day job is also an asset to your side business. You're able to be more creative and take more risks on a longer time horizon when you have a regular paycheck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also really liked this point, which influences me to this day, and is the reason I continue to write and want to begin work on another book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simonton finds that on average, creative geniuses weren’t qualitatively better in their fields than their peers. They simply produced a greater volume of work, which gave them more variation and a higher chance of originality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Adam Grant, &lt;em&gt;Originals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not just quality, it's quantity. It takes a lot of iterations to have a truly original, "genius" contribution to society. So let's get to the writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Write: I wrote about writing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In (https://rbucks.com/2017/12/04/how-i-wrote-17k-words-in-just-two-days/), I wrote about my book-writing process. I took a really relaxing 3-day, 2-night writing retreat in Sonoma and knocked out about half of my book. I prepared for this trip with a thorough outline, an open calendar, and a lot of motivation. I'd never done something like this before and I was committed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's me crossing the 30,000-word mark that I was shooting for. That's a last-call Old Fashioned in my hand. It was about 11pm on my last night of the retreat. I started with 13,000 words in the document. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/f1b51-1r6kq9ymy8_kogwoh68ompg.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Play: Mayonaise&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was always my favorite song on the Siamese Dream album. I listened to that album backwards and forwards in high school. I loved the sorrow, angst, and power of the Smashing Pumpkins. Such a great band, and the combination of Billy Corgan's rhythm guitar riffs and Iha's melodic leads is grunge rock perfection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mayonaise has it all and for the first time in twenty years (why did it take me this long??) I learned the rocking power chords, and that lovely arpeggiating intro and solo. This song is one of my all-time favorites in any genre.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="reading"></category><category term="writing"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="self-improvement"></category><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>What Can I Say</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2018/06/12/what-can-i-say/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-12T18:27:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-12T18:27:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2018-06-12:/2018/06/12/what-can-i-say/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m a straight white guy with no physical disabilities. That gives me a head start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On days like today, Martin Luther King Day 2018, in the wake of #metoo and #shithole, a year after the Kaepernick Kneel, I tried to reflect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People don’t stare at me, judge me …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m a straight white guy with no physical disabilities. That gives me a head start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On days like today, Martin Luther King Day 2018, in the wake of #metoo and #shithole, a year after the Kaepernick Kneel, I tried to reflect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People don’t stare at me, judge me, ask themselves questions silently but still show it in their eyes. That’s not my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go about my blissful day in a suburb of the San Francisco Bay Area that was once named a conclave for the “Caucasian race” (it said so on my land deed which was written back in 1949) and waive to my mostly white neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mom’s dad, Grandpa Irv, drew the connection between the oppression of blacks and the oppression of Jews. He marched in Selma when his children were barely teenagers and got arrested. He went to jail with Martin Luther King, Jr. It’s probably still his proudest moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His white neighbors weren’t as friendly as mine are. One of them spray painted “nigger lover” on the front of his house. My mom still remembers that day. It was a scary moment for her family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I say? I’m not prone to conflict, especially anonymous online conflict where it’s more like guerilla warfare than reasoned debate. I stopped trying to follow the Facebook and Twitter argument threads. I sometimes read the comments on a NY Times or Washington Post article that’s critical of the Trump administration but I don’t participate. Comments don’t change peoples’ minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest concern I have right now is securing financial freedom in one of the toughest regions in our country to achieve it. It takes a majority of my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the biggest difference between me today and Grandpa Irv fifty years ago is I don’t see the injustice. It’s not in my face like it was if I’d been alive in late 50s and early 60s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not one to let something go when I see something I don’t like. Large or small. Whether it’s some crumbs on the floor or a bad business strategy, I need to clean it up. It bothers me if I don’t do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t yet been in an environment where the problem was overt racism, sexism, or other forms of bigotry. I haven’t experienced it directed at myself or someone I’m with. I don’t see it in my community. I hear about it beyond my bubble, I believe that others experience it out there, but I don’t see it and I don’t know them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And because of that, like most people, I focus on the problems that fill my space: dirty diapers, mortgage payments, and what to make for dinner. It can be all-consuming with two kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to believe that I would be driven to action if I saw something every day that I thought was unjust, hateful, or just plain wrong. So I’m looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And maybe this is my ultimate reflection on Martin Luther King Day. We all should be looking. That’s what keeps it in the dark corners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want hatred of anybody around my kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way their experience will not be one of silent or overt oppression, too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="writing"></category><category term="creativity"></category><category term="expression"></category></entry><entry><title>The 3 things that mattered to me in 2017</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2017/12/28/the-3-things-that-mattered-to-me-in-2017/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-28T14:36:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-28T14:36:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2017-12-28:/2017/12/28/the-3-things-that-mattered-to-me-in-2017/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I can encapsulate my 2017 in three quick topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Fatherhood&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year began with a very high high and a very low low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The high was Norah, born just a month before the new year. I was excited to be a new dad again and go into it seasoned this …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I can encapsulate my 2017 in three quick topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Fatherhood&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year began with a very high high and a very low low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The high was Norah, born just a month before the new year. I was excited to be a new dad again and go into it seasoned this time. I wanted to soak it in, really enjoy it, not be as nervous as I was the first time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The low was my (https://medium.com/@rbucks/my-thyroid-got-cancer-b11f4494fc6f), thyroidectomy, and the announcement I had to make at Scripted within a few days of my surgery that we were going to lay off all but six employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately it’s been nothing but up since January and the side benefit to all of these changes was being at home with my family. A lot. I was probably in an office for less than two weeks this entire year. I spent a lot of time with Norah every day and witnessed every little development. I loved it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I look back on 2017 I’ll remember the many hikes, smoothies, jogs to the park, and visits to the library that I did alone with Norah. Most dads never get this chance so I took full advantage of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/9ab1a-1coacyech1j_zpvuiftap_w.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/ab14e-1ox89uabc99q9g74herbpvg.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/5fee3-1jrqa36xqmbl_zd3vetjgtq.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/c3f49-1m3j-bzs90xb7mz8pdp8p8q.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Tom Petty&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lost Tom Petty this year. His death hurt hurt more than Michael Jackson, more than Prince, more than Scott Weiland, Kurt Cobain, Chris Cornell, or any other musician I’ve admired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason is Tom Petty always felt timeless and ageless to me. He was always on tour, always sounded the same, always steady as a rock. Unlike most Super Bowl-tier musicians, he kept an even keel. He didn’t care about fame or fortune. He was never in the tabloids. He loved to make simple, beautiful music and I loved him for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Tom Petty song is pure, elegant, unobstructed, authentic. He didn’t have a stage persona. His performances were, for the most part, true to the albums and more importantly, true to himself. That’s how much he liked his own songs. He didn’t get tired of them, so I didn’t get tired of them either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know when I first discovered Tom Petty. In high school I was into 90's rock: Nirvana, Weezer, STP, Metallica, Soundgarden. Typical white suburban rollerblader kid music. That’s what I hear in my head when I think back to high school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that the soundtrack changes. When I took a road trip in 2006 and just headed out in my dark blue Cabrio east from Los Angeles I had two CDs on rotation, both were greatest hits albums. One was Bruce Springsteen and the other was Tom Petty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s what Tom Petty’s death did to me. It reminded me that I’m no longer that care-free 23-year-old guy driving down two-lane highways before Google Maps existed, the top down on my little convertible, singing “I Won’t Back Down” as the sun warmed my shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t disappear on long road trips anymore, but I still have Tom’s music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/2d51a-1xijcrjr2z5rz2vv64mgola.png)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Politics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(https://medium.com/@rbucks/whats-next-for-me-a6418447d3d0) back in April and set three goals for the following 12 months. I’m now 75% of the way there and two of the three goals are done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Done: Be able to live on (https://www.toofr.com) and get a second revenue stream going too (that’s (https://www.inlistio.com)).- Done: Write a book on parallel entrepreneurship. Well, it’s &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; done. I have a (http://www.parallelentrepreneurship.com/) and I wrote about my (https://medium.com/@rbucks/how-i-wrote-17k-words-in-just-two-days-2f1979f227a6).- In progress: Find my path into local politics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The political one has proven to be the most difficult because there’s no guide. There’s no data to measure against. It’s just a feeling of progress I have with every new connection I make, every insight I have on the local election scene in Contra Costa County, and every article I read about upcoming 2018 elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, I’m looking way out, probably 2022 because I’m starting from nothing. I have my fancy Harvard government degree but I don’t have a resume for local politics outside of my years on the UC Berkeley College of Natural Resources Alumni Association. I want to get plugged in and work my way up. I’ll also volunteer for one of my local 2018 state assembly campaigns so I can be certain I’m up to the task of running myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did register a campaign website though and will throw some links out once it’s ready. My online entrepreneurial instincts have kicked in: it’s never too early to start building SEO!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="parenting"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Open the gate</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2017/09/18/open-the-gate/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-18T11:42:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-18T11:42:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2017-09-18:/2017/09/18/open-the-gate/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve thought a lot about running for office. I studied it in college and in graduate school but I decided to take a detour through the private sector to get some practical experience and financial cushion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three years ago I started a family and just recently decided that I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve thought a lot about running for office. I studied it in college and in graduate school but I decided to take a detour through the private sector to get some practical experience and financial cushion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three years ago I started a family and just recently decided that I should prioritize a lifestyle that lets me maximize family time. So I’m doing that now, spending most of my day with my youngest daughter and working on (https://www.toofr.com) and other projects during her naps and at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result I’m at home or in the neighborhood all the time now and I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before long, however, both of my kids will be in school and I’ll probably get restless, so over the next five or ten years I should be able to increase my focus beyond my immediate family and finally pursue my public sector ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think platforms should simple. To that end, mine would consist of these three E’s: Education, Economy, and Environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Education&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to public schools all the way through college, when I graduated from the best public school of them all, UC Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m lucky to have lived with my mom in a great school district in Mountain View, California. I went to the same elementary school and middle schools as Steve Jobs. My high school sent more than 20 of us to UC Berkeley when I graduated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had great teachers, great resources, and at home I had a great environment to study and explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This stuff isn’t free and it’s not freely available. One of the most important duties of government is to equitably distribute essential education. Governments often fail to do so. That’s why education, even though it’s in pretty good shape in Lamorinda, the nickname for the area where I live around the cities of Lafayette, Moraga, and Orinda, is first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Economy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I studied business and I’ve started businesses. I love building teams, companies, and making money doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the area we live in, money is essential. There’s no way around it. An active, expanding economy that pays for good, real work benefits everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not against accumulation of wealth. I’ve written about how I’m trying to accumulate some myself. I am against excessive accumulation of wealth for goods or services that benefit small slivers of the economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When part of an economy expands while others stay flat or decline, it’s not good. It’s also not sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a public official, my economic policy would revolve around the philosophy that government should not stifle growth, but it should be very critical of inequalities in where the growth is happening, and intervene and correct when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Environment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“…because trees and animals can’t protect themselves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why I support environmental regulations. It’s about as simple a rationale as I can think of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To paraphrase the political philosopher John Rawls, we should design policies that support the most vulnerable populations. He asked what rules you might choose if you had no knowledge about your own social class and would be subjected to those rules upon birth. This thought experiment is known as the “(https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Veil_of_ignorance).”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I extend that concept to the natural world. I believe we are absolutely dependent on a healthy planet. To treat the natural world like a non-essential, expendable resource to be taken advantage of is short-sighted and tragically wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, ten years out from my formal education on environmental sciences and policy, I am admittedly tainted by real life. If people have to choose between themselves or their families and the environment, the environment will always lose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I’d agonize more over it, but I know I’d still put my family first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the role of government here is to try to not make people chose. Don’t put the birds and the trees in a position where they’ll always lose. To the extent sacrifices have to be made, and I believe it is inevitable, find the way where the environment loses least. That’s the essence of my environmental policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope within ten years I’ll have gone out there and done it. I hope I’ll have opened the gate. I hope that if I put myself out there and lost an election that I did not get disheartened. I hope I tried it at least one more time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I’ll be a good public servant. I’m going to use the next five or ten years figuring out how to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="writing"></category><category term="creativity"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>The Ascent of Blue</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2017/06/19/the-ascent-of-blue/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-19T07:32:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-19T07:32:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2017-06-19:/2017/06/19/the-ascent-of-blue/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Like many great love stories, this one begins on Craigslist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And like many young couples in San Francisco, after our first child was born we felt a magnetic pull to the suburbs. While my wife was researching neighborhoods and more practical things, I’d been scouring the internet to find …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Like many great love stories, this one begins on Craigslist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And like many young couples in San Francisco, after our first child was born we felt a magnetic pull to the suburbs. While my wife was researching neighborhoods and more practical things, I’d been scouring the internet to find a dog. And not just any dog. I needed a male chocolate lab, and I needed to name him Blue. The make and model of my dog-to-be was one of those requirements that can’t be explained. My mind was set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at professional breeders with online booking forms and waiting lists. I looked at rescue dogs and local pound listings. I didn’t want a professional hunting dog, and I didn’t feel comfortable bringing a pound puppy home to our young daughter. I kept looking, getting particularly interested in home-based, amateur breeders on Craigslist. It seemed like a dog in that environment would have the right temperament for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I found it. There was a breeder in Oakley with a litter of American Kennel Club-approved labrador pups expected to be born around Halloween. We were scheduled to get the keys to our house in Walnut Creek about a month later, and we planned to actually move in about a month after that. Puppies can’t go home for 8–9 weeks after birth, so that timing was perfect, if moving into a new house with a one-year-old girl and a 9-week-old puppy is indeed perfect (spoiler alert: it’s not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The morning of the day that we picked up the keys to our house I drove out to the breeder’s house in Oakley with my wife and daughter to choose my puppy. I’d never done this before and didn’t have a clue what to look for. I was hoping for a sign or an omen. I wanted my daughter to choose the puppy for me, or for one of them to come galavanting out to greet us, like in the movies. It didn’t happen that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The breeder and her family greeted us, friendly as could be, and she showed me the two remaining male chocolate labs in the litter. She brought them out of the cage in her living room and let me hold them. They both were tiny pups, but one was noticeably bigger than the other. I figured larger size at this point meant more milk and better health, so I chose the bigger guy. I remember looking at his pudgy nose, wondering why it was so flat and if there was something wrong with it. The breeder didn’t say anything so I didn’t either. His nose turned out fine, of course. Here’s a picture of that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/5a4fb-1s4wym6hh9fkmocvp7f9jrg.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My baby boy and my baby girl.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose my dog and then we drove to our new home to officially get the keys from our broker. Some neighbors were out in the court to greet us and a second relief passed over me. They were really friendly people and they also had dogs. Blue would have some friends in the neighborhood too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second trip to Oakley two months later was on another busy day. My family flew up from Los Angeles earlier that morning after visiting my in-laws for Christmas. We drove home to Walnut Creek from the airport. After we cleared the car I immediately jumped back in for the half-hour drive back to Oakley to take our Blue Boy home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;An ominous start&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was late December 2015 and the east bay was in a bitter cold snap. Before we left for our weeklong trip to Southern California I’d been playing with the wireless thermostat for our new air conditioner and in trying to connect it to our wifi, I messed up the heating settings. The furnace blew only cold air, so my wife couldn’t heat the house when we got home. I wanted to fix it before picking up Blue but it was getting late. The breeder made a point of telling me that Blue was the last of his siblings to be picked up. I needed to go get him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I arrived the breeder told me that she was secretly hoping I’d never show up. Her family spent Christmas with Blue and she said it was wonderful, that he’s a special dog. They were becoming attached. She also told me that he was always the first dog in the litter to smell his mom when she approached. She said that’s an early sign of love and loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thanked and paid the breeder, picked up the vaccination and AKC paperwork, and made two stops on the way home. The first was to Petco to pick up Blue’s dog food and his first chew toys, where he got many compliments as we explored the aisles in my shopping cart. The next stop was to Ace to get a heater for the house, on urgent text message request from my wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/35831-1z4teedqyumj7pyvsmoaiqg.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blue, master of the house.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sun was setting when I finally got home and was greeted by my frazzled, cold wife and runny-nosed daughter. She had already made plans to stay at a hotel that night, leaving Blue Boy at home with me. I put on some music and found the setting I messed up on that blasted thermostat while Blue Boy watched in confused amusement. The house was warm again and I was home alone with my dog. In that moment I was relieved and happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/37095-1fdw3ldootscekn9mlbhedw.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our first night together. He fell asleep to Beatles music.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/ee296-10zg998uzwrd5p7erwlmvaw.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lily greeting her new furry bro the next morning. Lots of runny noses that winter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following months would be challenging. We needed a new deck in the backyard and new windows throughout the house. My wife was contracting for her employer back then and my daughter was at home with her full-time. I commuted to San Francisco and had a lot going on at Scripted as we continued to deal with typical startup challenges. I couldn’t help with the puppy, leaving my wife with what must have felt like two kids as workers came in and out and Blue whined and yelped with excitement. Mix in a cold and rainy winter with a smattering of my evening work events, and you wind up with a few text messages like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/63358-1alz5o1o6nppif1meyxjavq.png)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a puppy and a toddler at the same time is hard. Our timing was off, but I didn’t know any better. We should have waited until she was older so her toys wouldn’t look so much like puppy toys. He chewed more plastic baby gifts than I can count, including her first potty, her first swing, and one of our two grey couch pillows. Even (https://medium.com/@rbucks/the-most-expensive-chair-possible-b958ee4d7ebe) ottoman has puppy teeth marks on it. He also liked to tear up his own beds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/603c1-1sswkwyimgxrzn-11kfkdqw.png)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t all bad news, though. He and Lily became fast friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/5360f-1bgzhbdpasu1_v10s8t6drg.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/92376-1rw0fji64zjr7dumgq7u5za.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They bonded and as they both grew they figured out how to play well together. She forgave him when his puppy energy knocked her over, and no one could get her to laugh more than Blue Boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/be697-1ext0ajfrgg12hcxvem5aqw.png)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/08c13-1wjzcc36p-1_pl_hx5w4daa.png)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I admit to getting annoyed with him when I’d give something to Lily and he would bolt over, ears perked, expecting something too. If we brought a bunch of Lily’s toys out, he’d start playing with whatever she wasn’t playing with. And by playing, I really mean chewing. We’d have to limit the number of toys out and pick them up as soon as she was done playing with them. It was more work for us, and when my wife became pregnant again, that extra work became increasingly difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we got to know him better, we found out more about what makes him special. First of all, he had very few accidents in the house. One or two solids and maybe five total wet ones. Within a couple of weeks of being in our house he was using the doggy door regularly. He’d go in and out, all day and all night, as he pleased. He was a quick study in the bathroom department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also had one huge surprise for us. He never barked. If he was a barker we wouldn’t have been able to keep the doggy door available to him all the time. Plus, with sleeping babies in the house, this is huge. UPS and DoorDash people would come to our door and Blue wouldn’t make a peep. He could sense that it was okay. The few times that we had people come to our house at night and I wasn’t in the room with him, only then would he bark. His guard dog instincts kick when it matters. I didn’t teach him that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only sounds he makes are whines and “Hey, what about me?” cries when we’re in the front yard and he’s left in the backyard. Those get annoying too, but he’s toned them down a lot in the last few months. He recently turned a corner with all of us, but most especially with my wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we’ve grown to know him, I think he has also grown to know and love us. In the mornings before my older daughter wakes up he lays down by her door and waits for her. It’s really sweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/67c1d-1qptdt2nzwkq578z9kpxisa.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blue waiting for Lily to wake up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I take him running anywhere. We go to parks, into the hills, and to Peet’s to get coffee and muffins. When it’s not too hot, we jog over to my daughter’s preschool to pick her up. She loves seeing him there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On summer evenings when the kids are in bed, he and I will sit out on the lounge chairs on our back deck and watch evening turn to dusk. The only lab I’ve known as well as Blue was my grandpa’s yellow lab, Bowie, but she wasn’t the lap dog that Blue is. He’ll put his huge head down on my lap and close his eyes, letting my hands brush across his forehead and velvety ears. Those quiet times are my favorite moments with Blue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/7d045-1jev8rp3x_det3yfsajxvyw.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beauty and the Beast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clocking in at 100 pounds, he’s able to do some accidental damage to my oldest and youngest family members, but so far, seven months along with my second daughter, he’s never caused tears. Not once. She crawls over to him now and pulls herself up onto his shiny brown torso. He’ll look surprised at first and then plop his big head down, let out a sigh, and allow her to do whatever she wants with him. When my older daughter does the same, he treats it more like a game and gives her little kisses. He seems to know that the baby is vulnerable and when she’s near him he can’t roll over or nuzzle her. He’s stuck at this point and knows he’s not allowed to move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who get to know Blue tell me he’s the best labrador they’ve ever met. My mother-in-law is a dog trainer and tells me this too. It’s not that he’s particularly well-trained. He knows no tricks but he’ll come and sit and lie down on command. I think Blue’s real gifts are not in what he does, but in what he doesn’t do. He doesn’t bark, he doesn’t growl, and he doesn’t get angry or frustrated. He’s happiest when he’s around us and when we’re happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read somewhere that the bond between humans and dogs has been evolving for millennia now. The first wolves were tamed a long, long time ago and the friendliest offspring were mated for hundreds of generations. What I now have loafing around my house these days is the pinnacle of that evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re my boy, Blue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/ad58a-1kdfzvuhwh10kkryxsz7rjq.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’re my boy, Blue.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="parenting"></category><category term="life-lessons"></category></entry><entry><title>Update: I shaved today</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2017/04/13/update-i-shaved-today/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-13T09:21:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-04-13T09:21:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2017-04-13:/2017/04/13/update-i-shaved-today/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A little over two months ago I wrote that (https://medium.com/startup-grind/im-not-shaving-until-my-company-is-profitable-ce9661362658). A lot of people liked it, but not everyone did. I expected that. I decided that I would follow the thread of truth wherever it led, even around the murky bends that are difficult to write …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A little over two months ago I wrote that (https://medium.com/startup-grind/im-not-shaving-until-my-company-is-profitable-ce9661362658). A lot of people liked it, but not everyone did. I expected that. I decided that I would follow the thread of truth wherever it led, even around the murky bends that are difficult to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The (https://medium.com/@rbucks/the-story-behind-our-layoffs-699c2d2eea53) in particular struck a chord. I got a lot of feedback from distant friends, and even an early Scripted writer. This is what he wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/26acc-1pxb2ui3ik47qb8lcvwmudg.png)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth is hard to find. It’s also hard to hear. I’m finding that honesty is a great filter. The people who I respect and want to spend more time with and learn more from respond well to it. They engage with me, ask questions, and make me probe deeper. I really appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here’s some more honesty: we’re not yet profitable, but I shaved anyway because we’re damn close. Also that beard was making my face itch all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That itching was kind of the point. I knew making a run for profitability would not be comfortable. There would be hard decisions to make and things to say no to that we otherwise wouldn’t say no to. That’s the discipline I really truly honestly believe was missing for the last three years at Scripted. We gained investor money and lost our grip on reality. We’re not alone, to be sure, but that doesn’t lessen the blow. We could have and should have learned from the mistakes of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month we did more revenue per dollar spent than we’ve ever done. We had 3X the membership revenue in March 2017 than we did in May 2016, and we did it with one quarter of the sales and marketing spend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In other words, we made a 300% increase in revenue while simultaneously decreasing revenue acquisition spend by 75%.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our profit also beat our payroll for the first time in years, maybe ever. It’s remarkable, really. So I shaved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope these are the last selfies I ever post online. I’m including them only because it’s the best picture I have of my personal development over the last couple of months. My beard grew in thick. I got compliments, but it’s not me (and neither is the mustache.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the best part of this profitability process, and the one that will stay with me for the rest of my career is that I really, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; like running a normal, profitable business. One that cares, a lot, about how much money it’s making and losing every month and is working &lt;em&gt;every day&lt;/em&gt; to narrow the gap. In that sense we’re like the millions of SMBs outside of Silicon Valley, and I think that’s a very good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="tiled-gallery__col"&gt;!({static}/images/df898-1yltx8w5qoxdqlrkrwmgs8g.jpeg)!({static}/images/b1dd9-1zbo30nkxqxxd0h2fwhutiq.jpeg)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growth is great. When high growth leads to big companies, that’s great too. It can happen naturally when your product works and makes people happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I no longer want to grow to become a public company with hundreds of employees and multiple offices. If Scripted ever gets there, I can guarantee that I won’t be CEO at that point. It’s just not me. It’s not what I want to do, it’s not what’s interesting to me, and I don’t need the money or the prestige you get from doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for what’s next in the immediate future for Scripted, it’s all good news, but I’m not saying what it is yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there’s one thing you can count on, though, it’s that &lt;strong&gt;Scripted don’t quit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="lifestyle"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="humor"></category><category term="self-improvement"></category></entry><entry><title>I don't have a dishwasher</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2017/01/01/i-dont-have-a-dishwasher/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-01T22:59:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-01-01T22:59:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2017-01-01:/2017/01/01/i-dont-have-a-dishwasher/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;About a year ago, my wife and bought a house. It took us six months and exactly four offers before we got one. Funny thing to spend so much time and money on buying a house… to discover it didn’t even come with a dishwasher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we didn’t …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;About a year ago, my wife and bought a house. It took us six months and exactly four offers before we got one. Funny thing to spend so much time and money on buying a house… to discover it didn’t even come with a dishwasher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we didn’t sweat it then, and a year in, I don’t regret it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, I’ve always liked washing dishes. Weird thing to say, I know. I like it much better than doing laundry. Dishes give me an immediate satisfaction. You go from high entropy to low entropy in a matter of minutes. Laundry just takes too long, and it’s not as satisfying since the machines do all the work. In fact, if we had a clothesline in our backyard I’d probably enjoy doing laundry more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a system down that I honed up at my family’s cabin where we also have survived for 80 years without a dishwasher. I rinse the largest dirty bowl, fill it up with warm, soapy water, and fill it with other dirty (but rinsed, quickly) items. Then I do a more thorough scrub in the soapy water, rinse off the suds using fresh water from the faucet, and place on the drying rack. When the drying rack is full, I bust out a dish towel and put them on the shelf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dirty to clean, disorganized to organized. It’s a beautiful thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to take dishwashers for granted. I don’t anymore. For centuries we’ve been using utensils and cookware that hasn’t gone through the magical germ-destroying electronic wash and rinse cycles and we somehow stayed healthy. That‘s what you worry about when not using a dishwasher, right? Cooties?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I don’t really need one after all.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="lifestyle"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="reflection"></category></entry><entry><title>Return of the nap</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2016/08/30/its-the-return-of-the-nap/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-30T07:21:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-30T07:21:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2016-08-30:/2016/08/30/its-the-return-of-the-nap/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week I was on vacation. I go to Pinecrest every year and stay at the cabin my great grandpa built 80 years ago. It’s a special place where life quiets and slows down. It’s the only place where I can very easily turn off the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week I was on vacation. I go to Pinecrest every year and stay at the cabin my great grandpa built 80 years ago. It’s a special place where life quiets and slows down. It’s the only place where I can very easily turn off the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also a wonderful place to nap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naps are the most underrated adult activity. My days as a parent now revolve around nap schedules. Meals, errands, and playtime are timed by the nap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is napping only a province for toddlers? I hearby beckon the return of the nap!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benefits are many:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay up later to get that extra reading or writing done- Sleep better when you decide to sleep for the night- Have a high energy afternoon, in which you’re happier and eat less- All the other regular benefits of sleep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Napping at work is a taboo. The mid afternoon doldrums hit and instead of napping, I go for a walk, often to get a coffee. Napping for 30 mins would yield better results, but I can’t nap while my colleagues work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I’ll have to wait until my office days are over. Then I’ll nap the same time my kids do, and it will be glorious.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="lifestyle"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="vacation"></category></entry><entry><title>My very expensive chair</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2016/03/23/the-most-expensive-chair-possible/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-23T08:01:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-03-23T08:01:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2016-03-23:/2016/03/23/the-most-expensive-chair-possible/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don’t usually love expensive things. For this piece of furniture, though, I made a big, whopping exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/10e40-1r3svmkllnh55ty3fv3mslw.jpeg)
&lt;em&gt;My Eames&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s my (http://www.hermanmiller.com/products/seating/lounge-seating/eames-lounge-chair-and-ottoman.html), and I just goddamn love it. It’s one of the things I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don’t usually love expensive things. For this piece of furniture, though, I made a big, whopping exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/10e40-1r3svmkllnh55ty3fv3mslw.jpeg)
&lt;em&gt;My Eames&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s my (http://www.hermanmiller.com/products/seating/lounge-seating/eames-lounge-chair-and-ottoman.html), and I just goddamn love it. It’s one of the things I looked forward to about owning a house. The justification was easy: when you spend your life savings on owning property in the Bay Area, what’s another few grand for a chair no one actually needs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That and the fact that I’d mentioned it many times to my wife over the years was enough justification to make the purchase. I think it was delivered within two weeks of us moving in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The look is iconic, and it’s as comfortable as it is beautiful. The wide, low armrest makes it great for laptop-ing, which can’t be said for most lounge chairs. The ottoman cushion is actually the same design as the seat cushion, allowing them to be swapped in order to even out the wear, effectively doubling the cushion life. The swivel is completely smooth and silent, and that low lean that it’s known for makes you feel like you’re sitting in the cockpit of a Formula One race car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I actually justify spending this much on a chair? Can anyone? Ultimately, that’s not the point. Money comes and goes. I don’t live to make money or to spend it. It’s fun to have nice things and to enjoy them with people I care about. It was equally fun before we could afford them. So what? I just like my Eames chair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, of course, Lily likes it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/3b004-127jxaqa_tqnodmk-a2dohw.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="lifestyle"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="design"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="family"></category></entry></feed>