<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>rbucks.com - philosophy-reflection</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rbucks.com/feeds/philosophy-reflection.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rbucks.com/</id><updated>2024-06-11T19:20:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>A short essay on free will</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2024/06/11/a-short-essay-on-free-will/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-06-11T19:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-06-11T19:20:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2024-06-11:/2024/06/11/a-short-essay-on-free-will/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My most pretentious title yet! 🥳&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever. I’m not a philosopher, but neither are my friends. So here goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in free will. Put me in the camp that says my choices today were not dictated by the cosmic explosion 14.3 billion years ago. I believe there is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My most pretentious title yet! 🥳&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever. I’m not a philosopher, but neither are my friends. So here goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in free will. Put me in the camp that says my choices today were not dictated by the cosmic explosion 14.3 billion years ago. I believe there is randomness in the world. I believe in chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I believe this truth to be self-evident. I’ll try to briefly explain using a short proof that the free will argument is flawed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logic goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we don’t have free will, then chance does not exist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If chance does not exist, then everything can be predicted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everything can be predicted, then time does not exist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time does not exist, then we don’t exist (consciousness, space, everything falls apart)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we do exist (just ask Descartes), then we must have free will&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fully give these ideas the inside-out analysis they need is beyond my ability. I don’t have the time to get caught up on all the philosophy already written on these concepts. I won’t enjoy writing about it, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I’m sharing here is a thought that I can’t shake. It’s my best attempt at explaining why it’s completely abhorrent to me that we should throw our hands up and believe we have no choice. That world sounds so dull. I don't want to live in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To not have free will implies the existence of a plan, a god-like creator who set the dominos tumbling. I don’t like this at all. It’s too religious, so I reject it on those grounds too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, I will briefly explain the five parts of my counterfactual argument. I'm going to argue against the existence of free will in order to prove that it does in fact exist. I'm trying to prove that free will leads to a conclusion that we all must agree could not be possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;If we don't have free will, then chance does not exist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeesh, what a place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I don’t think too hard about this one, it appears quite simple. With no free will, everything is pre-ordained. Let's be clear here: &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; are not special. We are made out of the same star dust as tectonic plates and asteroids. If we don't have free will, then nothing has free will. We have to apply the same rules to the entirety of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus everything happens for a reason, and that reason is built into the very fabric of our universe. Every law of physics, biology, and chemistry is describing the perfect order that was set from the beginning of time. If you wound back the clock and replayed the big bang, every single little thing, from the flicker of a butterfly's wing to the last presidential election, every war, murder, crash of a wave, earthquake and cosmic explosion would happen in exactly the same way at exactly the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's what no free will means. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, if there is no free will, then chance cannot exist, because all the cards were dealt 14.3 billion years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;If chance does not exist, then everything can be predicted.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that this argument doesn’t need to explain &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; everything is predicted. The point is the mere &lt;em&gt;possibility&lt;/em&gt; of perfect omnipotent prediction. Without chance, we leave open the possibility that every single little and large event can be predicted. I find that the anti-free will argument requires this to be true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, this argument flows logically from the last one. If everything is preordained, if the cards are dealt and the game proceeds by fixed rules, then if you know all the cards, you can predict everything. I'm not shaken by the idea that nobody can know all the cards. That fact doesn't matter. What matters is that if the cards are known then the future, the entire future can be predicted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this argument flows logically from the last one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;If everything can be predicted, then time does not exist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we start to get into the heart of what I'm trying to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the game of Hearts, this is where you see me slough a diamond instead of a heart or the queen of spades. You get suspicious of what I'm up to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, this here is the crux of my argument. Everything hinges on this point. If you want to attack my line of reasoning, this is where you should start. I'll try to support my position knowing I've left my kidney exposed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a universe where the future is perfectly predictable, we have no need for time. Given this as fact, time makes no sense. Therefore, it must not exist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll briefly explain. If I have the cards, I can play out the future. As I perfectly predict the future, time compresses. I bring the future forward and time loses meaning. It's only when the world is unpredictable that time is necessary. You need time for chance to be chance, for unpredictability to exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can predict everything, you don't need time. Therefore, time isn't required. If time isn't required, then it won't exist. If it won't exist, then it does not exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1585341984679469056).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;If time does not exist, then we don’t exist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It follows. If we have no need for time, then we have no need for anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time builds our reality. Without it, there's nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if we have no chance, we have no time, and we have... nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll just end that line of reasoning there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Since we do exist, then we must have free will&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's my other vulnerable point. I'm presupposing that we exist. I'm anchoring on Descartes, the one shoulder I stand on. I assume this to be truth, therefore the argument that we have no free will &lt;em&gt;must &lt;/em&gt;be false.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other way to turn this around is to say that those who are anti-free will are also anti-consciousness and anti-Descartes. They must believe that we are living in a grand simulation, connected to the matrix, that we all took the blue pill and are in a dream world controlled by intelligent machines. The AI overlords have already taken over and we're all just pawns on their grand chess board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reject this wholeheartedly. I just can't believe it. It's fatalistic. That is wrong and I think I've proven it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wouldn't you agree?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="philosophy-reflection"></category><category term="philosophy"></category><category term="free-will"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="writing"></category></entry><entry><title>A few things I learned from watching Einstein</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2023/08/02/a-few-things-i-learned-from-watching-einstein/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-02T06:43:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-08-02T06:43:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2023-08-02:/2023/08/02/a-few-things-i-learned-from-watching-einstein/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend suggested that I watch the first season of (https://tv.apple.com/us/show/genius/umc.cmc.i2eqkysudwuus6l2h73zl9bz), which profiles Albert Einstein. I checked to see how many episodes there were and how long each one was, as I always do when somebody recommends a new series to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend suggested that I watch the first season of (https://tv.apple.com/us/show/genius/umc.cmc.i2eqkysudwuus6l2h73zl9bz), which profiles Albert Einstein. I checked to see how many episodes there were and how long each one was, as I always do when somebody recommends a new series to me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten episodes! Each one 45 minutes! I hesitated at the commitment but took the plunge. Fortunately, I was not disappointed. The acting: phenomenal. I thought I was witnessing the actual Albert as a young man struggling with his place in the universe. I enjoyed seeing old Albert as a dirty old man, fondling his secretary. And in between, we get to know the wire-haired caricature Eintein, sometime in his 40s and 50s, as an unconventional physicist, unafraid to yield to his libertarian tendencies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this was brilliant because it presented Albert Einstein as a complex, flawed, deeply insecure human being. His brilliance and creativity as a physicist were also on display, but his success was merely a backdrop to his personal life, which was not brilliant at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tragedy around most, but not all, of his personal relationships was not due to social awkwardness. On the contrary, Albert was outspoken, charming, and funny. He had much to say and, famously, much to ask. Curious people are fun to be around, and Albert had many friends. He had a typical relationship with his own family, his parents and his sister. He struggled with an unapproving dad, but that's not unusual.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We witness his curiosity getting him into trouble in school, ultimately leading to expulsion. He had to find his own way into college, forcing his way to the Polytechnic Institute in Zurich, where he excelled at math and physics but had no patience for other subjects. We begin to see the iconoclast emerge in the classroom. His ability to break with conformity was a pattern throughout his life. I admire and respect him for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also chose not to conform as a typical husband and father when he got his girlfriend pregnant. The series presents this relationship as an honest, true love. I remember a scene when Albert tells Mileva, "I am madly in love with your mind." They agree to marry, but the relationship turns tragically toxic. They have two boys together, and Albert is an inconsistent father. Mileva, his intellectual equal at the Polytechnic Institute, gave up her career to raise their family and support Albert's research while he worked at the patent office. It's unclear how much she contributed, but there are several scenes where Albert professes his indebtedness to her hard work and insights. Nonetheless, he never formally credited her on his papers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was a doting father when he was with the boys, but when he needed to work, he focused only on his work. As his relationship with Mileva soured, he spent less time at home, and the boys suffered. Albert recognized the impact of his decisions but shrugged it off as the sad byproduct of a bad marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was also a philanderer. He met Mileva while in a serious relationship with another woman. He couldn't bring himself to tell her and kept his long-distance relationship alive while courting Mileva. Similarly, he fell in love with Elsa, a distant cousin, while his marriage to Mileva dissolved. And while he was with Elsa, he had numerous affairs: a secretary, an artist's wife who was a Russian spy... those are two I remember. Albert was either a man of the times (apparently, wives expected this behavior) or felt compelled to display his iconoclastic stripes in all parts of his life. The show didn't editorialize Albert's conscience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this happens against the backdrop of the rise of Hitler and the Third Reich. Albert is weary of Hitler's rise to power but refuses to believe that Germany will fall completely under the Nazi regime. He holds out, even as antisemites publicly disparage his research as "Jewish science." Eventually, he conceded that Nazism would overtake Germany, and he and Elsa moved to Princeton. The presentation of this tension is masterful. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show ends with Einstein struggling to maintain the mental stamina he had as a young man. He needed to solve the unified field theory, which would unify much of his earlier research, but he was unsuccessful. He succumbed to age as any old man will. He was merely human, after all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I admire Albert Einstein for making huge bets on himself many times throughout his life. He willed his way to success, and he paid for it personally, but history has paid him back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could he have been a good dad and a great physicist? Without his foibles, would he maintain his brilliance? These are the questions I'm left asking. I want to believe it's possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="philosophy-reflection"></category><category term="albert-einstein"></category><category term="profiles"></category><category term="philosophy"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="life-lessons"></category></entry><entry><title>Ode to the wheelbarrow</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2022/03/10/ode-to-the-wheelbarrow/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-10T20:49:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-03-10T20:49:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2022-03-10:/2022/03/10/ode-to-the-wheelbarrow/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The wheelbarrow cleverly combines two ancient technologies, the wheel and the lever, into a very useful device. Elegant and efficient, it's a beauty to behold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean really, look at this thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!(https://i.pinimg.com/originals/44/75/60/4475604f5fc6f95244b5aef24a77c24a.jpg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leverage you get comes from the long …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The wheelbarrow cleverly combines two ancient technologies, the wheel and the lever, into a very useful device. Elegant and efficient, it's a beauty to behold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean really, look at this thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!(https://i.pinimg.com/originals/44/75/60/4475604f5fc6f95244b5aef24a77c24a.jpg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leverage you get comes from the long handles. Keeping the load near the fulcrum allows you to lift the load off the ground with less effort. Since the purpose of a wheelbarrow is to move a load along a plane, not lift it up high, its design is perfect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I once needed to move a 450 pound boulder about 20 feet up a slight grade from the street to my front yard. I ended up watching a bunch of YouTube videos with grizzly-haired men talking about how ancient Egyptians built the pyramids. They relied on leverage and the efficiency of rolling and dragging rather than lifting and carrying. I got this boulder into my wheelbarrow, built a ramp to get it up the curb, and plopped that sucker onto its final resting place without herniating a disc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;!({static}/images/IMG_3856-1024x768.jpeg)
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have repaired this wheelbarrow many times. I've replaced and tightened many screws. I even had to buy a new wheel, a solid rubber variety that won't be susceptible to nails and rocks. It just keeps on giving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've lent it to my neighbors to move stumps and branches and piles of dirt around their properties. I've used this wheelbarrow to move stacks of pavers and bricks, cubic yards of dirt and decomposed granite, and even to transport gallons of water to a withering oak tree. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes engineering is so perfect, so elegant, that it appears boring. I'm grateful for this instrument, and I appreciate it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, wheelbarrow.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/IMG_3854-1-768x1024.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="philosophy-reflection"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="technology"></category><category term="appreciation"></category><category term="creativity"></category></entry><entry><title>The things we all want</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2019/07/06/the-things-we-all-want/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-06T07:08:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-06T07:08:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2019-07-06:/2019/07/06/the-things-we-all-want/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was July 4, and on this day for the last four decades my neighborhood has held a day-long celebration of community and country, in that particular order. I was reminded how much this neighborhood is cherished by an older woman I sat next to. Her son-in-law was raised on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was July 4, and on this day for the last four decades my neighborhood has held a day-long celebration of community and country, in that particular order. I was reminded how much this neighborhood is cherished by an older woman I sat next to. Her son-in-law was raised on the street where we spoke, and his mom still owns that house. He raised his family across the street and helped his daughter buy and remodel the house right behind us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some neighborhoods chew you up and spit you out, never wanting to look back. Some are like a cradle that you never want to leave. This neighborhood is that kind of neighborhood. The preferred method of leaving is being carried out feet first. The daughter of the original owner of our house told me that was her mom's plan. And her mom got her wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So on this day, long after the bicycle and scooter parade, sometime between the water balloon toss and bubble gum blowing contest, I stood with a dad I recognized from a few streets over. He worked in finance in London and, since I just happened to a read an &lt;em&gt;Economist&lt;/em&gt; article detailing the importance of London as a financial trading center, particularly in derivatives (which it turned out he traded), we got to talking about Brexit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He believed the whole thing was ridiculous, that clearly the Leavers hadn't thought through the impacts of breaking close financial ties with Europe and the devastating impact it would have on the economy, supply chains, and the financial markets he traded in. He want on to qualify his disgust, though, by saying that the underlying problems are real. Much like the populist wave here in the United States, Londoners and Brits are also feeling a sense of urgency to protect their own assets: jobs, property, and culture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completely pulling the UK out of the European Union is the wrong answer, but that doesn't mean the question is wrong. How do we make sure as many people are safe, secure, and healthy as possible? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that should be the role of the government, but I definitely understand that government doesn't always live up to that promise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked about all of this, but maybe due to the heat, it being my 3rd red Solo cup of Racer 5 IPA, and having woken up early with two very excited little girls who couldn't stop asking when the parade was going to start, I was not as articulate as I intended to be. When we discussed what the things are that people need most, I had opinions but they didn't come out clearly. I woke up today rehashing parts of that conversation and am writing this now to take a virtual do-over. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a much better articulation of what &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; people want, Republican and Democrat, neo-liberal and neo-nazi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone wants the good life, the American dream, a house and a job and savings for retirement all while being able to afford a family vacation every year and meal or two out at a restaurant every week. This is the picture of "middle-class" America: parents with a kid or three, a house in the suburbs, and &lt;em&gt;enough money to be comfortable now and well into the future&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people assume that the middle-class is the bell in the bell curve with a relatively small number of poor at the bottom and rich at the top. It's not. **There's nothing "middle" about the middle-class. **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are middle-class in California, you're well into the top 10% of earners. There are twice as many households making less than $100K per year as there are making more than $100K. And sadly families with $100K of household income would be considered low income (unable to comfortably afford food, shelter, and fun) in most parts of California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's an interesting exercise. Let's break down the expenses for a family with two kids in the Bay Area on a $200,000 household income. Note that $200K yields about $140K after tax, or $12K per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monthly expenses for a middle class family of four in the Bay Area:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mortgage + property tax + maintenance on a $1M "starter home": &lt;strong&gt;$5K&lt;/strong&gt;- Childcare (nanny or preschool) for 2 kids: &lt;strong&gt;$3K&lt;/strong&gt;- Loan payments (car, student loans, etc): &lt;strong&gt;$1K&lt;/strong&gt;- Food (groceries and restaurants): &lt;strong&gt;$1K&lt;/strong&gt;- Healthcare (usually taken from paycheck): &lt;strong&gt;$1K&lt;/strong&gt;- Savings or other: &lt;strong&gt;$1K&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a household income of $200,000, which is a princely sum by any stretch, you are just getting by in the Bay Area. Move-in ready homes in desirable neighborhoods with good schools run about $1 million. Everywhere you look, that's the rate. You might find a house with some maintenance requirements that will sell for $800-900K but even that will be competitive. Everyone's looking for deals like that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Childcare is expensive too. I didn't know it when I had kids, but for the first five years of their lives I'd basically be responsible for a second mortgage. Unless you have family or some other resource to help out every day (or a stay-at-home parent) you will need to spend &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; $2,500 per month on childcare. And then there's everything else which just adds up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you're really just getting by at $200K, and by that I mean your boxes are checked but you're without much cushion, imagine what it means to make less than that. Think about the sacrifices you make to live on $100K with a family here in California. Then look at this chart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/income.png)
&lt;em&gt;Most people don't make enough money to be middle class in California. Source: (https://statisticalatlas.com/state/California/Household-Income#figure/household-income-distribution)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's crazy. About 9 million households in California make less than $100K. About 4 million make more than $100K. And $100K is not even breaking even if you really want to live the middle class American dream. It's not even close. You need to be in the $200K+ bracket, which is only 8.6% of the population. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, the middle and upper classes are less than 10% of Californians. The rest are barely getting by or not getting by at all. This is the reality we face not only here, but elsewhere in the country as well. It's hard to live the life we thought we were promised in grade school, where we were taught to get a job, wake up in the morning and go to work, collect a paycheck and come home to support your family. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was supposed to be achievable simply by going to school and working hard. It wasn't supposed to be a top 10% proposition. It was supposed to be for everybody. It is not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what led to Trump, to Brexit, and to a host of other populist movements (France, Poland, Italy) gripping the world right now. It's not an irrational zeal for border protections and trade barriers. It's perfectly rational. It's just not the right answer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem isn't "them." It's us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Liberty&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our country was founded to avoid religious persecution (and British taxes) but clearly the principal that our founding fathers cared most about was liberty. Freedom to choose your destiny, where you live and work, who you pray to, and how you raise your family. Government was supposed to be primarily invisible, making things work in the background, appearing only when things needed to be fixed. The rest was to be left up to the people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our two parties today differ on what ought to be regulated. Democrats lean toward regulating businesses (stronger environmental, labor, and safety restrictions) while Republicans lean toward regulating people (stronger marriage, abortion, immigration, religious restrictions). Neither party is completely "liberal" and instead they differ on where exactly free will should be granted. It's fascinating when you dig into it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all agree, however, in freedom of opportunity. I don't know a single Republican or Democrat who doesn't believe that someone should be able to work hard, take some risks, and be rewarded if it works out. That's the common American ideal, shared by everyone, across party and racial lines. It's very American, but I think it transcends countries too. Everyone loves the entrepreneurial success story. Every country and culture celebrates its business titans. When fame and fortune come from movies or sports, all the better. We all love our heroes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liberty ultimately means the freedom to set your success. If you want to pull in a blue collar paycheck for forty years and retire with a pension to Florida, go for it, it's yours. If you want to drill for oil and strike it rich and get a library named after you then by all means. Give it a go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eat as much or as little of the American pie as you want. That's liberty. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is when other interests get in the way of that freedom. The destruction of liberties can be slow and silent. When our government prioritizes the health of businesses over the health of workers, when budgets and tax cuts are set to favor one class or one party over another, our collective ability to make an American living deteriorates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I believe people have been feeling for the last several years. Instead of lashing out against our elected officials and pushing for policies that prop up the middle-class, we elected someone (Donald Trump) who spoke to middle-class ailments but successfully framed them as coming from external sources. It's Mexico, it's Islam, it's China, it's everything and everyone attacking our liberties except us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn't disagree more, but nonetheless that's the state of things today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pursuit of Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you do with this American dream? Well, you feel happy. As you should, because you're lucky to be here. When you have the freedom to either make more money or less money, you're happy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness comes in many forms, of course, and not everyone needs the yacht and private jet to be perfectly 100% content with their lot. Merely being able to make your own decisions that impact your own outcome is sufficient to bring happiness. It's knowing that you did it your way. And if you don't like it anymore, it's knowing that you can change your course and fix it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When any of these elements are taken away or appear to unattainable, the entire system falters. That's what happened in the US and UK in 2016, first with the UK's vote to leave the EU and then the US vote to elect Donald Trump. It happened because people lost faith in their ability to reach their goals. They felt suppressed, anxious, untrusting of the existing norms that once yielded happiness but appeared to no longer do so. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agreed with my neighbor that the populist reaction is wrong, short sighted, and erroneous in thinking that we'll find strength in cutting off the rest of the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have the answer right now, but I know that blaming everyone else is not the right answer. We have to solve it by looking at the world and making ourselves better. There's plenty of opportunity, and a lot of it can be taken while actually improving the outlook for ourselves and the rest of the creatures we share this planet with. I'll dive into this in a future post.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="philosophy-reflection"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="philosophy"></category><category term="life-lessons"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>My favorite question to ask</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2017/10/09/my-favorite-question-to-ask-myself/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-09T21:07:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-09T21:07:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2017-10-09:/2017/10/09/my-favorite-question-to-ask-myself/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;These days I don’t have a lot of structure between 9am and 4pm. I don’t go into an office anymore. I don’t report to anyone. I’m running a nice little business now with no partners and no investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any given point in that 9–4 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;These days I don’t have a lot of structure between 9am and 4pm. I don’t go into an office anymore. I don’t report to anyone. I’m running a nice little business now with no partners and no investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any given point in that 9–4 window I can pretty much do whatever I want because my business doesn’t rely on me. I can ignore it for a day or even a week and it’ll still make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presents a new, unusual challenge: what am I supposed to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve begun asking myself a new question: &lt;strong&gt;What would be most fulfilling to do right now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fulfillment comes in many forms. There’s a leisurely fulfillment, like when I just want to sit in my hammock and watch an hour-long episode of The Sopranos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s also a stress-reduction fulfillment, usually related to a bug that’s bothering some Toofr users, and I know it’s going to open a wormhole, so I keep pushing it off. I summon the power to tackle it by reminding myself how good it will feel to fix it and put that buzz in my head to rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the enrichment fulfillment, which I (https://medium.com/@rbucks/three-life-hacks-i-wish-i-did-more-often-5d22bc572a55). Per that last tip, I will spend some time reading, playing, or writing (not work-related writing) and not feel guilty about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I can give myself the mental space to ask myself this question every day, I think not only will I be happier, but my business will be better off too. I find that when I return from a fulfillment activity, even if it’s work-related, it’s really gratifying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in control for that moment, directed my attention towards something, and completed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These small victories add up.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="philosophy-reflection"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="self-improvement"></category><category term="philosophy"></category><category term="life-lessons"></category></entry><entry><title>No such thing</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2016/04/10/no-such-thing/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-10T19:43:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-10T19:43:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2016-04-10:/2016/04/10/no-such-thing/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I never wanted to become a rock star.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t like performing enough, and I didn’t really try to learn to like it. Still, I’m a guitar player, and a pretty darn good one when I’m warmed up and practiced. I like to wonder what it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I never wanted to become a rock star.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t like performing enough, and I didn’t really try to learn to like it. Still, I’m a guitar player, and a pretty darn good one when I’m warmed up and practiced. I like to wonder what it would be like to perform in arenas with a kick-ass rock and roll band. It’s very much a part of who I am, what I like to do, and what I think about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, some people can recall exactly where they were when Lennon and Kennedy were shot. I recall exactly where I was and what I was doing the first time I heard “(https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H1W2UddURXI)” by John Mayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was driving north on the 880 in the East Bay, just up from the Oakland Airport. I had KFOG, a mellow rock station, on the radio, which I listen to in the car when nothing else is good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The song started. I heard the acoustic intro, a jazzy chord voicing that I didn’t recognize. Usually when I hear a guitar chord I can picture exactly where on the neck it is played. This time I couldn’t, and I was intrigued. A pop song with a complex guitar chord. Tell me more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His voice enters with the drum kit and bass. He sounds young, and also unique. I figured he was about my age, maybe a little older. As the verse continued I couldn’t make out the chord changes. Was it just a couple notes changing, or was his entire hand moving around the neck? How many chord changes per verse? I couldn’t tell. Usually overly complex chords mean the musician is trying too hard, but this song felt seamless, and the melody line fit the chords really well, despite their complexity. The pre-chorus and chorus had the same affect. Simple, interesting, just kinda perfect. I could tell he was a bad ass guitar player but he also had the sense not to rip into a guitar solo and spoil the vibe of the song. They put a keyboard break in instead. Smart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damn, who the hell is this kid?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tabloids have given John Mayer a rough time, and a lot of that is self-inflicted. However, as a musician and a guitar player, the guy stands out among the best. I’m not impressed by the technical extremists like (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yw74sDWPH7U) and (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aS_IYe5JTZ4). I never really cared for those players who overly romanticize guitar solos. I don’t like songs that sound like a music theory thesis project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I admire guitarists whose solos you can sing, who develop real voices in the way they play. I can pick out a solo (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Q7Vr3yQYWQ), (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JJx5626euOo), (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtLwuPCUEdg), or (http://slash%20november%20rain%20solo) just by listening to the way they strike the string. It’s distinct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t yet put John Mayer on the same level as those guitarists, but I give him a lot of credit for defining a style of guitar ballad that I’m not sure existed before him. Listen to “(https://g.co/kgs/xtWxH)” from that same debut pop album, “(https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Room_for_Squares).” Then listen to it again. Those guitar chords don’t exist anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that alone, I give the man props, but I also respect his later work. The jazz trio, the country pop album, the Hendrix and Petty covers. I feel like if I was John Mayer, I’d have had the exact same guitar playing career. Oh, and dating Katy Perry? Sure, that too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last decade of my life, since I’ve been aware of the guy, there’s been a thread in my brain that feels like I missed out on being John Mayer. The other threads remind me that I don’t have his voice, the guitar chops, the poise on stage, the libido. I would be a terrible John Mayer, and if I could get into his head for a moment, I bet there’s a thread there that wishes he could just have a (https://rbucks.com/2016/03/22/an-ode-to-the-suburbs/) with a hot wife and a couple of guitars hanging on the wall (like I do). Screw the fame. Simplicity, anonymity, and peaceful easy feeling is priceless. I’m sure he has those moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s fun to think about, and I enjoyed my brief time in the spotlight with (https://twitter.com/stephmarco/status/475511293395603456). Plus, I’ll always be able to pick up my guitar and sing John Mayer tunes to Lily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://youtu.be/ejubRbHs0J0&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="philosophy-reflection"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="philosophy"></category><category term="writing"></category><category term="life-lessons"></category></entry></feed>