<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>rbucks.com - politics-environment</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rbucks.com/feeds/politics-environment.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rbucks.com/</id><updated>2023-03-18T12:35:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Knocking your NOx off</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2023/03/18/knocking-your-nox-off/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-03-18T12:35:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-03-18T12:35:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2023-03-18:/2023/03/18/knocking-your-nox-off/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just started learning about nitrous oxide (NOx). When we (https://rbucks.com/2021/08/26/the-importance-of-electrification/), we did it to burn less carbon. I signed up for (https://www.walnut-creek.org/departments/e-c-o/energy-innovation/mce-renewable-energy) so our share of energy usage would come from renewable sources. I felt good …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just started learning about nitrous oxide (NOx). When we (https://rbucks.com/2021/08/26/the-importance-of-electrification/), we did it to burn less carbon. I signed up for (https://www.walnut-creek.org/departments/e-c-o/energy-innovation/mce-renewable-energy) so our share of energy usage would come from renewable sources. I felt good about paying extra (the notorious "green premium") for our all-electric home appliances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel even better now. Nitrous oxide pollution has long been recognized as a significant contributor to air pollution and climate change, posing a threat to both human health and the environment. To address this pressing issue, the Board of Directors of the Air District held a public hearing on March 15, 2023, to consider the adoption of proposed amendments to Regulation 9, which addresses inorganic gaseous pollutants. These proposed amendments include the introduction of zero NOx standards for space and water heating appliances and an ultra-low NOx standard for furnaces, which would have a profound impact on reducing NOx emissions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amendments (https://www.baaqmd.gov/rules-and-compliance/rule-development/building-appliances)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Need for Stronger NOx Standards&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOx emissions are produced by various sources, including transportation, industrial processes, and building appliances, such as natural gas-fired boilers, water heaters, and fan-type residential central furnaces. NOx pollution contributes to the formation of ground-level ozone, smog, and fine particulate matter, which are associated with respiratory and cardiovascular health issues, particularly in vulnerable populations such as children, the elderly, and people with pre-existing health conditions. Additionally, NOx emissions have been linked to adverse environmental impacts, including acid rain, eutrophication of water bodies, and the depletion of stratospheric ozone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amendments to Rules 9-4 and 9-6 are a vital step in mitigating these harmful effects. By implementing a zero NOx standard for both space and water heating appliances and an ultra-low NOx standard for furnaces, the amendments will significantly reduce NOx emissions from residential and commercial buildings. These new standards are set to be enforced from 2027 to 2031, depending on the appliance, providing a clear timeline for manufacturers and consumers to transition to cleaner and more efficient technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Addressing Concerns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Draft Environmental Impact Report (EIR) for the proposed amendments concluded that there would be potentially significant and unavoidable impacts associated with utilities, services systems, and noise, it is important to put these concerns into perspective. The increased energy demand resulting from the replacement of existing natural gas-fired appliances with electric ones can be mitigated by continued investments in renewable energy sources and improvements in grid infrastructure. Moreover, the benefits of reducing NOx emissions, such as improved air quality and reduced greenhouse gas emissions, far outweigh the potential challenges associated with increased energy demand. Furthermore, I believe the market will solve grid demand issues and supply will ramp up over time to bring prices down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the noise impacts associated with certain zero NOx equipment can be addressed through technological advancements and proper installation techniques. In many cases, the noise levels of these appliances can be reduced to acceptable levels, ensuring that they do not pose a significant nuisance to residents. My heat pump water heater is louder than my old gas one, but we put it in the garage and don't hear it. Plus, the cold air it blows as exhaust is amazing in the summer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm glad the BAAQMD passed the amendments to Regulation 9. By adopting these stricter NOx standards, we can significantly reduce air pollution, protect public health, and mitigate the impacts of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="politics-environment"></category><category term="environment"></category><category term="climate-tech"></category><category term="sustainability"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="policy"></category></entry><entry><title>Taking advantage of the Inflation Reduction Act in Contra Costa County</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2023/01/03/taking-advantage-of-the-inflation-reduction-act-in-contra-costa-county/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-01-03T12:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-03T12:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2023-01-03:/2023/01/03/taking-advantage-of-the-inflation-reduction-act-in-contra-costa-county/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After the success of (https://www.dvti.org/conference) conference, for which I chaired and did the bulk of the organizing, I was approached by a friend in the local sustainability community. She asked me if I'd like to help organize a conference focusing on green tech in Contra Costa …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After the success of (https://www.dvti.org/conference) conference, for which I chaired and did the bulk of the organizing, I was approached by a friend in the local sustainability community. She asked me if I'd like to help organize a conference focusing on green tech in Contra Costa County. I enthusiastically said yes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot to chew on around this topic. To summarize the three massive spending bills passed by the Biden administration in 2021 and 2022:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$550 billion in new spending over the next five years in the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (IIJA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$280 billion in the CHIPS and Science Act&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$390 billion for clean energy in the Inflation Reduction Act (IRA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This all amounts to "industrial policy," long considered the third rail in national politics for market meddling. But here we are, post-pandemic, with billions of money itching to be spent on green infrastructure. It's precisely the boon my fellow climate tech entrepreneurs have been waiting for. I want Contra Costa County, the (https://rbucks.com/2018/07/03/what-is-the-contra-costa-county-board-of-supervisors/) where I live, to take advantage of this. I want a green economy to grow and flourish in Contra Costa County. The question is: How do we take advantage of this windfall? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funds for climate come from the IRA and the IIJA. We'll start with the IIJA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IIJA includes $21.5 billion for clean energy demonstrations and research hubs. There's $8 billion set aside for clean hydrogen. $2.5 billion for advanced nuclear, and $10 billion for carbon capture, direct air capture, and industrial emission reduction. The $1 billion allocated to demonstration projects in rural areas probably won't slide here, even though much of Contra Costa remains in its 19th-century state. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the real industrial oomph comes from the IIJA. The IRA, which gets most of the attention in the media, provides nearly $400 billion in tax credits for consumers and businesses to adopt clean technology. McKinsey summarized these credits as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$4,000 consumer tax credit for the purchase of a used electric vehicle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$2,000 consumer tax credit for the purchase of heat pumps, heat pump water heaters, biomass stoves, and boilers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$3 per kilogram for the production of clean hydrogen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$15 per megawatt-hour for power produced at a qualifying nuclear facility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would love to see a renewed manufacturing sector in Contra Costa County. We're perfect for it. I'd argue we're better equipped than Fremont with its Tesla factory. We're closer to rail, the Central Valle,  Highway 5, and shipping ports, and we have "cheaper" housing. Our network of community colleges is perfect for supplying the labor for the advanced, high-skilled manufacturing industries to support the green economy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to attract these businesses. But how? Contra Costa County has refineries but not much appliance manufacturing. We have a strong services sector, especially in the financial, medical, and real estate industries. We also have highly-trained tradespeople for building construction and maintenance. Diablo Valley College and our other local community colleges provide much of that training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, where does Contra Costa stand to benefit from the IIJA and IRA funds? I would look here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Services industries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EV charger installation and maintenance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat pump installation and maintenance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EV and heat pump permitting, inspection, and construction management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial advice to access EV and heat pump incentives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real estate management to execute these retrofits and promote green buildings to tenants and buyers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Government sector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streamline EV charger permits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streamline water heater and HVAC permits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electrify government buildings and fleets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manufacturing industries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EV chargers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat pumps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solar panels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A stretch goal is to create a green technology manufacturing sector. For this to happen, we will need to get services going first and use that advantage to attract the industry. There's a lot of research to do here, starting with understanding if these appliances are built &lt;em&gt;anywhere&lt;/em&gt; in California. I suspect not. Suppose there's an economic rationale or the possibility of an incentive provided by these federal dollars directly or through the state. In that case, I hope our county leadership will be aware and make noise about getting our share. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How big is our share? According to (https://www.gov.ca.gov/2022/11/15/california-creates-17000-infrastructure-jobs-with-support-from-the-biden-administration/) from the governor's office, California will receive more than $16 billion from the IIJA. Allocated by population, Contra Costa should receive about $400 million. Then there's the $47 billion multiyear infrastructure package already in the state budget. Our share of that budget is over $1 billion. So we have $1.4 billion potentially to work with, and more &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; we can be creative and put good proposals together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The media calls this a once-in-a-generation event. Unlike the similarly-described extreme weather we've been experiencing, I agree that this funding won't come again next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the case for organizing a Green Economy Conference in Contra Costa County. We need our representatives to see this window of opportunity, a critical period when economic incentives strongly align with environmental needs. A boom in green economic output could transform this county, producing the change I've been working towards through the (https://www.dvti.org).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can continue to leverage my connection to Diablo Valley College, which will play a key role in connecting workforce development initiatives to the green economy. I'll also bring in the connections and perspective I've gained recently from my work on (https://rbucks.com/2022/11/22/business-evaluation-shovels/). This will be fun!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="politics-environment"></category><category term="climate-tech"></category><category term="inflation-reduction-act"></category><category term="contra-costa-county"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="green-economy"></category></entry><entry><title>Climate tech is my next big thing</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2022/11/26/climate-tech-is-my-next-big-thing/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-11-26T09:12:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-11-26T09:12:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2022-11-26:/2022/11/26/climate-tech-is-my-next-big-thing/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This has been a wild year. I guess I'll start from where I left off on that (https://rbucks.com/2022/02/20/how-i-wrote-my-childrens-book/) about a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming into 2022, I was doing really great. (https://mightysignal.com/blog/airnow-acquires-mightysignal) and was enjoying the process of moving into our …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This has been a wild year. I guess I'll start from where I left off on that (https://rbucks.com/2022/02/20/how-i-wrote-my-childrens-book/) about a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming into 2022, I was doing really great. (https://mightysignal.com/blog/airnow-acquires-mightysignal) and was enjoying the process of moving into our (https://rbucks.com/2021/11/14/how-we-did-our-home-addition-and-remodel/). I'd spend my evenings in the cottage (which wasn't described at all in that long blog post -- an accidental oversight) working on a (https://rbucks.com/2022/01/16/my-foray-into-web3/) and listening to loud music (thank you, (https://www.sonos.com/en-us/products/wireless-home-theater).) I was really happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I (https://rbucks.com/2022/02/10/my-first-month-of-real-teaching/) and my routine completely changed. As soon as I finished prepping for one class, another one was around the corner. Spring semester this year I taught thirteen units in five sections across four classes. Two of the sections were 90-minute lectures, back-to-back. It was a lot!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/image-1024x773.png)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured since I was working from home that I could fit this all in: my startup obligations, family life, exercise, creativity, and yes, teaching. A whole shit-ton of teaching. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was wrong, of course. What suffered was my creativity. I never missed a work call, rarely missed my share of walking my kids to the bus or taking them to practice, and even managed to do a lot of cross training so I wouldn't wreck myself on the (https://belgianwaffleride.bike/pages/california). I got into the best shape of my life, actually, and would knock out 13 miles trail running, or 2,000 yards of swimming, or 50+ miles with some major climbs on my road bike, on a whim. I could wake up feeling like doing several hard hours of exercise and totally crush it. I found a way to make that all work. But I stopped writing for fun. I didn't have anything left in the tank for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, my first year under Airnow was rapidly approaching. I figured I would stay a while because I really liked my team and I wanted to take MightySignal "all the way" -- basically to see it become something of a big deal in the mobile data industry. Airnow, it seemed, would get us there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as the post-COVID boom collapsed, inflation soared, and the war in Ukraine reigned in global economic optimism, a new reality set in. There would be no huge victory party for us in 2022. MightySignal was still in a stagnant growth pattern and it wasn't clear to me how the rest of Airnow's business units were doing. The last few months have been hard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in the midst of all my teaching, I started to think about what I would do next. It was an aggravating experience. I sent a few feeler emails out and got some responses, eventually leading to a couple of offers. One in particular was fantastic: an opportunity to lead another B2B SaaS company, build on my resume as a hired CEO, and take its $4 million revenue and $1 million net income startup into double digit millions. I could work from home, get good equity, and increase my salary by 40 percent. It was a virtual phone service company, a solid business with room to grow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only problem was I didn't want it. It took me a month to figure that out. When I turned it down, they offered me more money, and I turned it down again. "What kind of asshole turns down a job like this?" I texted a friend. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I was relieved. It felt good to make a decision symbolic of what I really truly want to do next: work in climate tech. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's time. It's time for me to take another big risk. It's time for me to work on something that I actually care about. It's time for me to combine my extracurricular interests with my day job. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't always see it this way. The turbulence en route stemmed from the recognition that a job doesn't &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to mean everything. I don't &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to love mobile data to work in it. If I'm passionate for something else, I can do it in my free time, which I'll probably get more and more of as my kids get older and older. So why not take a job that checks every other box and just let my job be my... job? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I suppose, the answer is it's just not that simple. Not for me, at least. I won't do my best work unless I can get truly excited about it, and I know I've been diluting my focus these last few years because I don't really care about the companies I've been running. The companies are functional means-to-ends, unfortunate necessities to allow me to volunteer and teach and do other community stuff that makes me happy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But all along I've had the nagging question: &lt;em&gt;why can't my day job also do thi&lt;/em&gt;s?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm going to find out. I've been telling people around me, including the guy who owns that virtual phone service company, that I'm doing climate tech next. It feels great! And along the way I've been networking with new people and re-networking with old contacts and beginning to sense where in the space I'm going to land. I've settled on two approaches: the well-funded startup and the unfunded idea, both in the residential retrofit space. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an incredible amount of work happening in climate tech. Here are just a few of the most interesting companies I've found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(https://www.twelve.co/), which makes critical chemicals &lt;em&gt;from air&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(https://www.brimstone.energy/), which makes carbon negative Portland cement at market cost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(https://www.blocpower.io/), which finances residential and commercial property decarbonization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(https://www.carbios.com/en/), which uses enzymes to break down plastics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(https://climeworks.com/), which absorbs CO2 from the air and stores it underground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(https://www.wattcarbon.com/), which sources carbon offsets from buildings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's all fascinating, incredible stuff. I would love to work at any of these companies and be on the frontlines of growing a business that is poised to make a lot of money while preventing humanitarian crises. I could see having boundless enthusiasm for this work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's competitive, and being ten years out of the professional environmental game, I'm not anyone's top pick for a senior role. I've tried and failed to get some of these interviews. I'll keep trying, but I also have another way to get in. I can build a company myself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thinking seriously about a couple of ideas. One was around financing residential decarbonization using carbon offsets. I wanted to find a way to use the market value of the future unused CO2 to subsidize carbon-free renovations. It seemed like there should be a way to do this, but the pathway is far from clear. Nobody has figure it out yet, but (https://www.wattcarbon.com/) seems to be the closest. My revenue model would be an arbitrage between what the company pays to homeowners for their carbon credits and what the credits sell for in the market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My other idea was to quantify how green a home is. This would be a pure software play, or possibly with some hardware if partners don't cooperate. This company would ingest indoor temperature and air quality, thermostat and water heater usage, smart device usage, and any other home-related data streams we can access. Besides analyzing this data to give tips for living greener, it would be a database of households' "home stacks," or the specific appliances that they use. The revenue model would be freemium -- free to use with some paid upgrades on the consumer side and possibly some paid advertising on the business side. This is a variant of the (https://rbucks.com/2022/06/22/business-evaluation-clime/) I evaluated previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibilities are endless, and I'm relieved to have finally settled on one idea, (https://rbucks.com/2022/11/22/business-evaluation-shovels/), which is not purely a climate business but one that fills a critical gap in the climate data puzzle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the way I describe what I do and why I chose to work on Shovels is that I found the intersection, after a lot of hard work, between B2B data and climate technology. Shovels is both and it's exciting and hard and... perfect for me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming years I will learn a lot about real estate and construction. I'll take another run at venture capital and running a high growth business that has to spend ahead of revenue. I can do it right this time and I'm very excited to use my scar tissue to my advantage. The current economic climate is also ideal for an entrepreneur with my background. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've known excess. I've known frugality. The ground in the middle is very fertile. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/b2b.jpg)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="politics-environment"></category><category term="climate-tech"></category><category term="shovels"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="career"></category><category term="environment"></category></entry><entry><title>Some great advice about how to stand out in local politics</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2019/03/02/some-great-advice-about-how-to-stand-out-in-local-politics/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-02T22:04:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-03-02T22:04:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2019-03-02:/2019/03/02/some-great-advice-about-how-to-stand-out-in-local-politics/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently drove out to Sacramento to try to see some old friends and public officials I know. The folks on my list were Assemblymembers (https://a19.asmdc.org/),  (https://a16.asmdc.org/), and (https://a45.asmdc.org/). I tried to track down (https://twitter.com/jason_elliott), my friend from …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently drove out to Sacramento to try to see some old friends and public officials I know. The folks on my list were Assemblymembers (https://a19.asmdc.org/),  (https://a16.asmdc.org/), and (https://a45.asmdc.org/). I tried to track down (https://twitter.com/jason_elliott), my friend from grad school who is now Governor Newsom's Chief Deputy Cabinet Secretary, but our timing was off, so I called up another grad school friend, (https://twitter.com/ZachNeumannCO), instead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It felt good to toggle my attention back over to local and state politics for a while. It'd been years since my last trip to Sacramento and I'd forgotten how busy it gets. Close to the capitol, it's all suits and ties and handshakes and ad hoc discussions between people carrying binders and iPads. It reminded me how much political infrastructure the state has. It also made me feel small. How can I make a dent in something this big?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest takeaway I got from my little field trip answered that question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's easy to make a name for yourself. Just do what you say you're going to do and you will stand out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my conversations weren't on the record, I won't attribute it directly. The point this person made was clear: there are tons of people who talk a big game, who want attention and power, but who don't put in the work. Just by doing what you say you're going to do, even if it's as simple as sending an email, will make you stand out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people are not dependable. In politics, I was told, the number is something like 99 to 1. You can be in the top 1% simply by following through with your commitments, no matter how small they are. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, baby steps make a difference. Another important bit of advice was this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to be helpful to a public official, learn about what matters to them, and volunteer to support &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; agenda. Don't try to pull them over to yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This point is brutally honest. Public officials are already pulled in multiple directions by community groups, public interest groups, and the media. If you're one person trying to establish a relationship, you'll be best served by beginning the relationship by being supportive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, I have work to do between now and when I throw my hat in the ring. There's a big wide gap between here and there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="politics-environment"></category><category term="politics"></category><category term="local-politics"></category><category term="advice"></category><category term="career"></category><category term="government"></category></entry><entry><title>Little Don</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2016/07/27/little-don/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-27T05:46:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-07-27T05:46:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2016-07-27:/2016/07/27/little-don/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s a speech I wish someone would have given at the 2016 DNC convention.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Republicans are now a party in shambles. They’ve splintered, and the leaders of the party have no clue how it happened or how to fix it. &lt;strong&gt;They spent the last eight years crying …&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s a speech I wish someone would have given at the 2016 DNC convention.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Republicans are now a party in shambles. They’ve splintered, and the leaders of the party have no clue how it happened or how to fix it. &lt;strong&gt;They spent the last eight years crying wolf, and then a wolf took control.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’ve nominated the most shady person in the history of American politics to be president of the United States. Nice going, Republicans. What a historic screw up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Democrats ran a long but constructive nomination process, culminating in the first woman to be nominated for president by a major party. Hillary Clinton has served her entire life in public office. She was a senator, a cabinet member, and the First Lady to one of our great presidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t think of a better resume to take the Oval Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there’s nothing presidential about someone born into wealth who uses his wealth to gain attention and bully people around who have less wealth than he does, so that he can make more money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been told to confront people like this head on. So I’ll do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Little Don, let me tell you something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know as much about world politics as my chocolate lab, Blue. If you wanted to be president, you should have  &lt;em&gt;listened to father and attended your private history lessons in the east study room with Sir Henry, your private history tutor&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Little Don, that’s not good enough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re not a blue-collar billionaire. That makes no sense. In fact, there’s a silver spoon stuck so far up your ass, it’s tarnished your hair color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Little Don, that’s not good enough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ve never held public office, so you’ve never written a bill or voted on legislation. Now you want to be executive of the most powerful government in the world. You’re a contestant on &lt;em&gt;The Bachelor&lt;/em&gt; applying to be the CEO of the American Broadcasting Company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Little Don, that’s not good enough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cheat on your wives and treat them like a car lease: “It’s been three years, time to upgrade to a younger model.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Little Don, that’s not good enough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, it’s not good enough. The Republicans deserved better. Hillary deserves a better opponent. One who will elevate the discourse, not take it down into the gutter, which will become the next phase of this election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mrs. Clinton, I give you permission to meet Little Don there. It is beneath you, but what is further beneath you is losing this fight because our electorate rewarded Little Don for playing in the dirt, like the little boy he is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t use surrogates to deliver the biggest blows. Show that you can dish it as well as any alley-fighting man. Then when you’re elected president, wash it off. You’ll never need to stoop that low again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immigration and trade deals are not the biggest problems we face right now, not even close. For the next president of the United States, the focus will need to be on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A weakened Europe&lt;/strong&gt;. Brexit must be contained, because if it’s not, a chain reaction of economic downturn and political fallout will turn Europe back into an early 20th century powder keg.- 
&lt;strong&gt;A warmer climate&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s already been reported that the last 12 months have been the hottest ever recorded globally. This will impact food and water for hundreds of millions of people. That in turn will create radicalization and wars. Presidents care about climate change not because of the birds and the trees. They care because of war and famine.- 
&lt;strong&gt;An even stronger America&lt;/strong&gt;. Our stock markets hit another local high recently. Our companies are still the largest and most innovative in the world. But America needs to continue to fix health care, to put new focus on education and infrastructure. Korea should not have faster internet service than us. Canada should not have better health services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are in no particular order. Building a wall with Mexico and screening out Muslims from our borders is Breitbart bullshit, plain and simple. There’s no benefit to us from doing this. Although liberals complain about trade deals too, nationalism to this degree is also destructive. Innovation has costs as well as benefits. The economic specialization of nations will continue to evolve, and we can’t be protectionist with our jobs. That’s short-term thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good president will keep open trade channels and help the impacted Americans get new jobs. That should be the American way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Little Don will disappear into the annals of electoral history. He will be a scar on the Republican party from the year when the Democrats again made history by nominating the first woman president.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s elect a real woman&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="politics-environment"></category><category term="politics"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="government"></category><category term="writing"></category><category term="opinion"></category></entry></feed>