<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>rbucks.com - teaching-education</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rbucks.com/feeds/teaching-education.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rbucks.com/</id><updated>2023-11-05T20:35:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>The importance of mentors</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2023/11/05/the-importance-of-mentors/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-05T20:35:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-11-05T20:35:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2023-11-05:/2023/11/05/the-importance-of-mentors/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;"Are you mentoring anybody?" my old mentor asked me a few weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"No, I'm not." And I stopped to think about that for a minute. I don't have a mentor right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lisa Bauer is my old mentor. I worked for her in college, but it felt like she …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;"Are you mentoring anybody?" my old mentor asked me a few weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"No, I'm not." And I stopped to think about that for a minute. I don't have a mentor right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lisa Bauer is my old mentor. I worked for her in college, but it felt like she was also my partner. She guided me through the politics of UC Berkeley, helping me understand the incentive structures that make the university tick. Our interests were aligned: I was a capable and hungry 18-year-old interested in environmental policy, and she was an ambitious and underfunded 40-year-old running the campus recycling and refuse program. She needed help. I needed a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't know this then, but I also needed a mentor, and she was the perfect fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through Lisa and the other students she cultivated, I joined a cadre of great organizers. They knew how to execute an idea and keep it running. They were smart in the right ways, and I discovered I also had a natural talent for navigating the campus bureaucracy. The truth is, I liked it, and the people I met on campus seemed to like me. It was easy, and it didn't feel like work. When I ran into problems, Lisa helped. I remember feeling back then that I made her proud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stayed in touch off and on after I graduated, reconnecting over a meal at her house in Berkeley every few years. It was easy to stay friends despite the long gaps in communication. When she sent a group email recently about wanting to find a renter for her house in Berkeley, I replied and suggested we meet again. After some back and forth, I offered to visit her ranch way out in the Anderson Valley. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It had been years, but we hit off like old times. We chatted while Lisa and her husband, Doug, cooked dinner. It occurred to me that I'm at the age now that Lisa must have been when we worked together 20 years ago. I told her that even in retrospect, with the decades washing away the loose memories, I still consider the projects we worked on the most important part of my Berkeley experience. That type of work, the organizing, politicking, networking, planning, strategizing... that's what I love to do. Doing this under her tutelage was a masterclass. It definitely helped me get into the Harvard Kennedy School, and MIT Sloan, and there's a straight line between all of that and meeting my wife, becoming an entrepreneur, and building the life I'm living today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mentor relationship is unique. It's personal and professional. These days that's a sensitive topic, but I liked that Lisa often treated me and her other student employees like peers. She said what was on her mind. She gave us relationship advice. The work was serious and important, but when we worked, it was casual and often funny. Most importantly, we knew that she cared both about the mission of making our little piece of the planet more sustainable and about nurturing and helping us.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have that now. I have friends, connections, formal and informal advisors, but I don't have an older, wiser coach in my corner checking in and making sure I'm doing my best work. I don't have someone opening doors for me, feeding me ideas and opportunities. I no longer have an advocate and I want to get that back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a mentor seems to be effective. I keep running into these relationships in the biographies of successful people. Here are a few that I remember:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arnold Schwarzenegger had Joe Weider to help him navigate the American bodybuilding circuit and get his first acting role&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Beckham had Sir Alex Ferguson as his coach and surrogate father for many years while he played for Manchester United&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Albert Einstein had Max Talmud, who introduced him to math, science, and philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it ever too late to get a mentor? I hope not. When I think across all of my professional relationships, I have the individual pieces that make up a mentor. I have a lot of people supporting me through my current projects. I have to work to solicit the output and cull the ideas. I don't have it all in one person the way I did with Lisa so many years ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I miss that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;!({static}/images/DSCF0096_0046-1-1024x768.jpg)

!({static}/images/AA0B9D9B-E6AF-4FD1-AFDE-9F9DDA1E5915_1_105_c-1.jpeg)
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><category term="teaching-education"></category><category term="mentoring"></category><category term="career"></category><category term="teaching"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="advice"></category></entry><entry><title>My first month of real teaching</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2022/02/10/my-first-month-of-real-teaching/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-02-10T21:58:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-02-10T21:58:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2022-02-10:/2022/02/10/my-first-month-of-real-teaching/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I leave Diablo Valley College each Tuesday and Thursday exhausted but on the equivalent of a mental high. Teaching two Introduction to Business sections back-to-back is a full body+mind workout that I've never experienced before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/FDE73FAF-9199-4C01-B425-A4CF0F7CA28D_1_105_c.jpeg)
&lt;em&gt;My classroom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm three weeks in with thirteen more to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I leave Diablo Valley College each Tuesday and Thursday exhausted but on the equivalent of a mental high. Teaching two Introduction to Business sections back-to-back is a full body+mind workout that I've never experienced before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/FDE73FAF-9199-4C01-B425-A4CF0F7CA28D_1_105_c.jpeg)
&lt;em&gt;My classroom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm three weeks in with thirteen more to go until the end of the semester. I've learned a few things, but before I go into that, let me provide some context. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I described (https://rbucks.com/2019/10/17/why-im-applying-to-be-an-instructor-at-dvc/) in a previous post. I still believe all of it. My heart is 100% still in this. I love the community college atmosphere, the type of students I teach, and the subject itself. My first two semesters were, like so many educators, a shallow pit of Zoom office hours and online quizzes. It was fine but not particularly rewarding. I did all that work upfront and merely shepherded the course along as the weeks went by. I didn't feel like I was teaching. I was just the facilitator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Business Administration Department asked me to teach the only two in-person sections of Introduction to Business, a course that every business student needs to take, I eagerly accepted. This would be my moment! I could finally don my elbow-patched tweed blazer, smoke my pipe, and wax poetical before a chalkboard in front of enamored students. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, late last year, I chose my textbook and began to imagine how my lectures would go. My sections would be Tuesday and Thursday at 9:30am and 11am. Each is 80 minutes. I wanted to believe I could give an enchanting lecture every time, peppered with tails of my business experience, maybe incorporating something interesting and current from (https://mightysignal.com) and (https://www.airnow.com). Thinking back on my favorite lectures at UC Berkeley, I admired most the professors who could riff on current events and tie them back to the reading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been trying, desperately, to be that professor. I'm not sure I'm doing it right, but I do think I'm getting better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let's get back to what I've learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Authenticity is rewarded&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I play Grateful Dead at the start of each class. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always get to class early, and since I use my own laptop for some slides and other multimedia, I figured I should play music the way it's played at a concert venue before the opening act. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose Grateful Dead because it's calming (for me, at least) and unique. When I first started doing this a student in each of my sections called me out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Is that the Grateful Dead?" they asked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Yup," I said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They nodded in quiet appreciation. I'd like to think they'll enjoy the class better now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also am quick to say when I'm not sure about an economic or business concept. It's not easy to riff on the news and relate it to the reading. Sometimes I talk myself into a corner, make a mental note and admit my confusion, and Google it as soon as I get home. I'm learning new things this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can actually feel myself getting a lot smarter. My own learning is driven by being curious, exploring the chapter concepts, and trying to teach it by drawing connections to current events. Sometimes it works better than others, but when I get it wrong, I recognize that's an opportunity for me to learn too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's good, and I believe my students reward me for it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preparation is paramount&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't improvise a lecture. It would not be fun. I would stumble, feel awkward, and also feel bad for my students. I'd be failing them. I've found that weekends are great for reading the publisher's lecture notes, reviewing the publisher's slides, and imagining how I would want to present this information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picture each lecture before I give it. I have the roadmap in mind and I leave myself little breadcrumbs so I stay on track. These might be penciled notes on paper or an agenda in PowerPoint. My challenge now is predicting how long it will take to go through a topic. I'm definitely getting better at that, but it's the biggest variable in my preparation. &lt;em&gt;How long will it take to talk about this?&lt;/em&gt; I have no idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often find myself rushing at the end of the lecture. Maybe it's good that time seems to fly at the front of the lecture hall? I figure if I felt it going slow, my students would feel it even more so. Better that the 80 minutes goes quickly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My preparation thus far has been sufficient. I'm sure I could do more, but I'm glad I haven't done any less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Teaching live takes stamina&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching is a workout. I get the same high as an eight-mile run, but here it's all in my head. The feeling also reminds me of playing with the (https://rbucks.com/2019/10/17/becoming-a-better-public-singer/) after a really good show. I'd still be pumped up on adrenaline, glad that's over but happy with how the performance went. I get that buzz every Tuesday and Thursday after two back-to-back lectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure what about it is so tiring. I do feel like I'm performing. I'm very deliberately shoving my introversions aside and my mind is running in overdrive, especially when I'm going off the cuff on one of my business news tangents. But like these workouts I've been doing recently, I've learned to love the exhaustion. I tell myself during my physical workouts that this is where muscle is born. It hurts because I'm giving birth to strength. Lecturing on a subject like microeconomics, international trade, or a new business framework is like that. I'm giving birth to knowledge. It's supposed to feel hard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also appreciate that it's getting easier. Like training to do a five minute straight-arm plank, what once felt impossible is now a daily routine. I'm just three weeks in. I don't know what it will feel like after sixteen, but I can't wait to find out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've always been told I'd make a good teacher. I've always agreed. I'm grateful to have the chance to explore this now. I'm glad that Diablo Valley College is a close drive (or, more commonly now, a bike ride) away. I'm glad I got a (https://rbucks.com/2019/06/06/what-my-grad-school-experience-meant-to-me/) -- without it, I would not have been hired. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole experience has been a major positive in my life and I expect it will only get better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="teaching-education"></category><category term="teaching"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="career"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="community-college"></category></entry><entry><title>What my grad school experience meant to me</title><link href="https://rbucks.com/2019/06/06/what-my-grad-school-experience-meant-to-me/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-06T13:04:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-06T13:04:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Buckley</name></author><id>tag:rbucks.com,2019-06-06:/2019/06/06/what-my-grad-school-experience-meant-to-me/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I write this from Cambridge, MA. I took the red eye last night, flying in from SFO. There used to be a lot more flights out of OAK a decade ago when I did this trip several times a year. Now they are few and far between. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I write this from Cambridge, MA. I took the red eye last night, flying in from SFO. There used to be a lot more flights out of OAK a decade ago when I did this trip several times a year. Now they are few and far between. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I have a house and a family to miss and a dog to get cared for while I'm gone. The last time I was here for a class reunion was five years ago. I was almost a dad then, but not quite. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of this stretch between Harvard and MIT has remained the same. And the weather in Boston right now is perfect, just barely humid, a nice cool breeze in the shade. I forgot my sweater and am happy to not miss it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received my acceptance email from the admissions office at the Harvard Kennedy School of Government  on March 4, 2006, just over 13 years ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was obviously a big deal for me and my parents. I'd be the first in my family to attend a school like Harvard and for my mom it was a dream come true. She'd encouraged me to apply to Harvard when I was in high school. I did and got waitlisted, but in my heart of hearts I wanted to go to (https://nature.berkeley.edu/). I told Harvard College to bugger off, and I made a mental note to do everything I could to build a competitive application for a Harvard grad school program instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The path from August 2000, when I matriculated to Cal, to February 2006, when I submitted my Harvard Kennedy School admission application for the Master in Public Policy program, was a long one. I worked hard at UC Berkeley, both in and out of the classroom, to differentiate myself. My grades were good but not among the best. I knew I'd need something special to catch the eye of admissions officers at Harvard, so I focused on environmental activities and leadership in those circles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The capstone of my admission packet was probably the letter of recommendation from Chancellor Berdahl. I never read it, but I'm pretty sure it was good. He and I had a lot of mutual respect and I was able to capitalize on it to move my sustainability agenda forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of note, it wasn't Chancellor Berdahl who I worked with to get that letter drafted and delivered. It was one of his staff, a guy named Sean Ireland, who probably wrote the letter and got the Chancellor to sign it. He was my man on the inside and nothing would have happened without him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've learned time and time again that you have to be nice to and appreciative of everyone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!({static}/images/berdahl-award_orig.jpg?w=1024)
&lt;em&gt;The Chancellor of UC Berkeley giving me one of the first Berkeley Sustainability Awards.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I was good at this campus sustainability politicking and probably the best at doing this at UC Berkeley at the time. My skills met the right opportunity and it catapulted me forward. I made sure that my Harvard grad school application emphasized that point. I got in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I forwarded that fateful email from Harvard to my mom and went to the bar at a nice restaurant downstairs from the office tower I worked at in San Francisco to celebrate. It was five in the afternoon and I decided to splurge on a shot of Johnny Walker Blue on the rocks. My mom called while it was being prepared. She'd been crying. When the bartender overheard what I was celebrating (not too many 24-year-olds order a $60 shot at five in the afternoon, even in San Francisco), she told me it was on the house. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on cloud nine. I soon made plans to quit my job, spend the summer on an epic road trip through the southwest to Colorado and then to Spain and Europe. It was a unique and amazing time in my life. Limitless opportunity, no obligations, and most of all, a sense of pride that I'd worked towards an ambitious goal and achieved it. It was done. Nobody could take it away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;!({static}/images/img_0108.jpg)- !({static}/images/img_0182.jpg)- !({static}/images/img_0275.jpg)- !({static}/images/img_0353.jpg)- !({static}/images/img_0438.jpg)- !({static}/images/img_0473.jpg)- !({static}/images/img_0624.jpg)- !({static}/images/img_0649.jpg)- !({static}/images/img_0699.jpg)- !({static}/images/img_0788.jpg)- !({static}/images/img_0972.jpg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the rest of my life I'd always have that Harvard acceptance letter. I was in the club. Indeed my life would change forever, but not in the ways I originally expected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was through the Kennedy School that I (https://rbucks.com/2019/06/12/on-nine-whole-years-of-marriage/): Chancellor Berdahl introduced me to the Lieutenant Governor of California, John Garamendi. He offered me a summer internship writing environmental policy papers. His wife Patti gave me a ticket to the event where I met Melissa. We would eventually get married and start a family, raising my (https://rbucks.com/2018/06/27/benefits-of-being-a-work-from-home-dad/). This is easily the biggest, most important thing I've ever done. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought the Kennedy School would set me on a path into government, but instead I caught the (https://rbucks.com/2016/05/20/the-scripted-origin-story-as-i-remember-it/). I applied to and got accepted to the MBA program at the MIT Sloan School of Management. The registrars at Harvard and MIT allowed me and three other students to get two Master's degrees in three years. The company I'd go on to co-found with Sunil Rajaraman was a ten-year odyssey through the (https://rbucks.com/2019/02/01/the-bitter-taste-of-failure/) of startup culture in Silicon Valley. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My career to date stems entirely from this startup rather than from my graduate school degrees. I can't say that I regret it. The startup experience I've gained allowed me to (https://rbucks.com/2016/03/22/an-ode-to-the-suburbs/) and raise two kids in the Bay Area. I have tons of flexibility to explore my community and work on a lot of (https://rbucks.com/2018/07/02/my-first-commission-seat-in-contra-costa-county/). I had no idea 13 years ago that this is what I would be doing now, that I'd skip my 10-year Kennedy School reunion in favor of my MIT Sloan reunion, where the cover band I played in would headline the main happy hour party for my entire class. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But such is life. It's unpredictable. At 36, going on 37, I'm still young. I feel young too, physically in better shape than I was when I was a student. I'm definitely stronger. I can do way more pullups now than I could at 24. Jogging up hills pushing a double stroller has done wonders for my fitness, so I'm probably thinner although my weight is more or less the same. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm taking my time here in Boston this weekend to soak it all in. The Charles River is beautiful, the brick sidewalks and lush vegetation as alluring as it was the first time I stepped foot in Cambridge. This place has the same magnetism that it had for me back then, and it gives me the same curiosity about my place in the world, the potential I still have in front of me. I can't help getting excited about (https://rbucks.com/2017/07/11/whats-next-for-me/).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first I have a concert to practice for,  my first rock and roll performance in five years. It's all going to be awesome. All of it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="teaching-education"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="reflection"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="career"></category><category term="harvard"></category></entry></feed>